-: Right now in our application,
if we run the project everything is working as expected.
But what we want to do next is,
where we have one product in our project,
I want to basically display,
I want to basically display a list of products.
So in here, if we log in as admin,
you can see we have one image per product.
What I want is here we should be able
to upload multiple images for a product.
In order to handle that situation
we will have to update quite a few things,
but first thing will be inside the product model
where we have the image URL,
we will have to remove that.
But because if you remember,
I'm upgrading from .NET 8 preview downgraded that to .NET 7
there is some issue with the migration.
First, what I will do is in product here,
let me try to add one more property here,
prop int TestProperty.
We'll open the package manager console
and let me add a migration, addTestProperty.
You can see it gives a weird error object reference
not set to an instance of an object.
If you are facing this error message,
I have already reported this to Microsoft.
But this solution this time is,
we can start fresh with our migration.
So if we go to DataAccess here,
I can delete the Migrations folder.
Let me remove that.
And once we remove that, we can add a new migration here.
And this will be initial migration.
Because now there are no migrations here,
it'll create a new migration,
where it'll basically create all the tables.
So let me do add migration
with the name of initial migration.
Perfect. You can see that is done.
But with that we have one more issue.
We already have a database.
So if you directly try to say update database here,
it will not work.
It'll say that ASP NET roles
and all the other tables are already present,
so you cannot proceed.
And for that, what we will have to do is,
let me go back here.
I will have to change the connection string here
to be Bulky New.
With that new connection if I just run the project here,
it'll automatically push all the pending migration
because we have that in the DB initializer.
Perfect. You can see it is up and running.
In the Content Management, we are already logged in,
but you can log out here
and log in back with the admin account.
That will work where we have the product.
Let me add it here and I can upload an image.
Let me do that real quick for Dark Skies as well.
I can upload one more image.
And let me upload the lawn leaf image.
And perfect. That looks good.
Right now I do not want to add image to all the product
because we will be removing them and erase.
So in the next video, let me work on the product model
and remove image URL from there.