Narrator: We want to remove the image URL
from our product model.
So let me switch back here and close all the tabs.
I will open the product model,
let me stop the solution here,
and we want to remove the image URL
and I also added a dummy property for a test property.
Let me remove that as well.
But when we remove the image URL,
if we build the solution, it will not work.
We will have to remove that reference from all the places.
So let me pin this here and start on that.
First thing here is in the DP Initializer,
we were populating initial product
where we had an empty image, U R L.
We do not have that property
so we will have to remove this particular line here.
Perfect. Let me go back here.
Whoops.
Where is the error list here?
Pin that.
The next one is when we are updating in the repository
we do not want this.
Let me remove that.
Then where we are displaying the image in the views,
I will comment all of them for now.
We will keep them commented
and we will come back to them later on.
In the product controller, we have the absurd action method.
So when we are creating or updating,
we have the logic to handle image U R L.
I will comment all of them here.
Perfect, that looks good.
We have a hidden property somewhere.
We will comment that as well.
And we have an image U R L A S P four.
Remove that.
In the delete, when we are deleting product,
we have logic to remove the old image.
I will comment that as well.
Then let me see what is pending here.
One more view,
and let me see if anything else is missing.
Nope, I think that looks good.
Yep.
Let me build it one more time.
Perfect. It succeeded.
So when we are removing the image U R L here,
we have to add a new migration.
So package manager, let me scroll down here, add migration.
I will call that remove image U R L.
Perfect. It is dropping the column and that looks good.
Let me update the database.
And great.
With that we have removed image U R L from products
and if I run the application, it should work this time
but we do not have image with our product.
Next task that we have is adding the image U R L
in a separate table.