Instructor: Now we need to add a new model that will be
responsible for adding or managing all the images
for a product.
A single product can have multiple images
in the models project.
We will add a new class and call that product image.
We will make that a public clause here
and the first property will be primary key.
Let me call that as id.
That is good enough.
Then we want the U R L.
So we will have string,
and that will be image URL
for the individual image that we have.
And that will be image URL.
I will make this a required property.
After that, we need the product ID
because one product can have multiple image URL
so we need that relation here for product id
and product ID will be a foreign key.
So I will add the navigation property for product.
Now if you think about this, the relation
between product and product image is a one to many relation
because a single product will have many product image.
So in the product here we can create a list
of product images.
So in the product model, we can create list
of product image where we can carry
or load all of the images for our product.
So that way we are telling entity framework core
about the one to many relation
that we have between product and product image.
With that configured, we have to add that to application
DP context that is inside the data access here.
We need to create one more DP set
for product image and I will call that product images.
That will be the table name.
With that configured, all we have to do is
add a migration to add product image to db.
Perfect. That is done here.
Let me update the database.
And with that we have created a new table to
handle all the images of products.