Instructor: Now the way we have designed our project
is we have repository to access any
of our core model
similar to category repository.
We will also have to add a repository for product image
and then we will have to add that to unit of work.
That is the design
of repository that we have in our project.
So let me copy the category repository,
paste it,
and I will modify that for I product image repository.
I will copy that name and we will modify the interface here.
That will be on model product image.
And, in the update here
we will receive a product image object.
Perfect. The interface looks good.
Let me copy the implementation of category repository
paste it one more time
and I will rename that to be product image repository.
I will copy that name here
and I will modify the product image repository.
Let me do that real quick.
Model here will be product image
and the constructor name will be product image repository.
On update, we will receive a product image,
and we will go to underscore tb
dot product images dot update.
That looks good for both the repository.
Finally, we have to configure unit of work.
In the interface here,
we just need to create I product, image repository.
And in the implementation here,
let me create public I product image repository
and initialize that.
Perfect, that looks good.
And with that we have added the product image
to our unit of work.
Let me continue from the next video.