Instructor: The first thing that I want to handle now
is inside areas, admin, controllers.
I have product controller
and in the view we have the upsert view
for product right there,
the hidden property that is not needed.
But if we scroll down where we have the file upload,
we need to change this.
That way it can upload multiple files.
I can rename the name here to be files.
That way I am being more explicit.
But main thing that I have to do here is add multiple
and then user will be able to select
multiple images to upload.
We have a label here.
I can un-comment that
and rather than image URL, we can display product images.
You can give that label some name if you want,
but that looks good.
So with that, user will be able to select multiple images
for our input field.
Right here we are displaying image,
later on when they are editing,
but we will handle that in the upcoming videos.
We do not want to touch that right now.
First I want to make sure
that when a user selects multiple image
and hits the submit button, it actually uploads that image.
Now, previously in wwwroot images we have a product folder
and there we were maintaining all of the product image,
but now we will have images for individual product.
We can still go with this route because it will be a grid
and it will be distinct, but it will be even better
if we create folders for each product with their ID.
So for that we will have to go to product controller here
and where we have the post,
we will not be getting one file now.
I will be getting a list of I form file
and the name we modified that to be files right here.
So make sure to rename that to files.
And then we have to check if files is not null.
Now we have multiple file,
but before we save any of the file logic that we have here
we first have to create a product,
because that way we will get the product ID.
And with that ID we will create a new folder.
So let me cut the if else.
I will also grab the unit of work.save
and I will add that first thing if the model state is valid.
Once the product is created here,
on product view model.product.ID
we will have the product ID of the newly created product.
So then we can iterate through each file
that were uploaded here.
So if files is not now
we will have a for each loop I form file
and I will call that file in files.
So now for each file we will have to give that a file name
and product path.
Let me cut and paste it here.
File name looks good, but we have the product path.
There we need to add the product ID.
So what I can do is I can create
a new variable product path,
which will be inside images, products
and then product-.
We will append the product ID
that is inside product view model.product.ID.
And here I can call this final path
that is a combination of wwwroot and the product path.
After that, we will have to create
this particular product folder if that does not exist.
So I can check if directory that does not exist,
the final path, then create that particular directory.
That will create the directory
where we have to upload all the files
for this particular product.
Then we have the logic to upload.
Let me copy the file stream and paste it here
and comment that.
And there we will use the final path.
Once we upload the file, then we have to save a record
in the product image table.
So we have to create a product image is equal to new.
And right here we can populate all the properties.
First one here is the image URL
and I will save that with a backward slash here.
Plus I will add the product path.
We do not want the wwwroot path,
we only want the product path.
That product path will only have path of the product
but not the file name.
So I will add a plus sign here
and I will append another backward slash here
plus the file name.
That will have the final image URL.
And inside the product image
we will populate the product ID,
which is inside product view model.product.ID.
Then we have to populate this product image in a list
and we have that
inside product view model.product.product image.
But we will do one check here
if product view model.product.product image.
If that is now, then we will just initialize that.
So we will say product view model.product.product image
is equal to new and perfect.
That way we will not get an exception
if product image is null.
Once we have the product image
we basically have to add
the product view model.product.product image.add.
We will add the individual product image
that will be configured right here.
Now, once we do that, you can add that directly
using underscore unit of work.product image.add.
And there you can pass the product image.
Whoops, I scrolled up accidentally.
Let me go back here.
This is also perfectly fine,
but I want to show you another route here.
What you can do is outside this for each loop
you can directly call unit of work.product.update
and we will pass the product view model.product.
Let me call unit of work.save here.
And basically when we are updating the product
we want to save the product image.
If we go back to our repository in data access,
we have repository, product repository.
Where is that?
Here we can configure obj from db.product image
is equal to obj.product images.
Now, with that one line
entity framework core is super smart.
it will automatically do all the configuration
that is needed inside the product images table as well.
And with that
you will see real power of entity framework core
and that is all the configuration that is needed
to add product image.
When we update the product
it will automatically configure the product image.
So with that, let me remove everything in the comments here
and in the temp data I will say created
or updated successfully.
Let me run this.
We have done quite a few things here,
so let me see if everything is functional in the next video.