Instructor: Now we need to test
if everything is functional.
Let me break this out and open the www root folder as well.
Open that and I will add that right here.
Where is the file?
Perfect.
So here, let me go to content management product
and let me click edit, cotton candy.
It will create a new folder with the name of products here.
We will see that.
First, let me try to upload to image here and update.
Perfect.
It says product created updated successfully.
If I refresh the folder, I have that folder here and great.
We have product four.
If I add it here, that is the product ID.
Inside there, we have both the image.
Let me go to database here,
and we will open the bulky new here.
I will examine the product images table.
It should have two records.
Great.
All of that is done automatically
by Entity Framework Core.
Now, if I go back here and if I select one more image,
it should automatically add that in the same folder.
I will have to refresh here and great.
Finally, let me try to create a new product here.
Test.
I will have dummy information here
and let me upload to image there.
It will create the product.
Let me see what is the ID of the newly created product here?
That is seven.
It should create a new folder, product seven and perfect.
If we go to database
we have the new records right here, so great.
With that, we are able to upload all the images
and when we create a new product
we see all the records in product images.