Instructor: Now that the image functionality
for creating and updating is working as expected,
what I want to do is when we run the application,
I want to display all of the product on the absurd page.
So if the product has any image
when a user goes to update the product,
I want to display all the existing image
and that we will have to go
in the web project product we have observed
and we have the image tag that was there before,
but now we will have a collection of image
because there can be more than one image for a product.
We basically have to populate that
and pass it on to our view from the controller,
which is product controller.
We have the absurd get action method.
When we are updating,
we need to retrieve that product image.
If we take a look
at our repository inside the repository here,
we added something called as include properties
where we can include navigation property.
So in the include property here,
we can pass that as a string and that will be the model name
and that will be product images.
So here, where we are getting an individual product,
we can also pass include properties.
We want to include the product images,
name here must exactly match the name that we have
in DB context right here.
So if it is plural, including the casing as well.
P is capital and I is capital,
so we will have that exact name here.
If that is any different, things will not work.
With that, it will include the product images
for that product automatically using EF corp.
Once we have that navigation property in product populated,
we can iterate in for each loop and display all the product.
But first, we need to check
if model.product.productimages is not known,
then we will have a for each loop
and we will iterate through variable image
in model.product.productimages.
Inside there, let me add a div
and between that div, we will display the image.
So I will cut this image from here,
paste it right there and we need the image url.
That will be inside image.imageurl .
With that configured,
let me run the application and see if that works.
We will go to product here, add it.
I believe we had a few products there and perfect.
We see all the three product go back here,
dark skies and I did not add any image there,
but the new product that we added, perfect.
We have the two image.
We are able to display all the image for product
on the update product page.