Instructor: We have the image
that is being displayed here.
We can also add a delete button below each image.
So if a user wants to remove any image
they can remove that.
And of course, if they want to add,
when they are on the update here
they can always select a new image update.
And I believe with that,
now we have the three image.
So let me add a delete button right here.
We will go back to the Upsert here,
and we will have an anchor tag, asp-action,
let me call that delete image.
We will add some bootstrap classes of btn btn-danger,
and when we are deleting any image,
we need the image ID.
We will pass that as asp-route-imageId
is equal to @image.id.
Let me hide this here.
We will write delete there.
And let me add a bootstrap icon of the trash fill,
save that, we will have to rebuild this time.
Let me go to product, edit,
and perfect.
We have a delete button,
so let's make that functional.
We need to create an action method, delete image.
Let me do that right here.
In the parameter here,
we will receive image ID,
which will be an integer,
based on the image ID.
We will go to unitOfWork.productImage,
and we will retrieve the image that we have to delete.
Next, we will check if image to be deleted is not null.
In that case,
we need to check if the URL is also not null,
so if not string.isNullOrEmpty,
imageToBeDeleted.imageUrl.
As long as that is not null or empty,
we can retrieve the old image path and delete that.
We will have to get the old image path and delete that.
We are doing something similar right here,
so let me copy what we had in the delete
when we were deleting product.
This time we want to delete only the image directly.
So old image path, we have the web root path.
On top of that,
we will combine the image to be deleted
and we will trim the backward slash.
If the file exists, we will delete that,
and after that is done,
we will say unitOfWork.ProductImage.remove.
We want to remove that record from the database.
So imageToBeDeleted and underscore unitOfWork.Save.
Then let me add a temp data for alert.
We will display "delete successful".
Finally, we want to redirect back,
so return redirectToAction.
We want to return to the name of Upsert action,
and we want to navigate to that product ID
because if you know the Upsert action,
let me go to the get,
we need to pass the ID.
So right here we will pass ID is equal to
and we need the product ID,
which we can retrieve from this image to be deleted.
So right here I can say
integer productId is equal to imageToBeDeleted.
That product ID, we will pass that right here.
I believe that looks good for delete image.
Let me save this and restart the application.
We will go to product here.
Let me go to the new product
and try to delete an image.
I will also open the folder,
product seven, that has three image here.
Let me delete one.
It reloads the page and perfect.
It removes that from the location as well.
So you can see that is working as expected.
I have to press F5 to refresh,
and that goes away.
So now we can manage image for a product
from the Upsert page.