Instructor: One last thing
that we have to work on is on product.
When we delete any product
we have to make sure that we remove those images as well.
If we go back to the code
and scroll down where we have the delete action method
we had some logic to remove the old image,
but now we will have
to basically delete the complete directory.
And in that directory we can delete all the files.
We will know that directory from the product ID here.
So, let me scroll up.
Here, we had the code where we were creating that directory.
I will copy that and paste it right here.
We do not care about the file name, the product path.
We need the ID here.
We get that in the parameter.
That looks good.
The www route path we can get using
webHostEnvironment.the WebRoutePath.
So we will have the final path with the product ID.
We can check if that directory exists.
If it does, then we want to do some calculations here.
Rather than create directory, we want to delete that.
But before we delete the directory, we have to retrieve
all the files in that directory and remove each file.
We will retrieve all the files in a string array,
and I will call that file path,
where we will set Directory.GetFiles.
And then for each file in the file path,
we want to remove file.
So, we can save file.delete, and file path.
We will have to add system.io.File.Delete, and perfect.
So we are deleting the individual files here in that folder.
And finally we are deleting that directory.
Everything else here looks good.
Let me remove the commented code here and save that.
We are already running the application.
Let me create a new product.
I will upload three image here.
Perfect.
Let me go to the folder.
Refresh here.
Perfect.
10, 10 is the product.
If we edit here, that is the product.
Let me go back and delete that.
It got removed.
If I press F five here, perfect.
The folder is also deleted.
So all the credit functionalities
for product is working as expected.
In the next video,
let me work on displaying image right here.