-: Now on the homepage here
we do not want to load all the images
but rather, I want to load one of the image
and display that right here.
We will go back to the application
and we will go to home controller.
Let me go to customer.
Perfect.
We have the index here where when we are including
the category for product,
we want to include product images as well.
Again, make sure there is no spelling mistake here
and on top of that
we can pass multiple include properties with a comma.
Our repository is capable to handle that so this will work.
We also have the details here.
Let me make sure I load product image
when we are navigating to the details page as well.
After that, let me go to the index view, go to view.
Here we are displaying an image URL,
but now what we will have to do is
we will first have to check if there are any product image.
We will have an F condition.
I will say product dot product images is not null
and product dot product images dot count
must be greater than zero.
If that is the case, then let me copy this IMG tag,
paste it here, the SRC, we will get that from
product dot product images dot first or default.
We want to retrieve the first one on there,
we have image URL.
Now in the L spot, it basically means that
that product does not have any image,
so rather than going empty here,
I can display a fake image here.
And to display that I can add a link to placehold dot co,
define a random size, and PNG.
With that, let me save here all of that.
Let's go back and great.
Wherever we have the image it is being displayed.
If not, we have the placeholder.
Let me try to modify the product image for cotton candy.
Delete that, delete that, and delete that as well.
We need cotton candy.
Go to homepage and perfect.
That looks good.
Then let me add a few items to the cart here
which have image of course.
And then if we navigate the shopping cart
let me display the image here
before we work on displaying image in the details page.
So we will have to display in shopping cart.
Let me go there.
For shopping cart, we will go to the cart controller.
Where is that?
Right here.
We have the index.
When we are retrieving things here
product is already in include properties.
Now with EF core, you also have then include
but I am honestly not big fan of then include
because when we are including properties,
entity framework core is also tracking them.
So rather than making our repository way more
complex to include the dot then include,
we can manually include all the product image right here.
First, we will retrieve our innumerable
of all the product images from the database
and where we have the for each loop,
we can load cart dot product dot product images
is equal to product images dot where.
We can say U goes to U dot product ID.
That product ID must match the card dot product dot ID.
That way it will retrieve
and we will convert that to a list.
Perfect.
So now the product dot product images
in the shopping cart will be populated.
We can copy the condition that we added
on the homepage here, copy that,
and I will open the index view
or card controller where we have the image.
Let me paste it right there.
Here we also have to add a class of width hundred.
Let me do that in both the places.
We will have to navigate to
item dot product product images.
Copy that and paste it here.
Perfect. Let me save all, continue editing, save everything.
Rebuild the changes.
Rebuild the change.
We have an error here.
Whoops. Let me reach something is wrong.
Let me restart.
And I see an issue here.
For some reason, Stripe is added in the product controller.
Let me remove that and run the application.
Perfect. Let me go to our cart here and great!
Shopping cart is also looking much better.
Let me continue in the next video.