Instructor: Now what I want to do is
if I go to product here,
let me add image for all the product.
Like in "Cotton Candy" we have the front image.
I have added more images in the project resource,
so if you go there in the images,
you will see two image for "Cotton Candy."
I will add the back one here, hit update.
Let me see, that looks good.
Let me go back here, "Dark Skies,"
I will add the back image, update that.
"Fortune of Time."
Let me select front and back here.
Update that and let me go to the homepage.
Perfect! That looks good.
Let me go to product.
Next, we have "Leaves and Wonder."
Now when you select,
make sure that in here you see "Leaves and Wonder" comes
before the back image.
That particular image will be displayed
before the other one.
Which one is this?
"Rock in the Ocean."
Let me update that and the final one is,
"Vanish in the Sunset."
Perfect.
Let's hit the update and we go to the homepage.
Great!
Well, "Leaves and Wonder," we have the back image first,
so we will go to product here, delete this one
and upload the back one again.
Great! That should fix it.
If you want to take this one step advance,
what you can do is you can have a page
where you can manage all the image
and basically set an order or set a main image
that needs to be displayed.
You can create a new column in the database for that
and track which one is the main image for a product.
But we will not go into those complexities.
What we have right now looks good.
What I want to do now is on the details here,
I want to display both the image that we have added.
So we will have a carousel here and display all the image.
To get started, we can search for bootstrap 5 carousel.
Let me scroll down.
This one looks good.
Let me copy the step altogether.
Go back to our code
and we will go to home controller.
We have the details action, go to that view.
We have image right here,
remove that, make some space and let me paste that code.
Here we will have to get creative.
In order for carousel to work you can see,
we have to give the data-bs-slide
and we have to give it zero, one and two.
And then where we have the image src here,
if the index is zero, we have to give it a class of active.
So first what I can do is add an if condition.
If Model.Product.ProductImages is not null
and Model.Product.ProductImages.Count
is greater than zero, then we want a carousel.
So let me cut this carousel,
paste it inside the if condition.
After that for all the product image
we will have to iterate in a loop right here.
So we will have a foreach loop, variable,
let me call that imageWithIndex.
Inside we have Model.Product.ProductImages.Select.
And now we need projection
because we also want index of the image.
So we can project using select here that hey,
what we want from select is the image itself,
on top of that I want something like an index
and we want to convert that to a new object.
That object will be a custom object,
where first will be of the type, productImage
and that is image.
Next, what we want is the index itself.
So Index = index.
This index will automatically give us zero, one
and two values based on whatever index this image is
in the product images right here.
So let me go to the right here,
I have to add one more closing bracket here and perfect.
I believe that looks good.
Let me break it out in different lines,
so it is easier to read and perfect.
Inside there let me cut the button here,
paste it one time, scroll to the right.
We want the index here.
So I will add the @imageWithIndex.Index.
Now next thing that you notice here
is there is a class of active
and that only applies if the index is zero.
You do not see that on index one and two right here.
So we have to be more dynamic on how we assign class here.
We will say @imageWithIndex.Index,
if that is zero, then we want a class of active
else we do not want any class.
That looks good for the button.
We have to do something similar
with the carousel item as well.
Let me remove these two div.
We need a foreach right here.
Copy this, paste it here, add the closing bracket.
Active again will be based on the index.
So let me cut this here
and we'll say @imageWithIndex.Index., if that is zero
then we want the class of carousel item an active,
else we only want the class of carousel item.
Finally, we need the src here,
that will be inside imageWithIndex.ProductImage.
Inside there we have the ImageURL.
Now if you want for simplicity,
we can directly call this Image.
We can use whatever name we want.
So let me modify that and I believe this looks good.
We will have to save and go back here and perfect.
We have a slider here with the carousel
and if I move forward I can see the image.
That looks great!
We will have the same functionality
for the other products as well and perfect.
With that we have a nice carousel that we have implemented
to display all the image in product detail.