Instructor: One thing that I want to show is
in UserController we are using application DbContext.
Typically throughout the application,
we have directly used unit of work
and we avoid using application DbContext directly
in the controller.
So I want you guys to take that as an assignment
and modify the code in this particular file.
That way you only have to deal with unit of work
and like we have helper method of UserManager,
we also have something called
as a role manager that we can use.
So take that assignment.
You might have to Google some things
on how to access roles and other properties
and I want you to figure out a way to use unit
of work rather than application DbContext here.