Instructor: I hope you were able
to complete the assignment.
For that, we will have to update
the ApplicationUserRepository and the UserController.
In UserController,
we do not want the ApplicationDbContext anymore.
And in the constructor here, we will get UserManager.
RoleManager, that will be on IdentityRole and unitOfWork.
Rather than _db here,
we will say _unitOfWork
is equal to unitOfWork and roleManager.
Then let me go to the interface here,
and we will add an Update method
that will take applicationUser.
Implementation of that is pretty simple.
Right here, we will add the Update.
We will call _db.ApplicationUsers.Update.
That is what we have done so far, and that looks good.
Now, let me scroll down.
Wherever we have _db,
we need to replace that with unitOfWork.
We can say unitOfWork.ApplicationUser.
And where we have the .Include,
we basically have to cut this Company here.
And rather than FirstOrDefault, we have Get.
There, we can add includeProperties of Company.
That looks good.
For the RoleList here, we need to access all the role,
and that, we can access directly from roleManager.Roles.
Now, again, this is something that you might have to google
on how to access roles using roleManager.
That way, we can avoid going to unitOfWork.
But if you want, you can extend the role table
like we did with ApplicationUser.
Next, we have the CompanyList here.
That will be unitOfWork.Company.GetAll.
Finally, we need to populate role of the user.
We can do that in an interesting way, and let me show that.
First, we will use userManager.
On there, we have the method GetRolesAsync
that will get roles assigned to a user.
Now, in our case, we only assign one role to the user,
so we can do first our default and get the first one.
But inside here, you can see it expects the user object.
So we basically need to retrieve the user,
unitOfWork.ApplicationUser.Get.
We will get that based on the userId.
So u.ID is equal equal to,
and where is that userId?
We have that in the parameter here, so we can pass that,
and this is an async method,
so we will have to call the GetAwaiter.GetResult.
Let me break that in a separate line.
And after that, we can do FirstOrDefault.
That will automatically retrieve role of the logged-in user,
and that will give us a role of the userId
that we provide right here.
So we do not need this RoleID anymore. Let me remove that.
Now, if we scroll down, in the Post,
we, again, need to retrieve the oldRole.
So let me copy this, paste it right here,
and let me modify that.
Perfect, we need the userId
that is inside roleManagementViewModel.ApplicationUser.Id.
That way, we will retrieve oldRole of the user.
Then let me retrieve the ApplicationUser
that we were doing in the if condition.
Let me remove that.
And right here, we will retrieve that using unitOfWork
rather than _db.
Once we do that, where we have _db.SaveChanges,
that will be unitOfWork.Save,
and now we are not working with _db.
Because of that, we will have to explicitly call
unitOfWork.ApplicationUser.Update,
and we will pass the applicationUser that we retrieved
and modify it right here.
So perfect, that makes sense.
But in the current logic here, we have one error,
and that is we are only going in the if condition
if role is updated.
But what if a user has not updated a role
but they have modified a company?
So an account belongs to one company,
and user only wants to change company of that user.
How can we handle that right here?
Now, I know I am adding some new things here,
but we can do that in an else condition,
and I will show that.
We will say if oldRole is equal equal to SD.Role_Company,
and we can check the CompanyId.
If applicationUser.CompanyId is not equal
to the CompanyId that is selected in the dropdown
that is populated from the input field,
that means they have updated the company.
So in that case, we need to assign new CompanyId,
update the applicationUser, and save the changes.
That looks great. Let me open the API calls here.
And right here,
we will have to use unitOfWork with include properties,
and then we have to do quite some things here.
We are retrieving the userRoles,
and then we have the roles table.
We are finding the roleId of the user,
and we are modifying things here.
Ultimate goal that we had here
is to populate role of the user when we are displaying that.
We can do that in a simpler manner.
Using our userManager,
we have the helper method GetRolesAsync.
Then we need to pass the user object.
We will have to await and GetResult because it is an async,
and we can call FirstOrDefault.
With that, we no longer require all of this code.
Let me remove that. Then we will scroll down.
Here, we will have unitOfWork.ApplicationUser.Get.
That looks good.
And where we have to save the changes,
we will first have to call Update
because previously we were working on _db,
but that is not the case.
So Update, and then save the changes.
Perfect, with that, let me run the application
and see if everything is working as expected.
Let me log in here as an admin user,
and I will go to MANAGE USER.
We have a company account.
Let me modify the company here, and perfect.
You can see new company is assigned here. That looks good.
So with that, our managed user or rather UserController
is fully functional with our unitOfWork repository.