Instructor: One more thing that I want to add
in the course is what if in social logins,
how can we give Microsoft login?
For that, you will go to portal.azure.com
and you will search for app registrations.
We will click there
and we will create a new registration, call that bulky login
and what type of accounts will we allow?
We will allow accounts in any organizational directory
and personal Microsoft accounts.
Then we have to select a platform.
We will select that and we need a redirect U R I.
Let me run the application,
copy the local host U R I for now and paste it right here.
Select the register button.
And perfect. With that, we have few things right here.
First thing we need to create a client credential.
So let me create a client secret.
We'll call that bulky secret and the expiration.
Let me set that to be 24 months.
Let me add that.
Perfect. We have the secret ID here.
Now let me go back to the project here.
In the web project, I will select manage new get packages.
Whoops, let me stop the application,
and let me search for Microsoft dot
ASP net code authentication.
If I scroll down here, I should have Microsoft account.
Let me install that.
Perfect. That is done.
We will have to register that in program dot cs.
So copy this, paste it one more time.
We will say add Microsoft account.
There, we don't have app ID and Secret.
We have something called as Client ID and Client Secret.
Let me go back here.
I will copy the value that will be Client secret
and then client ID here.
We'll go to the overview tab.
We have that right here,
paste it there.
And I believe I forgot one thing in the web here
where we have the redirect, like in Facebook,
we have sign-in hyphen Facebook.
Here we have sign-in hyphen Microsoft.
Save that here and let me run the application.
We will navigate to register, collect Microsoft here.
Let me try that,
and it looks good.
Let me see.
Perfect. Registration is successful.
I can hit the register button.
And there we go.
If I log out
and next time when I go to log in here, I can use Microsoft,
select my email and it'll automatically sign me in.
So you can see how easy it was to implement
social sign in using Microsoft.