Instructor: What we did previously
is we downgraded our application to .NET 7
in order to deploy that from Azure Portal,
but we can also deploy that directly from Visual Studio,
as I said before,
and for that, let me go to SQL Database here.
We have the bulkymvc.
Let me delete that database.
We will delete that here.
Wait for that.
And while that is being deleted, let me go to App Services.
I can search here.
And we have the bulkymvc-dotnetmastery.
Delete that as well.
We need to copy the name here,
paste that, and delete.
Right, that looks good.
Let me go back here,
and from the Visual Studio,
if we right-click on the web project, select Publish there,
well, before we do that,
let me upgrade our version to .NET 8.
So, let me right-click here.
Edit Project File.
Make this .NET 8.
Let me open all the project files,
make them all .NET 8 here,
and save that.
Close all the tabs here,
and then we can open individual,
Manage NuGet Packages,
Include Prerelease here,
and let me update the package.
That looks good.
We have the models here.
Include Prerelease.
Perfect.
Where we have the DataAccess.
Let me update all of them.
And finally, we need the web project.
Let me handle that. Whoops.
Manage NuGet Package.
Update all the package.
We did the wrong update here. Decline that.
I need prerelease there, and update.
Whoops, decline that again.
I do not want the Stripe, but I want Microsoft.
That looks good.
Continue.
Perfect.
With that, let me close all the tabs,
rebuild the solution,
and great.
Let me run this to make sure that the project is good,
and we are getting an error here.
When I google that, it says that the new .NET 8 version
is not automatically installed,
so let me download the preview 2 here,
and let me download that.
When I started the application, I had preview 1,
and preview 2 has been released,
so even though we are adding that in the NuGet package,
it has not been installed on my machine.
That is why we saw that error message.
Let me install that, and I will close Visual Studio.
Perfect, that is complete.
Let me open the project again
and try to run that with .NET 8.
Perfect.
This time, it is up and running
and everything is looking good.
In the next video, let me work on deploying the application.