Instructor: Now we need to deploy the application.
Let me stop it here.
Right click on the web project, select Publish.
Previously we had a published profile
where we were deploying that using GitHub
and we had the CI/CD pipeline.
We do not want that anymore.
We want to start a new publish here.
We'll select Azure and we'll go with Windows.
It'll automatically sign me in here, and perfect.
You can see based on the subscription
it is displaying me the existing app services.
We want to create a new one here.
Let me select that.
I will call that bulky-dotnetmastery.
That name is available.
That looks good.
Resource group, let me put that on DotNetMastery-LiveProject
and we need a hosting plan.
I can use any of the existing
but right here I can select a new plan
and let me call that BulkyBookWebFreePlan
and it'll be the free one.
Let me use that and create that.
With that, we are creating the app service.
So let me wait for that.
Perfect. That is done here.
Let me select next here and finish that.
Publish profile,
it is successful here.
Let me close.
And we see the new published profile.
Now when we are using .NET 8, it is in preview.
Because of that, the deployment mode,
we will have to edit that.
And let me expand this.
That will be self-contained.
If it was .NET 7
then you can use framework dependent.
But with the preview version
you have to use self-contained.
We scroll down here and it is asking us for database.
We do not have that here.
So let me save this,
and if you scroll down in Visual Studio
you can see in service dependencies
it says that, "Hey, a SQL Server database is needed."
If I select + here
I will be able to create that dependency.
So we will search for SQL Server
and we have the Azure SQL Database.
Let me select the Azure SQL Database
and we will create a new SQL database directly
from Visual Studio.
You can give it whatever database name you want.
Resource group will be the same, DotNetMastery-LiveProject.
And then we will create a new database server.
And let me call that bulkybookliveserver.
We need a username and password.
Let me add that.
Scroll down, we have a confirm password.
Perfect. That looks good.
So we are creating a new database server.
But one thing that is missing here
is when we are creating a new server here
it does not give us the option to select what is the type,
like is it a DTU version?
It is a production development?
We do not get that.
So that is one limitation that we have right here.
Let me create and see what happens.
If you create the SQL Server directly from Azure Portal
then you will be able to select what size you want.
But we do not have that option in Visual Studio right now.
Now that is not a big deal
because I can always go to Azure and create that database
but I want to show you from Visual Studio.
That is why we are using this.
Perfect. That is done.
We will select that, hit the next button
and we have the connection string,
here we will have to write the username and password
based on that,
connection string will automatically get that.
After that we can copy the connection string,
and if we add it here,
let me scroll down where we have database,
we will have to replace that with the new connection string
that we copied
and we will select use this connection string at runtime.
Save that.
And if we notice in the web project,
we have appsettings.Production.
We can go there and modify the connection string
because that way it'll use that connection string
once the application is deployed.
Save that here
and let me publish.
Now while it is publishing,
let me switch back to Azure portal.
There let me go to SQL database
and we have the new database here.
Let me scale down
because I know the computing here will be higher scale.
So if we go to Compute + storage,
you can see the estimated cost is 15 here.
Let me scale that down to basic.
That is good for our testing.
We did not get that option in Visual Studio.
Let me also go to SQL Servers here,
we have the bulkybookliveserver
and there if we go to networking tab,
when we create this from Visual Studio
it automatically checks
allow Azure services and resource to access the server.
So that is a good thing.
You can also add your IP address if you want.
And with that, let me go back and wait for the deployment.
Perfect, it is loading the application.
Let me see.
And great.
You can see our application is up and running here
and that looks great.
Let me log in here with admin@dotnetmastery.com
and see if that works.
That is also good.
We go to product here
and let me upload an image for cotton candy.
Where is that?
Right here.
We go back here, and that image is coming along.