Educator: Now it's time for a third assignment.
This will be similar to what we did with the menu item
but a lot simpler.
In this assignment,
I want you guys to create a company model
which will have the following properties.
ID will be the primary key,
name will be required, and street address, city, state,
postal code, and phone number.
They can be optional field.
Once you create the table,
then you will have to add company to Repository
and UnitOfWork.
Using that repository,
you need to perform the CRUD Operations
on Company using DataTables.
And also we will implement one action for update and edit
so you will have to do the same like menu item.
So that will give you more practice with DataTable,
alerts that we have,
and, of course, validations will be the same.
So good luck with the assignment
and let's continue from the next video.