Instructor: Now in our project,
when we go to the details here
we cannot add items to the shopping cart.
And the reason is simple.
We do not have a model to store shopping cart in database.
Now there are multiple ways to store shopping cart.
You can obviously store all the shopping cart
in the session as well.
I always like to store that in database
because what typically happens
is when someone has items added to the shopping cart,
if we have that in the database
we can always track that,
hey, the item was in cart for three days
and we can send them promotional emails.
Because of those marketing that could be done
with the shopping cart,
it is always good to add that to a database.
So think about what will be all the properties
that are needed to add an item to the shopping cart?
For that, we will require what product has been added,
what is the count of that product,
and on top of that,
what is the user ID of the user
that added the shopping cart?
Because without user ID it will be a big mess
because any user can add an item.
So our model is pretty simple.
Let me switch back and stop the application,
close everything else here,
and we will be adding a new model.
Add a new class that will be shopping cart.
It will be a public class and it will have four properties.
We will have ID, which will be a primary key.
We have product ID and user ID,
and count will resemble to the quantity.
Product ID that we have here will be a foreign key
to the product table.
So let me add that foreign key and validate never
and we have the application user ID.
That will be foreign key to the application user table,
so we will add that as well.
Finally, where we have the count here
I can add a validation.
That range must be between 1 to 1000.
If it is not, we will display a custom error message.
So that looks good for the shopping cart model.
We have to add that to our database.
And thankfully with shopping cart
we will not have to seed any record.
So we have shopping cart here,
call that shopping carts,
and we have to add a migration.
I will call that add shopping cart to DB
and let me update the database.
Perfect.
So our shopping cart model has been added
to our database.
Let me continue from the next video.