Instructor: We have added shopping cart to our database.
We have to create a repository and add that to unit of work.
So as simple as it is, we will copy the category repository
and modify that for shopping cart.
We will change the interface name,
model will be shopping cart
and update will be shopping cart.
Perfect.
After the interface, we have to implement repository
so let me copy the category repository
and we will modify that to be the shopping cart repository.
We will modify all the names here.
Let me do that real quick
so you do not have to wait and watch
and, perfect.
That looks good.
Finally, we need the unit of work.
Inside unit of work, let me create that.
Perfect.
With that, we have configured unit of work
to use our repository and let me continue
from the next video.