-: For some reason,
if we have to work with our user,
then we should also create
an application user repository.
So let me do that real quick
before I continue on with the course.
It will be a simple application user repository
without any update functionality.
So let me paste that here, application user,
and it will not have anything to update.
That looks good.
Copy and paste the category repository,
rename that to be application user repository.
And let me modify the classes here.
Perfect, we do not need any update there.
That looks good.
Let me also add that to unit of work.
First, the interface here,
I application user repository,
and unit of work.
Application user is equal to new.
Application user repository
and underscore db.
Perfect.
With that, let me close the unit of work
and we have added
our application user repository.