Instructor: Now we want to work on one
of the main functionalities of how
to add an item to the shopping cart.
If I run the application here,
and if we go to the details here,
we have count and based on that
we can add item to the shopping cart.
So we have to enable the button here and work on that.
Let me stop the application.
That button was inside customer area views details.
Controller is the home controller.
So in the details here where we have the button,
I will remove the coming soon and where it's disabled.
That looks good.
I have a form here so it should be able to post
what is the count and what is the product.
But in order to post where we have the count input
we need to add the ASP4 tag helper
and that requires a model.
If I go to the top here, we do not have a model.
We have the product model but in product model
we do not have the count.
So what we basically need is we want a model
where we will have product
and we will also have a counter for our input.
If you examine the shopping cart
that we created in our models,
it has a product which will have to be populated
and on top of that it has the count as well.
So we have to modify the model in our details
from product to shopping cart.
When we do that, everything here will be broken
because rather than model,
it will have to navigate to model that product.
So let me modify that.
And perfect.
Now with that for ASP4, we can directly access the count.
And perfect, that looks good.
With that configured, let me run the application.
Now this time when you go on details
you will see an error message.
The error message is self-explanatory
so try to find out on what is wrong here.
I hope you were able to figure that out.
The issue is what we are passing on to the view.
If we go to home controller in details,
we are passing product, but in details,
we are telling that hey,
it should expect a shopping cart model.
To solve that, we will have to pass
a shopping cart object here.
Cart is equal to new and inside there we have the product.
I can cut this, paste it here.
On top of that, I can set the default count to B1
and I can also populate the product ID.
That is the product ID.
When we return back to the view,
we have to pass the cart here and that looks good.
With that configured, if I go back, perfect.
The details is now visible and we have the count.
In the next video,
let me work on the post action method for details.
That way we will be able to add items to the shopping cart.