Lecturer: Now it's time to work on the post action method
for details.
So let me copy and paste that and it'll be Http post.
The model that we will receive here will be shopping cart.
Now if we go to the details here
we will be receiving the count
but we will not receive product ID
because that is not inside any input properties.
We will have to add a hidden input field for product ID.
That way in the home controller when we receive
shopping cart, the product ID will be populated.
But on top of that
when we have to enter a record in the shopping cart table
we need user ID of the user that is logged in.
So this Http post
we have to add the authorized keyword
because if someone is posting,
they must be an authorized user.
We do not care what role they have
they just have to be logged into the website.
That is why we will use authorized keyword here
without any role.
Now that is good that a user is authorized
but how will we get that user ID of the logged in user?
We have helper method for that.
So we will first have to get something which is
a claims identity that is inside user object
that is provided by default dot
we have the identity
we have to explicitly convert that to claims identity.
So let me do that.
Now from that claims identity
there is a special claim with the name
of name identifier that will have user ID
of the logged in user.
These are the default methods that are provided
by the dot net team and I'm not reinventing anything
just accessing them right here.
So user ID is inside the claims identity dot find first
and we want to find a claim type dot name identifier.
This name identifier is nothing but a constant
and that is where the user ID will be stored.
When a user logs in, we have to access dot value
and that way the user ID will be populated.
Now in order to show that, let me actually
add a debugging point here and restart the application.
Let me go to details and if I select add to cart
it'll ask me to log in.
So let me log in as a customer here and perfect.
Now, if I click add to cart
It hits our breakpoint.
And if you examine we have a claims identity
and insight there we have all the claims there.
If you examine, we have name identifier
and that has the user ID.
That is the user ID that we want and that user ID
we have to add to the shopping cart when we create a record.
So if I press F10 again here
user ID is populated and that looks good.
So perfect.
Let me stop the application.
We have the user ID and the product ID will be
inside the shopping cart model.
So all we have to do is say shopping cart dot application
user ID is equal to the user ID
and then we have to add that shopping cart.
To add that we will say underscore unit of work
dot shopping cart dot add,
we add the shopping cart and we say underscore unit of work
dot save.
With that let me run the application and see what happens.
I will open the database here, let me refresh the tables.
Shopping cart is empty.
And let me go to details here.
We will have to log in again and let me add three items.
Add to cart.
Now it hits an exception.
Can you try to find out on why it hits an exception?
The reason is in home controller
when everything is successful
we are redirecting back to the view.
But this details view expects a shopping cart
that is not provided here.
So basically everything was done
and then it returns back to the view.
So if I go to the shopping cart, perfect
we have the entry right here.
All we have to do is if I go back and continue
rather than returning back to the view
I would have to redirect them to the homepage.
Now, when we redirect them to the index action method
rather than writing the magic string here
we have something called as name of.
And there it provides name of all the action method
inside this controller.
So that way you can see we avoid the spelling mistakes
and we avoid magic string.
With that, let me run the application again.
Let me go to the details here
and let me update the count to be one,
we will have to log in.
Perfect that work.
But if I go to database, previously the count was three.
I logged in with the same user
and I updated the same product.
But you can see what is happening here
it is adding duplicate entries in the table.
We do not want that.
If the product ID already exist
then we have to update the count,
else we have to add a new entry.
We will have to clear things here.
So we will say delete and let me drop all the three rows.
But now we need to figure out that, okay
if a cart already exists for that user and that product
then we have to update
else we will create.
Let me do that in the next video.