Instructor: Now we need to figure out a way
to make sure that Cart does not already exist
while that User and ProductID.
Both of them must match.
Only then, it is a duplicate entry.
So, what we can do, is we can go to ShoppingCart
and get CartFrom database,
so will say _UnitOfWork.ShoppingCart.Get
and we want to get a ShoppingCart where U.ApplicationUserId
is equal equal to UserId and, on top of that,
we want to make sure that ProductId is also same.
So, ProductId is equal equal to ShoppingCart.ProductId
If there is any entry in the database,
with both of them matching,
so if CartFromdb is not null,
in that case, the ShoppingCart already exists.
In the else part here, we have to add a Cart.
Let me cut add Cart here and paste it here,
but now, how do we update the ShoppingCart?
Well that, what we can do is CartFromdb
is retrieved from the database.
So, we can say, CartFromdb.Count plus equal to
and we can add the Count that is inside ShoppingCart.Count
That will give us the new Count.
Once we have the new Count, on UnitOfWork.ShoppingCart
we have Update, we can invoke that.
With that configured, let me run the application
and see if that works.
I will log in with the same user of Customer here
and let me go to the same product, Dark Skies.
Right now, I do not have any product,
because I deleted everything.
Let me add three items.
That worked.
Let me see, perfect.
Let me try to go to Details and add four more
and if I execute here, we see an issue.
It creates a new record here.
Let me add a debugging point
and I will try that once again.
Count one, that is fine.
CartFromdb is not null, perfect.
It is calling it Update,
but still it is creating a new record
and the reason is if we examine the ShoppingCart here,
you can see the Id is zero.
The issue that we have here is in Update.
We should be passing the Cart that we retrieved
from database, that is where we have the new Count.
With that saved, let me remove debugging point.
We will have to delete things again here.
Let me do that, perfect,
and let me run this.
We will go to Details.
I will have to log in first
and let me try to add 3 Count.
Go to database, that works, add 1 more Count here,
and let's see, perfect.
Now, the Count is updated successfully,
and if I try to add a new product,
we should see a new entry with the different ProductId.
That works and, with that, we are able to add entities
to the ShoppingCart.