Instructor: Now, let me show you something odd.
Let me switch back to the code here
and let me comment out this Update statement.
With that commented out, let me run the application again
and see what happens this time when we try to update.
So, let me log in again as customer here.
And let me go to Details.
Add this 10 items.
I will go back here. Count is four and three.
When we hit Add To Cart, what do you think would happen?
You would think that
because you commented out that Update statement,
nothing will happen.
But, to your surprise, if we refresh here,
you can see count is updated to 14 from four.
How did that magic happen?
We do not have the Update statement that has been invoked.
So, how can it update that?
Answer to that is power of Entity Framework Core.
What happens here is right here on line 46,
you are retrieving a ShoppingCart.
When you retrieve something with Entity Framework Core,
it is constantly tracking that.
And then on line 56-
well, not here, on line 51,
we have updated count of a shopping cart
or an object that was tracked by Entity Framework Core.
So, it is tracking that okay.
You have updated account of the ShoppingCart object
and when we are calling unitOfWork.Save,
it will go ahead and update that change.
So, even though you are not calling Update here,
Entity Framework Core is already tracking that
and because of that it will automatically update.
The feature that is provided with Entity Framework Core
is a great feature.
But, in some situations, if you are not careful,
it can be harmful for your application.
Because of that, what I personally like
is when I am retrieving something using the Get,
it should not track that entity.
We can change that default behavior in the Repository.
What we can do is-
let me go to our Repository
and where we have the Get,
right here,
let me add one more property, which will be Boolean flag.
And, by default, it will be false.
Let me save that
and we will have to stop the application.
Implement that in the Repository
where we have the Get right here.
I will add that tracked flag here
and then, basically, we will have to add an if condition.
If tracked is true,
then whatever we are doing here, that looks good.
But, if tracked is false,
then we will have to modify things.
So, I can copy that, paste it in the else here
and where we have the dbSet,
we have to add the AsNoTracking.
That will make sure that Entity Framework Core
does not track the entity that is being retrieved.
With that configured, let me run the application.
And now, if you add items to the cart,
it will not automatically update the count.
Let me add 12 more here.
We have to log in. I forgot that.
And let me try updating six more.
If I go back to SQL server,
this time the count does not get updated
and that is how it should be.
When you have to update anything,
you should be explicit about that.
Only then it should work.
Before I end the video, if I go back to the Repository,
we have a false code here
and there is many repetition right here.
We can simplify that by taking the query out,
pasting that out of the if-else condition.
And the Iqueryable, we will add that right here.
If tracked, then we will say query is dbSet.
Else, we will say query is equal to dbSet.AsNoTracking.
That looks good.
Let me restart the application.
And perfect.
With that, it should be functional.
Now, all we have to do is enable the Update statement here
and, with that, it will be able to update ShoppingCart.
Let me log in again here.
And for the Dark Skies,
update by four.
We had 14.
And perfect. Now, it's 18.
With that, we have learned an important thing with EF Core,
which is AsNoTracking.
One thing before I go is,
if I go back, and where we have the ShoppingCart,
we can add some TempData to display notification.
So, right here I will say, "Cart updated successfully."
Let me restart
and make sure we see the toaster notification.
And perfect. That works.
With that in place, let me continue from the next video.