Instructor: Now we want to work on the
shopping cart controller so we can display everything
on the UI and display a shopping cart.
For that, we will have to do quite a few things.
First thing, we need to create a controller
and we will do that in the customer controller.
Make our shopping cart will be customer facing
and let me call that as cart controller.
Inside there we have the index action.
Let me right click.
Go to view does not work.
We have to add the view.
Let me create the index view.
Now, where I have the underscore layout,
we need to add a shopping cart icon there.
So let me scroll there
and let me copy an L I.
Well, it's inside dropdown.
Let me copy this one.
Paste it outside of the comment here.
The area will be customer
but controller will be cart controller.
And what do we want to write here?
I will be using the bootstrap icon.
So class is P I P I card,
and by default, let me display zero inside there.
With that, let me run this and see
if we are able to navigate to the index page.
Our shopping cart looks good.
If I click there, we go to customer cart and privacy.
Whoops. The action method will be index.
That was the culprit.
If I go back here and if I click there
you can see it says the page cannot be found.
Can you try to find out or think of a reason on
what we are missing?
If you said, we did not mention the area here,
you are correct.
We have to give that a area of customer,
and that should fix the issue.
We will have to rebuild here.
Let me wait for that.
And if I click this time,
Perfect. Empty page is being loaded here.
Now we do not want to waste our time in writing
H T M L and C S S.
Because of that, in the project resource snippets,
we are in section 10.
I have the shopping cart UI
which is purely H T M L and C S S .
You can copy that and paste it in the index view
for the shopping cart.
Save that, and if you go back,
perfect.
You have a basic template that is up and running
and now all you have to do is retrieve that
shopping cart and modify all the properties here.
Let me do that in the next video.