Instructor: We need to display all the items
in the shopping cart and this page must be authorized.
Let me switch back to the application
and where we have the cart controller with the area,
I will say
that only authorized user are able to access the page.
Now inside the index action here, we have to
retrieve the shopping cart and pass that to our review.
But if I examine the shopping cart model that I have
I only have product ID
and user ID along with the product details.
In shopping cart, we also want to show the order total.
We need additional property along
with an I innumerable or a list of shopping cart.
For that, we will have to create a view model,
and let me create and call that shopping cart VM.
We will make that a public class here,
and what will be all the properties?
One property that I can think of is an I innumerable
of shopping cart, and let me call that
shopping cart list. That will be more meaningful.
Along with that, I can have a double
which will be order total.
Those are the two properties I can think of right now
but when we move ahead
we will change the view model based on our requirement.
For now, this looks good.
If I go to cart controller
I need to populate the shopping cart.
For that I will have to get the unit of work.
Let me get that with dependency injection.
And on top
of that we will have the shopping cart view model.
Then in the index section we have to retrieve shopping cart
for a user.
For that, we will require the user ID,
and we know how to get that.
We did that in the home controller.
We have the claims identity.
Let me copy these two lines and paste it right here.
Based on the user ID we can populate the shopping
cart view model is equal to new,
and there we will populate the list is equal to
_unitofwork.shoppingcart.getall.
We want to get all based on u.applicationuserID.
and for some reason it is not working.
Let me examine the repository that we have.
And I will open the I repository.
And whoops, where we have the get all,
we are not accessing the link function for our filter.
I will add that logic, close the interface.
And in the implementation we will have to add the filter.
Perfect. With that, if I close everything other
than the cart controller, let me do that.
And the index action.
Now we can say application user ID is equal equal
to the user id.
When we retrieve shopping cart,
we also want to include product.
We will say include properties, and this will be product.
Here, you have to make sure it is case sensitive.
It must be the exact model name.
With that, let me save that and we will pass
the view model back to the view.
Now here, let me add a debugging point and run
the application to see if that works.
We have error here.
Let me see what that is, and let me open the error again.
We forgot to add the filter.
Let me do that. And perfect.
That should work.
Well, we will have to make that an optional
because it will not be required every time.
And that makes perfect sense.
Let me open the interface as well, and where
we have the get all filter will be optional.
Because if we want to retrieve all the categories, then
we do not want to pass any filter.
Filter will be only applied
if filter is not null.
And perfect.
We are making our repository more dynamic.
Let me run this and see.
Whoops, that did not happen.
I did update the repository. And where we have
the filter, we will have to explicitly define null there.
Perfect. Let me go to shopping cart.
When we log in, we hit our break point.
And let me examine.
We have the cart list here.
and great. It has the items.
That looks good.
Based on that, we will have to populate the order total here
before we proceed further.
Let me do that in the next video.