Lecturer: Where we have the index get action method,
we are populating the shopping cart view model.
But in that view model,
if we press F12 here,
we have the OrderTotal that we have to calculate.
Calculating that OrderTotal is a little bit tricky,
because based on the quantity we have different price.
Like if we have this book for an example,
if the quantity is between one to 50,
the price is $30.00,
more than 50 it's $25.00,
and more than 100 it is $20.00.
When we display the OrderTotal we need a helper method,
that will calculate based on quantity,
which price should be utilized.
So let me create that helper
inside the Cart Controller right here.
We can make that method a private method.
Return type will be double,
and let me call that GetPriceBasedOnQuantity.
And the parameter here we will be passing ShoppingCart,
and that looks good.
Based on that we can check
if(ShoppingCart.Count <= 50).
In that case,
we want to return the default price,
so that we have inside ShoppingCart.Product.Price;
In the else part here we will have an if condition.
If (ShoppingCart.Count <= 100),
In that case we want to return
ShoppingCart.Product.Price50;
It has to be less than 100,
else if it is greater than 100 then we will
return ShoppingCart.Product.Price100;
Based on that,
whatever cart we pass here,
we will know what is the price that we have to use.
Right here where we have the ShoppingCart view model,
we have to iterate through each one of the cart.
So (variable cart in ShoppingCartVM.ShoppingCartList).
We have the ShoppingCartList there,
and we have to calculate the Cart.Price.
Right here we can add a
double price = GetPriceBasedOnQuantity,
and we will pass the shopping cart.
Now using that price,
we can calculate the
ShoppingCartVM.OrderTotal
+= (price * cart.Count).
Perfect.
I believe that looks good.
Let me restart the application,
and see if we are able to calculate the total price.
Let me go to our shopping cart,
and we examine the view model.
Perfect.
We have an order total here based on
the price and the count that has been added.
So some number is coming up,
if that is true or false,
we will see in the upcoming lectures.
But right now this logic is working.
Now one thing that I want to modify is,
what if I want to display this price on the UI?
I do not have that in the view model.
We can add that to our view model,
but that will depend on each shopping cart item.
In a perfect situation,
we have to add that inside the shopping cart model.
Let me open that.
And we do not want to add that to the database.
We only want for display purposes,
so we will add a double price,
and we will add not mapped.
Because of that,
it will not create this column in the database,
and we are good.
Now here,
rather than storing that in double.price
I will store that in cart.Price.
We will use that here,
cart.Price.
And that way we will have that particular price
calculated and assigned inside the shopping cart.
We have spent quite some time
to get all the items for our shopping cart.
In the next video,
let me replace everything that we have with a static HTML,
with what we are passing here from the Index Action method.
Which is a shopping cart view model.