Instructor: From the index section
we are returning a shopping cart view model.
That will be the model
for our index page inside the cart views.
So we will define model
and that will be shopping cart view model.
Based on that, let me modify other things here
and let me run this.
That way we can see everything that needs to be updated.
And let me go to the shopping cart here.
Perfect.
First, when we click continue shopping
it should take us back to the homepage.
We have continue shopping here rather than href.
We will say ASP area will be the customer area.
ASP controller will be home controller
and ASP action will be index action.
Then let me go back and whatever we see right here
that we will have to repeat every time
for all the items in our shopping cart.
So we need a for each loop
and we will have to iterate through that.
That is inside the column medium 10 here.
We will add a for each loop variable item
in model dot shopping cart list,
and the closing bracket.
Let me remove that.
We will add that right here.
Perfect.
Now if I save this and if I go back,
we have two items
and you can see it is being duplicated two times.
Let me fix the image here.
That will be inside item dot product dot image URL.
Let me see and great.
Looking good.
The title here will be inside item dot product dot title.
Let me copy this.
Next, we have the description.
For description, we need HTML dot raw
and we will paste the item dot product dot description.
Next, we have the price here.
That will be item dot price.
We'll use dot to string and see for the currency count
will be inside item dot count.
The price that we see here
will be the price based on the quantity
because that is the price in shopping cart
that we are calculating based on the count that we have.
If I open that, it is right here.
So let me save that and let's go back.
Perfect.
UI is looking good here.
After that, we have the patterns to update the quantity
or remove an item that we will cover in the upcoming video.
But before that,
let me display order total.
We will go back, let me scroll down.
Where is the total?
Right here.
We need to display that
from model dot order total dot to stringing,
convert that to currency.
Let me see.
And great.
With that in place
everything is looking much better.
Now, in the next video,
let me work on the plus, minus,
and delete here to update our shopping cart.