Instructor: Now we want to implement
increment, decrement, and remove item from Shopping Cart.
If I go back and look at the code,
we have all of them right here.
So what we can do is where we have the anchor tag,
we can call a new action.
And for increment, let me call that as plus.
For decrement, let me call a new action which is minus.
And for delete here we will have an asp-action of remove.
When we are updating any quantity,
we need to know the cart Id.
Based on that, we can toggle the quantity.
So when we are calling the action here,
we need to pass the Id,
which will be cart Id as a parameter.
So asp-route
and let me call that cart Id is equal to item.Id,
copy that and paste it for all three of them.
Perfect.
Now we need to create this action method
in the cart controller.
In the index here we have not defined any controller.
Because of that, it will look inside the same controller.
And for that we can directly create controller action.
And I will do that before the private method
that we have here.
That way, all the action methods stay together.
We will create the first action method
which will be public IactionResult, name will be Plus here.
And the property that we will receive here
will be integer cartId.
So what will be the return type here?
Well, we will return back to the view
after we increment the Count.
In order to increment the account,
we first have to retrieve the Shopping Cart
from database using unitOfWork.ShoppingCart.Get,
and we will get that based on the Id.
So, u dot Id is equal equal to the cart Id.
Once we retrieve that, we have to update the count.
So cartFromDb dot Count plus equal to one.
And after that we have to call
unitOfWork.shoppingCart.update cartFromDb,
and unitOfWork.save.
That will update the cart, but once we update,
we have to return back to the index view
of the card controller,
which will be the Shopping Cart page.
So we can say return RedirectToAction index,
but rather than magic string we can use nameof
and we can use index.
So Plus here looks good.
Let me copy and paste that here for Minus.
And in case of Minus,
we have to be careful about one thing,
if the Count is equal to one.
In that case, we want to remove that item
because we do not want an item with count of zero
in the Shopping Cart.
So we can say if cart.Count is equal equal to one,
or we can say if less than equal to one,
then we want to remove that from Cart.
In the else, we will decrease the count by one,
and we will save the changes.
So let me cut this from here, paste it inside.
And where we have to remove that,
we can say _unitOfWork.ShoppingCart.remove,
we want to remove the cartFromDb.
With that configured, the Minus also looks good.
Copy and paste that again.
The last one is Remove,
and that we only want to remove,
so we can remove everything else.
And perfect.
I believe that looks good.
Let me press Control + A, Control + KD
to align everything here.
And perfect.
That looks great.
Let me restart the application and see if that works.
Perfect. Let me go to Shopping Cart here.
Let me select the minus button and great.
The TOTAL as well as the Count here was updated.
You can see it is modifying both of them.
Let me try to remove them more,
and perfect.
Looks good.
If I remove this further, let me make the quantity of one.
And now if I remove,
it should delete this item from the Shopping Cart.
That works.
Let me try to add one more item here,
and I will go to the Cart.
Let me click Delete here, and perfect that also works.
So increment, decrement, and remove functionalities
are working as expected.