-: Now that we have the create page that is looking great
let me apply the same style on the other pages.
It is pretty simple.
Where we have the form here,
let me delete that for a second,
and this will be kind of a template that we want.
So copy that and then bring back the form
by pressing Ctrl Z or undo the changes here.
Create is back to what it was.
Let's work on delete.
We will paste what we copied here
and we will cut the form, paste it right here.
Do the same for edit as well
but I think I copied the wrong div
so I'll have to copy this again.
Go to edit, copy this, paste it again, and let me zoom in.
Cut this, and we will paste it within the card body.
Perfect. Let me run the application and see.
We also have to make them floating
so I can copy this div here.
Go to delete, paste it right here.
Whoops, what happened?
It pasted the wrong thing.
Let me copy and delete, paste it here.
We did not need validation and this will be disabled.
Let me copy this and paste it again for display order.
Perfect. That looks good.
Go to create.
Copy that once again
and modify the edit here, paste that two times.
Name and display order.
Let me switch back to the project.
It's already running, and we have hard reload
so let's go to create.
Well, create is done.
Let me try edit.
That looks much better.
I need some margin here.
Margin top three and delete as well.
And let's see.
Perfect. Looks good.
We do not need the edit category.
Let's remove that.
Well, let me change it first
and remove that row, edit as well.
And perfect.
Let's wait for the hard reload.
Great. Delete.
That also looks perfect.
Finally, let me modify the category list here.
Let me switch back here where we have the index here.
Go to my notepad, copy the template, paste it right here.
And I do not think I need the container here
but let me cut everything else here
and paste it in the card body.
Let's go back and see.
Looks much better.
We do not need the category list anymore.
Remove that.
No padding here.
And let's see.
Well, I'll take the padding bottom here,
and let me see.
Perfect. That looks much better.
The heading here will be category list,
and that looks good.