Instructor: We have multiple projects in our solution,
but right now everything is bundled
inside BulkyWeb project.
We want to move that from BulkyWeb
to the individual projects, so let me do that.
We will move the data folder to DataAccess.
That project will be responsible
for all the data-related operation.
Once we move that, make sure to delete
the data folder here.
And then we have Models.
That we will move inside the Models project
and we will delete the Models folder from BulkyWeb.
Finally, in the utility here,
let me add a new class, and I will call that SD
for static details.
This will be a public static class
and there we will have all the constants
for our website.
Perfect.
And when we are working with data here, we have Migrations.
That also we will move inside the DataAccess
and we will delete migrations from BulkyWeb.
Because we moved quite a few things
in the DataAccess project, we need the NuGet packages
related to Entity Framework Core inside DataAccess.
If you open ApplicationDbContext
you can see we have all the errors here.
If you press Control + . here
typically it does show you the package
that needs to be installed
but it is not displaying that
so I can right-click Manage NuGet Package here
and right now when you click on the project
it will display that project
but you can click on the solution here
and if you click Manage NuGet Package
it will display all the packages for the solution.
So EntityFrameworkCore, we can install that
and DataAccess.
Next, we need the tools package, as well.
And I believe that should be sufficient.
Let's go back, and perfect.
The errors went away.
If we examine the dependencies packages, we have those, too.
That looks good.
Let me examine if migrations have any error.
Nope, that looks good.
We need the SqlServer here, as well.
So let me add that.
Manage Packages for Solution.
And SqlServer.
Perfect, that looks good.
Now we have more errors with the models
because the namespace have been updated.
Well, technically, they have not been updated
but I will update them.
If I open ApplicationDbContext
you can see it is inside BulkyWeb.
That is not true.
Now it should be Bulky.DataAccess
and then we have the data.
So let me copy that here
and I will modify the Migrations, as well.
Let's do that.
And perfect. That looks good.
This BulkyWeb will be DataAccess, as well.
And great, I believe that looks good here.
Let me save everything.
And the Models here will be different, as well.
That will be Bulky.Models
but Bulky.Models is not accessible here
so we will have to right-click here.
Add project reference
and we want to add models and utility project.
With that, if you press Control + . here, perfect.
We now have the BulkyWeb.Models
and let me try to build only the DataAccess right now
and let's see if that works.
And we have few errors right here.
Migration could not be found.
Let me press Control + . here
and we have to install the NuGet package
so let's do that.
We do not have the data here.
We need the updated statement, and that looks good.
Let me try to build that once again.
Perfect, we have the same issue here.
Add the using statement.
And let me try that once again.
There are a few errors with the SeedCategoryTable
but let me worry about that later on.
Let me close everything right now
and we have to change the namespace
in the Models Project, as well.
This will be Bulky.Models.Models
but rather than that, let me move it directly
in the Models here, and that way
it will be directly Bulky.Models.
And perfect.
Both of them looks good here.
Save that.
If I build this, it should work.
Perfect. Utility Project is also fine.
Now let's try the DataAccess, rebuild that one.
And we have the Models error here.
Fix that with the using statement.
And then finally, we'll get back
to the elephant in the room,
which are these two error message.
Now I want you to pause the video
and try to find out on what is going on here.
If you Google, you will not find that,
but you need to focus something
with the files that are open right here.
I hope you were able to figure that out.
Basically, when you see Migration,
they have the Designer file and the .cs file.
Namespace, we updated that in the .cs file
but not in the Designer file.
That is why we have this issue.
So here we have to change that
to be Bulky.DataAccess.Migration
and then the error goes away.
We will have to do that in both the places here,
that way it will link the cs file
and the Designer file,
and now if we build the DataAccess, that works.
So perfect.
Our DataAccess, Models, and Utility are working.
Let me close all here.
So now for the BulkyWeb, let me run the project here
and it will automatically display all the error message.
There we go. Let me handle them one by one.
We need to remove the old namespace,
press Control + .
and we will have to add a reference to the other project,
DataAccess and Models.
Perfect. That worked.
Let's see the other one.
Next, we have the category.
The other errors are inside the views
so we will fix that later.
We have one in program.cs.
I can handle that one.
And we need to go to Views
to fix the other errors.
Perfect, so View, we have the error
and here we have the ErrorViewModel.
Now rather than writing everywhere here,
like Bulky.Models.ErrorViewModel,
what we can do is we can add this Bulky.Models
in the global using statement
for the BulkyWeb Project.
That we will do inside the ViewImports file.
So here, we can say using,
we have the Bulky.Models,
and once we save that, this using statement
will be available for all the Views right here.
So then we no longer have to add this particular line
and you can see ErrorViewModel as being readable.
Let me build it once again.
We should see fewer errors
because we added the global model statement,
and great, all the errors have been resolved.
So even though it was a lengthy video,
I did not want to implement the interior architecture
from the beginning.
It would have been simpler, for sure,
but many times what happens is
you start simple, and then as the complexity grows,
you separate things out.
Everything that we did in this video
will give you some practice on how to separate things out
if it is needed in your project.
With that configured, let me run the project
and see if everything is working as expected.
Perfect, we have the create, edit,
and all the pages are loading as expected.
But now our application is much cleaner.
We have multiple projects in our solution.