Instructor: We have the homepage and the details page
that are working as expected.
With that covered,
I want to work on authentication and authorization
and scaffolding identity with the .NET project.
When we talk about identity,
we think directly about registration, log-in,
what if the password is invalid,
how to create all of those tables in the database,
and making sure that security is top-notch.
But when it comes to .NET project,
we do not have to worry about all of that.
The .NET team provides a default identity implementation
that we can use with confidence
because it is built and provided by the .NET team.
And that basically lifts off all the heavy lifting
and we can trust the code that is being written.
But how do we add that identity,
which is, login, registration
and everything related to that, to our project.
To get started, on the web project we will right click, add,
and we will select new scaffolded item.
There we have identity and we can select that.
Now, in the later versions of .NET 8,
the identity might get updated.
If that happens, I will update the course as well.
But this is what it is right now.
On the top here
if we want a different master page, we can select that.
If not, we can leave that.
But then you can see all of the files
that are provided by the identity team.
We have many pages here for login, logout, set password,
register, reset password, and much more.
You will not need all the pages right here.
So what we can do is, we can select the pages that we want
but before I do that, we have something called as DbContext.
Now we already have a DbContext in the data access
but you can see that is not being detected here.
The reason it is not being detected
is not because it is in its own project.
It is because when we have a DbContext for identity,
we need to do some configuration
and we will do that before we continue.
If I open the DbContext that we have,
which is ApplicationDbContext,
that basically implements the DbContext.
But if you have to implement the identity,
then we have to implement something
called as IdentityDbContext.
And if you press control + dot here,
we have to install the NuGet package,
Microsoft.AspNetCore.Identity.EntityFrameworkCore.
We can install that package directly from here,
or we can say install with package manager,
opens the package manager here
and we can install the .NET 8.
Let me do that.
Perfect. That is done.
Once that is done,
we have to add that using statement
and the error goes away.
Now that is the only change that we have to do.
But when we use IdentityDbContext,
if we run our project, something will fail.
And let me show that.
We see an exception here, the entity type IdentityUserLogin
requires a primary key to be defined.
I will not go into much details about what is going on here
but basically where we have the ApplicationDbContext
if you have OnModelCreating,
there basically you will have to write
this one piece of line.
And that is because
keys of identity tables are mapped in the OnModelCreating,
and if this particular method is not called
then you will run into the error message.
So, ignore all the details here.
It is one of the configuration that is needed.
So when we have IdentityDbContext
we have to add base.OnModelCreating(modelBuilder)
and with that, if we run the project here
it should work again.
And perfect.
You can see the application is coming up here,
we can navigate to the details
and everything is working the same.
But basically the DbContext now is implementing
the IdentityDbContext rather than simple DbContext.
With that change of IdentityDbContext,
if we right click on the web project
and if we try to scaffold the identity here,
let me do that,
and by default let me override all the files,
but the DbContext, you can see
it automatically now detects ApplicationDbContext
because that has IdentityDbContext.
With that configured,
let me hit the add button.
This might take a while,
so let me wait for all the scaffolding to be done.
And perfect,
you can see that completed successfully.
And in the git changes here,
you can see there are 79 changes.
So quite a few things have been changed here
and many things have been added.
Let me walk you through all of that in the next video.