Instructor: Scaffolding identity is one
of those things that has always some issues
from what I have encountered,
and this time also it is no different.
When we scaffold identity,
if I directly run the application,
you will notice we have an exception here,
where we are seeing a weird exception with unit of work.
Now, because I have worked with identity
and I know what exactly they are doing, basically
they have added a new application DbContext rather
than using the existing application DbContext.
Now, why they are doing that, I have no idea,
but identity has always had these issues.
So, to fix that, you can just search
for application DbContext
and you can see in areas identity
they have added a new application DbContext, as well,
which is not needed.
This application, DbContext, is basically implementing
the identity DbContext.
That is what we had in our application DbContext, as well.
And you can see the base.OnModelCreating.
That is what we added, as well.
The only thing that we do not have
in our application DbContext is the identity DbContext.
We have not defined the default user.
That is not required, it is optional,
but you can always define that and perfect.
With that, it is exactly the same.
So what we can do is close everything here,
and let me delete the application DbContext
that is inside the bulky book web project.
We do not need that.
With that deleted, let me try to build the solution.
Perfect.
Everything is successful.
Let me try to run the project and see if that works.
And perfect.
Everything is functional.
So, now, our application is working as expected
with identity being scaffolded.
And with that configured now let me walk you
through all the changes in the next video.