Instructor: Before we proceed further,
let me walk you through some of the changes that we have.
I know there are quite a few changes,
but, thankfully, I have committed the changes
so we can exactly see what is going on
and what got updated.
Perfect.
So first thing in the ApplicationDbContext here,
we added the OnModelCreating,
and these are the changes that we did, so that looks good.
Then the next thing here,
let me take a look at Program.cs in the BulkyWeb project.
There, you can see in the green what got added.
Basically, when we scaffolded Identity, it added a Service
which is AddDefaultIdentity for IdentityUser,
and there it has option where it is saying
that, "Hey, if you want to sign in,
your email account should be confirmed."
This is one of the option which is not required.
So if you remove that, then if your email is not confirmed,
even then the user can log in,
and we will go with that option.
But on top of that, we have something special here
which says AddEntityFrameworkStores,
and then it has the ApplicationDbContext.
So what happens this time?
When we add Identity to the project,
it basically also adds all the database tables
that are needed for the Identity,
like we have users table, we have roles table,
we have user roles table, claims table, and many more.
On this line 14, we are telling Entity Framework
that, "Hey, all of those tables will be managed
with the help of DbContext which is ApplicationDbContext."
That is where we are binding Entity Framework
with the Identity tables.
And with that, Identity is added in Program.cs.
One thing that we shall also add here is in the middleware,
we should be adding UseAuthentication,
and that, we must add before authorization.
And the reason behind that is authentication
is basically checking if username or password is valid.
If the username and password is valid,
then authorization comes into picture.
Authorization basically tells
that, "Hey, now you have access to the website,
but based on your role,
you might have access to some pages and not all the pages."
Like where we are updating the product and everything,
maybe role of admin has access to that page.
But if role of a logged-in user is customer,
they can only access Home page and Details page.
They cannot access the Product page.
But in order to check role of a user,
they must be first authenticated.
So always remember
that authentication will come before authorization.
That looks good for Program.cs.
Let me see what is updated in appsettings.json.
It added a new DB connection. We do not need that.
It added that line
because it was trying to add a new DB connection.
We do not need that so let me remove that,
and perfect, the comma as well,
and perfect, that looks good.
We do not have any change in appsettings.
I can revert that back as well.
Next, we have a change in LoginPartial.cshtml.
Now, this is not a change. You can see an A here.
That means a new file, _LoginPartial, has been added,
and in that partial view,
we basically have the Login and Register button.
If a user is already signed in,
then we have the Logout link,
and we have a Details link to manage that user.
We are injecting few things here.
Do not worry about any of them right now.
Basically, a new partial view has been added here,
and let me see what we have in the Areas, Account.
Quite a few files have been added right here.
But with all of that configured,
if we go to Solution Explorer, inside Areas,
we have a new folder with the name of Identity.
We can remove the Data
because there we had the ApplicationDbContext.
But in Identity, Pages,
it added all the pages that we selected,
and we selected all of the pages that were available
with the Identity package.
So you can see there are quite a few pages right here,
and all of these pages are not MVC pages.
They are Razor Pages
that we saw in the beginning of the course.
I gave you a brief idea on how Razor Pages work.
For example, we have the Login,
then we have the .cshtml.cs for the PageModel.
So right here in the page,
we have the PageModel, we have Log in,
we have Email, Password, and a Submit button.
On the PageModel here, we have few details,
but then we have the OnGet handler,
and we have the OnPost handler.
So that must feel familiar
to what we have already seen in Razor Pages.
Now, when the Identity was implemented by Microsoft
in initial version of .NET Core 2,
there were both MVC and Razor Page implementation,
but later on, Microsoft moved Identity only to Razor Pages.
That way, they do not have to maintain that
in both the places.
So, unfortunately, the Identity that we have
is only in Razor Pages.
But good thing is Razor Pages are not that different,
and we have seen how to perform
CRUD operation in Razor Pages,
so you should also have a basic understanding
on how Razor Pages work.
But if we're on the application,
how can we see the Login and Register page?
Because if I run right now,
you will notice on the Home page,
we do not see anything in the navigation.
Adding that is super simple.
If you remember, it already added one of the partial view,
let me show that in the web project,
which was LoginPartial right here.
So basically, if I go to Pages, well, not here.
In the default views, Shared, we have LoginPartial,
and that has the Login and Register button.
What we can do is in _layout,
we can add call to that partial view.
So right here, after the ul, this ul is the navbar-nav.
And rather than flex-grow-1, let me make it me-auto.
And after that ul here, we will be adding partial.
name is equal to, and name of that view is LoginPartial.
Make sure there is no spelling mistake there, save that,
and let me go back.
Perfect, you can see when we save it,
we have REGISTER and LOGIN right here.
We have to toggle the text there.
So if I go back here, I will remove the text-dark.
We do not need that in any place here.
Perfect. Save that and let me see.
Perfect. Now, we have the REGISTER and LOGIN buttons here.
And when we click on them, it is taking us to Identity,
and then it has page, Account, Register.
Now, why is this not working?
Let me explain that in the next video.