Instructor: Now, in our application,
if we click on register or if we click on login,
you will notice that it does not work.
Can you pause the video and try to think
or maybe even Google on why that is not working?
It is a little bit tricky,
but I want you to see
if you can identify on what is missing.
And to give you a hint,
something is missing in program.cs file.
I hope you were able to figure that out.
Now, if I go back to the project here,
we added login partial.
Let me examine that.
When we go to login partial,
we have the ASP area,
but we do not see ASP controller
or ASP action for routing.
We rather see ASP page.
And if you remember, that is used for Razor pages.
So what we have here is indeed correct because register
and all the identity pages are indeed Razor pages.
But in the program.cs file,
we only have support for MBC.
If we go back here
that is the route that is being supported
and we do not have any services that tells that,
hey, our application will also have Razor pages.
So we need to add that basic configuration
and tell our application in services we will register,
add Razor pages,
and then where we have the pipeline here,
we will say app.MapRazorPages.
That will make sure that it adds a routing
that is needed to map the Razor pages.
With that configured,
now the register and login should work as expected.
If I click on register here, perfect.
We have a default registration page
provided by the .NET team
and there is email, password, and confirm password.
If we click on login here, we have email and password.
So you can see many of the pages
have already been implemented
and provided to us by the .NET identity.
But before we move forward with login and registration,
let's say when we register a user,
where will this user be saved in the database?
We do not have any tables in the database.
But what actually happens is because of the identity,
when we add migration,
it will automatically add migration
to create all the identity-related tables.
Let me see that.
We will close all the tabs here.
Tools, package manager, console,
and I will add a migration addIdentityTables.
We have to change the default project and press Enter.
Perfect.
You can see in the migration
it is creating a table AspNetRoles,
AspNetUsers table, RoleClaims,
and many more tables related to identity.
So all of this configuration of tables
is already being done in the .NET identity.
All we have to do is add migration and update database.
You can think about if you had to do
all of this implementation,
it would take quite a few time,
and then also when it comes to security,
you need to be very sure that everything is super solid.
The .NET team has taken care of all of that
and we can just use that with confidence.
Once that is done,
if I switch back to the SQL server and examine tables,
great, we have so many new tables
that are created for identity.
The main table here is the users table
and you can notice all the identity related tables
will have ASP.NET before the table name.
So users table is basically ASP.NET user.
Roles table is ASP.NET roles.
In the users table, we have username, email.
We also have phone number.
But it is possible that you might want more properties
in a user table,
like you might need address of the user,
full name of the user,
and much more.
So now the question is how can we modify
the existing users table
and add more columns based on our requirement?
Let me show you that in the next video.