Instructor: Now we want to add more tables
to the user's table
which is the default implementation in .netidentity.
For that, if I switch back to the application
let me close everything here, and if I examine
program.cs, where it added the default identity
you can see the default user is identity user.
But if we want to add more properties to identity user
we can always extend that user.
So basically in our models here, let me create one more file
and I will call that application user.
We will make that a public file and in that file
we need to make sure it extends the identity user
and we will have to add the using statement.
For that, we will have to install the package
microsoft.extensions.identity.store.
Once we do that
that means application user will have all the
default settings of identity user.
On top of that, let's say we want to add name
of the user and that will be a required field
along with the name here we can add four more properties
like street address, city, state, and Postal Code.
We can make them nullable, but name will be required.
Now, once we have that, we need to add that
to migration and we also have to add a mapper for that.
So if we go to application DB context
we will create a DB set for that.
So DB set here on application user
and I will call that application users.
With that configured, we can add a new migration
and I will call this extend Identity user.
The migration, you can see it is adding column, city.
There is also a discriminator column
but we have name, postal code, state and street address.
Looks good.
Let me update the database and let me switch back
to the database and let me do select top thousand again.
Perfect.
It added all of those columns
but one column is this Discriminator column.
What exactly is that?
Well, now in our application, if you think of that
we have two type of user.
We have identity user and we have application user.
So Discriminator column will basically have
a value that will tell that the user on that record.
Is that an application user or is that an identity user?
Simple as that.
But with that,
we have seen how to extend the default identity user
in our project and add more columns.