Instructor: We have added ApplicationUser in our models
and we have pushed that to our database,
but the default identity here is still using IdentityUser.
With that, let me run the application
and try to see how the default registration
and login functionalities work.
So let me register for a user here
and I will call that test@gmail.com.
Password, I will do Admin123* with a capital A,
because if I only use 123,
you can see password is not strong enough,
so we have to keep something strong.
I will add Admin123* and register.
Perfect, once I register here,
it automatically signs me in.
But if we log out here,
and then if we go to log in, we can try that again.
Test@gmail.com and Admin123.
I did not add the asterisk at the end,
so we should say invalid login attempt.
That looks good.
Now let me type the correct password.
Perfect, with correct password, it logs me in,
and we have a profile,
and on the top right here,
we see Hello test@gmail.com.
Now if you click there, it displays the profile
where it displays username, phone number,
they can update their email, verify email,
modify their password, add a two-factor authentication,
and they can download or delete their personal data.
All of this is provided by default
with the identity that we scaffolded.
So you can see when we scaffold,
it provides many things,
not just the basic identity setup,
and it is more like a complete identity package.
But of course, if you add more fields to register,
you can always update profile and all the other pages.
But before anything, let me switch back to SQL Server
and examine the user that got created
in the ASP.NET User Stable.
Perfect, you can see we have the record here.
If you scroll to the right,
what should be the Discriminator column?
Will it be ApplicationUser or will it be IdentityUser?
If you said IdentityUser, you are correct,
you can see that right here.
Because right now in our application,
the default identity is IdentityUser,
but on top of that, the important thing is,
when we are registering the user,
we are creating an IdentityUser
and not an ApplicationUser.
So we need to modify that, because with IdentityUser,
we will not get city, name, postal code,
state, and street address.
If we want to capture those properties,
we need to find out a way to register an ApplicationUser.
So let me work on that in the next video.