Instructor: Now, we have the discriminator
as IdentityUser.
Changing that to ApplicationUser is super simple.
But before I walk you through that, let me go back here,
in area, identity, pages, account,
we have register.
Let me open the register page model.
Again, this is a razor page here
and you can see we are injecting many things
in dependency injection.
I want to spend some time to explain you few things
right here.
Now think about when you are implementing a login
or registration functionality.
You will have to write all the code
of what should happen
when a user enters username and password.
You will have to encrypt that code.
You might have to validate that
with what it is there in database
and then you can be like, okay,
authentication looks good, login is successful.
On top of that, you will have to store that in session
or some place that user is logged in
and you might have to store the details about user
in session.
Now these are only the basic things.
If you think about the complete authentication
there are way more functionalities that are needed.
Taking care of logging a user,
all the way to logging out a user
and managing their credentials between there.
When we use the .NET identity,
.NET team has taken care of all the heavy lifting for us
and they have given us these classes like SignInManager,
UserManager, RoleManager to manage your roles
and all of that is provided by default.
All we have to do is directly inject them
in dependency injection
and then using UserManager or SignInManager,
we can manage the user.
Now, SignInManager expects the type of user
and that is IdentityUser.
You can keep that, that is okay.
We only want to change the discriminator
when we are creating that user
with the help of these helper classes.
If we scroll down,
in razor pages if you remember,
we have handlers.
So we scroll down,
we have a get handler and we have a post handler.
Inside the post handler you can see there is a method
which says CreateUser.
If you press F12 or if you scroll down,
you will see that method right here.
That CreateUser is doing nothing
but it is creating an instance of IdentityUser.
Rather than that
we want to create an instance of ApplicationUser
and we will have to update the return type here as well.
That will make sure that CreateUser right here,
the user will now be of type ApplicationUser.
Then on line 120,
you can see we have a helper method in _userManager,
which is CreateAsync,
there it expects a user object and password
and it will automatically create that user.
So when this method will be invoked
it'll insert an entry in the ASP.NET user's table
and on top of that it'll encrypt the password as well.
So helper method is taking care of all the heavy lifting.
On top of that, if result is successful, we scroll down.
It is also doing something to generate email token
and sending email,
but it is only the interface,
implementation of that has not been done.
But if you examine on line 144,
we are using _signInManager,
and we are automatically signing in that user.
And because of that, if you remember,
when we register a user and hit the submit button
it automatically signs in the user.
We do not have to write any code,
we are only calling the helper method
in _signInManager and _userManager.
So, that is great.
Now that we have modified the user to be ApplicationUser,
let me run the application and see what happens.
Let me try to register a new user.
I know this will be an ApplicationUser,
so let me say applicationuser@gmail.com
we will enter a password
and hit register.
It will automatically sign us in as well.
If we go to database and execute that,
we have the application user here.
And if we examine the discriminator,
you can see it is of type ApplicationUser.
So things are indeed getting different here
and we can now register an ApplicationUser
rather than default IdentityUser.
Now because we are adding ApplicationUser here,
on user we have more properties
like if we want name or if we want street address,
we can populate all of them.
But before I populate all of those properties,
what is the role of current user?
By default, when you add identity,
it does add the table to manage roles,
but if you examine the roles table, it is empty.
So we do not have any roles in our website.
Like if we want admin role, employee role, company role
or any individual role, we do not have any roles.
We have to write some code to seed this ASP.NET roles table
and then we have to use some helper methods
that when a user is created based on what we select in role,
we want to assign that role.
So let me first work on that in the next video.