Instructor: We want to work on roles
and how we can configure the identity.
If I go back to my code here
let me stop the application and open program.cs.
In the add default identity, it only adds identity user,
it does not add role to the identity in our project.
If we have to add the role
then rather than default identity, we have to customize that
and we will say, hey, I want to add identity.
Now when you add identity, by default along with user
it expects a role as well.
And just like identity user
we have a default implementation, which is identity role.
With that particular line, we have added roles
to our identity and that is included in our project now.
Once we add role here,
let's say when we are registering a user in a dropdown,
we want to display all the roles that are available.
But right now if we go to our database,
we do not even have any role.
We need to seed that role.
So what I will do is right now I will have hacky way
of adding those roles.
In the OnGet handler, basically when page will be loaded,
I will check in the database,
hey, is there a role of admin here?
If there is, then I won't do anything.
But if there is no role
then I will create that role right here.
In order to do all of that
we will need helper class here.
Just like SignInManager,
we also have something called as RoleManager.
RoleManager works on identity role
and we will have to inject that using dependency injection.
So let me do that.
_roleManager is equal to roleManager.
Let me scroll down where we have the OnGet handler.
Now first I want to check, is there any role?
Rather than having magic string of admin or customer
let me create a file that will contain those constant
and for that we have BulkyBook.Utility
where we added a class static detail.
Inside there I will create four constant.
One will be customer role.
Then I will add a company role, an admin
and an employee role.
Based on the roles here
we might have some functionality
that we want to turn on and turn off.
Right now we will be working with admin and customer role.
But before anything we have to create these roles
inside our database.
We will do that in register here.
We can check using our helper method _roleManager.
There is a helper method RoleExistsAsync.
We can check, hey, is there a role
with the name of SD.Role_User_Customer?
If there is, then we do not want to do anything.
But if that role does not exist
then we want to create all the roles.
Now because this is an async method
we will have to await that.
So rather than writing await right here,
what we can do is after the method here
we can say .GetAwaiter .GetResult.
That is same as writing an await statement
but when we are calling here we cannot do that.
So that is why we can use GetAwaiter .GetResult.
So that will check if the role exists.
If it does not exist, then we want to create that role.
So on _roleManager we have another
helper method CreateAsync.
Inside there, if you hover it expects an identity role.
We will have to create new identity role
and there we have to pass the role name.
So I will say role customer.
Once I do that, again it is an async,
so we will await that.
We can use GetAwaiter .GetResult.
Now we can check if any of the role does not exist.
We want to create all the roles
that we have inside our static detail.
So let me do that and perfect, that looks good.
Now let me use full name here
and rather than user let me directly use customer
or if it is a company client maybe.
So here I will rename them to be company
and I have customer.
That makes more sense.
Great, so we are creating four roles in our database.
Now when we are using the CreateAsync
or those helper method, we do not need save changes.
The helper method is taking care of everything
and we do not have to worry about adding a unit
of work or any DB changes.
With that configured,
let me save this and run the application.
In order to create the role,
all we have to do is click register
and that will invoke the get handler.
But when we do that, we will see an exception.
It says unable to resolve
IEmailSender while activating register model.
What exactly is going on here?
Why are we seeing this IEmailSender error now?
The reason is in register we modified the create user
but on top of that, if you scroll up
we have IEmailSender that has been injected here
and we are using this email sender
if we scroll down in order to send emails.
But that is not important.
When it is trying to inject the email sender,
it gives the error message
and because we have not implemented this interface,
it is saying that hey, I am not able to resolve
on what should be the implementation
for this email sender logic.
And that is exactly the same thing
with unit of work as well.
If you remember where we have the interface of unit of work
we added the implementation of that in program.cs
and after that it was able to give us
that implementation when we asked independency injection.
But email sender does not have a default implementation.
In order to solve that error, all we have to
do is have an implementation for email sender.
Now of course we do not want to spend time right
now to implement the email logic,
but we can implement a fake email sender
because the error is when it is trying to inject
and not actually sending the email.
Now where should we add the implementation for email sender?
That is something common and I believe it should fall
inside the utility project.
So let me stop the application.
Utility, add a class file,
and I will call that EmailSender.
We will make that a public class
and that should implement the IEmailSender.
We will press control dot
and we will have to install the package
Microsoft.AspNetCore.Identity.UI.
Once we install that
then we will have to implement the interface as well.
So let me do that and there is one method, SendEmailAsync.
Now, right now, rather than throwing an exception here
it makes sense to only return task.completed.
In future if we have to send email here,
we will actually have the logic here to send email.
But right now we are keeping things super simple.
Once we have the implementation,
all we have to do is register that in our services.
So builder.Services.AddScoped IEmailSender
and implementation is inside email sender.
With that configured, the error should go away.
And let me go to register here.
And perfect the page loaded.
Now again, why this broke when we added role
is because in program we are no longer
using the default identity.
We are adding a custom implementation.
Because of that
it does not have any fake implementation for email sender.
But once the get handler is invoked
our rules must be created.
If I refresh here, perfect.
We have our roles table automatically populated
based on the name that we gave for our role.
So perfect.
Our roles table is now populated and we have user.
When we register a user, how can we assign user some role?
Let me do that in the next video.