Instructor: Now that we have roles in our database,
when we register a user,
I can add a dropdown here
where user can select any of the existing roles.
Now you might be saying that, "Hey, you are giving someone
"the right to register an admin user
"from the registration page. Is that a good approach?"
Of course it's not.
But right now we are learning things,
and that is why we will keep it here.
But later on in the advanced sections
I will obviously remove that
before the code is being deployed.
So right now we are learning things,
and it is completely okay when you are learning.
But when you deploy,
make sure that does not go into production.
So we need to add a dropdown.
When we add a dropdown on the UI,
we need to pass some things from the page model.
That way it will be accessible on the page,
and we can display that in a dropdown.
So we have the page model here,
and we have input model,
where we have "BindProperty" in Razor Page.
Inside that input model, I will be adding more properties.
So what we will do is after confirm password,
let me create a property which will be a string of roles,
and then we actually need a role dropdown list.
For that we need an IEnumerable of select list item.
So let me close this here,
and I will add an IEnumberable of select list item.
Call that "RoleList," and for validation,
I will say "ValidateNever."
Once we have that IEnnumerable,
we need to populate that inside the "OnGet" right here.
So we need to populate the input is equal to
new input model.
We can use the new syntax here.
In there, we want to populate RoleList,
and in order to access all the roles,
typically, we use unit of work,
but when we are working with identity,
we have "roleManager."
Inside there we have roles,
and that will have list of all the roles.
Now we do not want all the roles.
We will have to project that to be a select list item.
So for projection, we will use "Select,"
and we can say x goes to x.Name.
We only care about the name, we select that name.
And once we select that name,
we will project that into the select list item.
So "i" goes to "new SelectListItem,"
and we want to populate "Text is equal to i"
and "Value is equal to i," as well.
What we are doing is, from roles,
we are selecting only the name.
And whatever we are selecting here,
we are adding that to a SelectListItem,
and we are adding that field to both "Text" and "Value."
You can see how projections can get super fancy
and how they simplify multiple lines of code
in just a few lines of code.
Now the final thing is to display this particular RoleList
inside our register.
So, "Areas," we have the register here,
and let me copy this "div," paste it one more time.
We do not want any validation here or label as well.
All we need is a select field.
So you can use "Input," or you can use a "Select" here,
where "asp-for," that is "Input.Role,"
and "asp-items" is equal to "Model.Input.RoleList."
Give it a class name of "form-select." Perfect.
Now again, when you are using asp-for,
it automatically checks the model,
but if you are using any other tag helper,
you have to use the "@Model" before that.
With that configured, let me save
and restart the application.
I think I have to restart
because hot reload might not kick that in,
but let's see.
Perfect. We have Admin, Customer, Employee, and Company.
On top of that I can also go back, and within "select,"
I can add an option, which is disabled, to select a role.
If I go back, perfect, looks good.
Now we have added a role in the UI,
but based on our selection,
we have to assign that role to a user.
Doing that is super simple,
and we have to write one line of code
in the register "OnPost" handler.
We will do that if the CreateUser is successful right here,
because we are checking if a result
is succeeded of creating user.
If that is, then we want to assign the role.
We will first check "if(Input.Role)," if that is not null.
Or rather than that, let me do a "String.IsNullOrEmpty,"
if that is not null or empty, then we want to assign role,
and we will say "await" on "userManager,"
we have a helper method, "AddToRoleAsync."
Now you can see there are two methods here,
so be careful when you type.
If you type "AddToRolesAsync,"
that means you are adding multiple roles to a user.
You can see it expects an IEnnumerable of roles.
But we are only adding one role,
so we will say "AddToRoleAsync," pass our user
and the role that has been selected by the dropdown.
In the "else" part here, I can copy and paste that
and basically if user does not select anything
from the dropdown,
then I want to assign them "SD.Role_Customer."
So if Input.Role is not null or empty, we will assign that,
else we will assign them the role of customer.
It is super simple, thankful to all the helper methods
that are provided by the .NET Identity.
With that configured, let me restart the application.
Whenever I make change in the .CS file,
I feel like restarting just to be confirmed.
Now, let me register here.
I will set "testadmin@gmail.com,"
and we will select a role of "Admin."
And we see an exception here
where it is generating email confirmation token,
and that is because of the same thing.
Previously, we were using the default identity,
and that included the implementation,
but when we have the "AddIdentity,"
it is not included by default.
So we have to add the "AddDefaultTokenProviders,"
because when we register in the page model here,
you can see it is generating the email confirmation token,
and that requires the default token providers.
But if you examine, that code is after the user is created
and role is assigned.
So that means our user should be created in database.
If I go to AspNetUsers, perfect.
We have the testadmin here,
and how do we see if that user is assigned the correct role?
Well, we have a mapping table, which is "AspNetUserRoles,"
that maps users to their corresponding roles.
If I do "select top thousand" and examine the user ID,
it ends in "80." That is correct.
The role ID here starts with "045."
And if I go to the roles table, "045" is Admin,
so that means correct role have been assigned
in our database.
Let me try to register one more.
Let's go back,
and this time we should not see the error message of token.
Let me see that.
This time let me register an employee,
and let's register.
Perfect, we don't see that error here.
Let me go to database, employee ends in "19."
Let me refresh here, and perfect.
The new user has a role that ends in "19," that is employee.
Now finally, if we do not select anything,
by default, it should be customer.
That ends in "12."
Let me test that, as well.
We will not select any role.
And register that. Perfect.
If I go here, once again, customer is "12,"
new user should have "12," and that looks correct.
So with that, we can see users are being created
in our database,
and correct rules are being assigned to those users.
We did not have to write much code to implement that.
All credit goes to the built-in helper method,
provided in userManager and roleManager.
With that configuration,
let me continue from the next video.