-: Now that we have user
who have actual roles in our website,
we can make one modification
and that is,
the content management should only be visible
if a user is admin.
If it is not,
then they should not see the content management right here.
So, how can we check role of a logged in user?
For that, if we go back to the application
and we have to add that inside the _layout
which is the master page.
There we have the dropdown right here.
To check role of a logged in user,
we can add an if condition using the razor syntax
and we have the user object
that is already available with the project.
So, we can check if user
that is a helper method IsInRole
and we can check the name of the role.
We need the static details here,
but it is not accessible.
We have to add the using statement.
We will say BulkyBook.utility
and if we do not want to add it here,
we can add that inside the ViewImports right here.
And let me also add that in the other views that we have.
So, in Areas actually.
Admin, Views, ViewImport.
Paste that.
Customer, Views, ViewImport.
And let me see the identity.
We have ViewImports.
Paste that.
Now, I will also paste the other two
inside Identity.
And I think I cut that.
So, perfect.
That looks good.
Let me close all the tabs.
I had too many tabs open.
Let me collapse all.
And we were working on Views, Shared,
and _layout.
So, now SD is accessible
and we can say if user is in role admin,
then we want to display this particular li.
If I save that and run the application,
you will notice that this dropdown will be hidden
unless the user is an admin user.
So, right now, we do not see that.
If we log in as test customer,
it'll not be available.
You can see that.
And if we log out here...
Let me log in as test admin.
Whoops.
It should be admin.
There we go.
And perfect.
Then, we are able to view that.
Now, here we are only toggling
when to display this content management,
but if someone has the URL here,
if the logout here,
and even then if they type the URL,
you can see they are able to access that
and manage categories.
That should not be possible.
We need to make sure
that only admin has access to this page.
Adding that is super simple.
And what we will do is...
Where we have the controller?
Let me go to Areas, Admin, Controller.
We are in the category Controller.
Here, we can add an authorized keyword
and we are telling that only the roles is equal to SD.
Admin can access all the controllers action method.
So, if a user tries to access the index action
or any other action method,
if their role is not admin,
they will not get that access.
This authorized keyword,
you can add that at the complete category controller.
That will apply to all the action methods.
But if you want to apply them individually,
you can also do that
on top of the individual action methods.
So, whichever route you want, you can select that.
I am going to apply that globally
for category controller
as well as product controller.
Once we do that, let me save the application here.
Let me log in as an admin first.
We should be able to access that.
Let me log out and let me log in here as test customer.
And if I paste that URL here,
you will see something odd.
It is going to account and then access denied.
But we do not have that page.
If you go back and search in the solution explorer,
we do actually have an access denied page,
let me show that,
which got added in the identity.
But that is inside identity area.
Here, it is trying to look directly
into account access denied.
If it was like this,
then that page is actually loading.
So, the default route for access denied is not working
and we have to overwrite that.
And it is not only that route.
If I log out here
and if I try to access the admin product,
you will notice it is redirecting me to log in.
Because a user is not logged in,
they cannot access that.
First, they have to be logged in
and then, they must have the role of admin.
So, here also, it is missing that particular area,
which is identity.
If we have that, then it'll work.
Now these are the default application path
that are set by default in the application.
But because we added the identity here,
we have to overwrite those default configuration
and we will do that inside Program.cs.
Let me minimize this and open Program.cs.
Inside the builder.Services,
we have something
called as builder.Services.ConfigureApplicationCookie.
And there on the option, we have login path,
logout path, access denied and other configuration.
Right now, I will only toggle these three configuration.
And with that, let me restart the application.
With that change, if I try to access admin product,
things will still not work.
It is still going to the old route.
What exactly is going on here?
Well, when you add ConfigureApplicationCookies,
there is one thing that you should remember,
you cannot add that
before you add identity.
So, we have to add that after line 16
and only then it will work.
With that saved,
let me restart the application.
This time, if I try admin category,
it redirects to the correct path.
And if I log in as customer,
we will see access denied.
Perfect.
With that, we have implemented authorization successfully
based on role of the user
that has logged in.