Instructor: Final thing that I want to toggle
is in the as AspNet user
we created many more properties.
I want to add all of those properties in the register page
so we can go back here, we will have to add them first
to the register page model.
We scroll down, we have the input model and there
we have few properties.
We added the role dropdown.
We want to add the other properties so you can copy them
from AspNet users if you want.
But basically we want to add street address, city, state
postal code and phone number.
Now, phone number, we did not add that in the
application user because if we switched to our database
and examine the AspNet users table, phone number column
is created by default that you can see right here.
So I am adding a property in the register so we can capture
and save that as well.
Once we add that here in the register, we have to
copy the email here, paste that one more time
before the roll here.
Make sure to change that to column MD6.
Next what we have is street address copy and paste that
we do not want auto complete.
We can remove that one and perfect, that looks good.
Paste it four more times, now rather than street address.
I will update that to city.
We have state.
Postal code and phone number.
Save that and let me see the UI.
Perfect, that looks good.
We need to update here as well.
So let me do that
and perfect.
That looks good.
Let me take a look at that.
We have a weird error here.
Let me restart the application.
Let me navigate to register and perfect.
The register looks good.
We have many more properties here and we have placeholder.
Now you can obviously remove everything that is there
in place holder, but you can see
because of placeholder we are getting the fancy design
that when we click, it's slightly hovers
on the top and I personally like that, because of that.
I am going to leave the place holder here
but of course you can make the placeholder according
to what the ASP 4 is.
I am not going to spend time editing that
but you can obviously fix all of that.
With that we have added all the properties
on the register UI.
Now when we post, we will receive all
of them in the OnPostAsync where we have our model.
But when we are creating or passing the user here
we are only populating email for that user.
We will also have to populate the other properties
from the input model.
So let me do that, now let me go back to the database here.
We also added name column there
so let me create that property as well
and name will be required.
Save that here and that's okay.
It should go away.
Let me also modify here.
We need to add the UI there.
So let me copy the street address.
I should add that right after email
but I want to keep password and confirm password together.
So let me do name here
And I will cut name along with phone number
and I will cut these two, paste it right after email.
So email, name and phone number goes together.
We have an error there.
Let me see what it is.
Well, we have an issue with the required
let me see why, it says required is ambiguous reference
between data annotation and some other required attribute.
We will modify that to be data annotation.
It is conflicting with something else there.
So let me add that
and let me examine the change commit here.
I want to make sure I did not add something.
Yes I did.
I added this line, this using statement,
that was not needed.
So remove that and now required should work.
Yep, sometimes when you add some other using statement
you can see how conflicts can happen but thankfully because
of git changes I can easily make sure that I only
have the changes that I intended to go in this comment.
With that configured, let me run the application.
We still have an error here
and what is in here and let me open application user.
I think accidentally something is integer
which should not be, whoops, name cannot be integer.
It has to be a string.
If we modify something there, we have to add a migration.
I will call that update name to be string application user.
I like to name migration as meaningful
as possible and I forgot to change the default project.
Perfect.
Let me update the database
and great, that is all done.
Let me run the application
and make sure everything is working.
I will create a new user
and this time all the details will be populated
and we have multiple street address that is not correct.
Let me go to register.
This will be name
so let me change that to be full name and perfect.
Let me type that once again.
If I do not select a role
it'll be customer role and that works for this user.
Let me create that.
Perfect, that looks good.
Let me switch back to the database here.
And if I examine AspNet users, perfect.
Now you can see all the columns are getting populated
and that is working as expected.