Instructor: Now, I want to show you one small bug.
If I log in with any user,
and if we click on managing their profile here,
previously there was a navigation here,
and now it is gone.
I want you guys to pause the video
and try to find out on what exactly is wrong,
and why that is not working.
To give you an hint,
something is wrong in _layout and manage.
I hope you were able to figure that out.
Now if I open the _layout here,
you can see the default layout is areas identity pages
and _layout.
If you examine the pages here,
we do not have any _layout that is inside views,
shared_layout.
So, we have to correct that path here to views,
And with that, if you refresh the application,
things will still not work.
Let me show that.
We will go to login here.
And let me click on the profile.
You can see it is still not working.
The reason is simple.
Again, we have added or modified the _layout
that is inside manage.
But how will all the pages inside manage know
that it has to use this _layout?
We do not have a view start file inside the manage folder.
Because of that the pages inside manage does not know that
they have to use this _layout file.
So, what we can do is I can copy any of the view start file,
copy that, paste it in the manage folder.
And in there, we just write _layout.cshtml,
then all the pages in manage now knows that
they have to use this _layout,
which has that manage nav bar.
So, we restart the application,
and everything should work now.
Let me log in first.
And perfect, you can see everything is working.
Now similar to adding fields in the register,
you can add that in the profile.
But I am not going to do that.
You already know how to accomplish all of that.