Instructor: When we work with orders in any website
we typically have two tables.
One is order header and one is order details.
Order header will have all the information about order
like where the order is being shipped,
what is the payment status, what was the order date,
what was the payment ID
what is the tracking information and much more.
Order details will have all the details about that order
like what are the items in this order
and what is the count of each item and so on.
So we have to create both of these tables
and let me switch back, stop the application,
close all the tabs here
and we will go to the models project.
Right click here, add a new model.
First one here will be order header.cs
and the next one will be order details.
We will make both of them public class here and perfect.
First, we'll work on all the properties in order header.
ID is pretty straightforward.
Every order needs a unique ID.
Then each order will belong to a user and user ID is a grid.
So we will say application user ID which will be a string
and that will be foreign key to the application user table.
So we will have to add the foreign key
and where we have the navigation property
make sure to add validate never.
We do not want to validate that
when we will be creating or updating any order header.
Next property here will be a date time
and that will be order date
and when an order will be shipped,
we will also have another date time
which will be order shipped.
So shipping date and we will have a double
which will be order total.
Perfect, that looks good.
Then for each order we have an order status.
On top of order status,
I will also be adding something called as payment status.
That will give us an idea of what happens with payment
of an order, whether it is pending, it is completed
or it is a delayed payment.
Once the order is shipped
then we want to add the tracking number
and the carrier information so they can track the order.
Lastly, if you remember
for company user we will give them net 30 days
to make payment after the order has been placed.
So we can also track what is the payment date
and by when the payment is due.
Now the due date
I want that to be a date field only,
because of that with EF Core
we have a special feature date only
and that will be converted
to a date only field when EF Core generates the SQL query.
So we have date only and time only if that is needed
but we do not need time only for this case.
We will be using date only.
Finally, when we work with payments using credit card
and Stripe, we will be getting a unique ID from Stripe
which will be payment intent ID
that will uniquely identify each payment
that has been done for an order
and we will save that in the database.
Other properties that we want to add here are basically
name of the person and phone number and street address.
These are the same properties that we added
in the view as well.
So we have phone number, street address, city,
state, postal code and name.
With that configured the order header looks in great shape.
We have added quite a few properties there.
Next, let me work on order details here.
There also we will need ID for the order details
but along with that we need the order ID
and that order ID will be the order header ID.
So if you want to be explicit you can say order header ID.
Now this order header ID will be a foreign key
to the order header.
So make sure to add the foreign key and order header.
We will add the validate never with the navigation property.
Next property that we want here is the product ID
and then we will have navigation property
for product as well.
So let me add the navigation property for product
and then for each product what is the count or quantity?
So we will add a count and I will also be logging
what is the price.
So we will have double and price here.
And the reason I am logging price is
if you examine the product here
it can happen that in future that price can be updated
but when we place an order
we want to log that, hey, this is the price user got
for the order and that should never change.
So it makes sense to add price inside the order details.
With that configured, I believe order details
and order header looks good for now.
We need to add them to the database.
To do that we have application db context here
and inside there we have to create the db set.
One thing I noticed here is I'm using plural here
for order details.
Let me actually fix that
and I will be converting that to be singular
as order detail and perfect, that looks good.
The class name also got updated.
If not, you'll have to manually update that.
So we will be adding two db set here,
one for order header, table name will be order headers
and order detail.
Table name will be order details.
With that in place here, let me save everything.
Package manager console and I will add a migration,
add order header and details to db.
Perfect, that looks good.
Let me update the database.
Whoops, I have a spelling mistake there and there we go.
Now let me also examine the migration here.
Once that is done, if we scroll down
we added the payment due date as date time only
and you can see the type here is date.
So EF Core is able to convert that successfully
and that is a great feature.
Because of that, now we can have date only
and time only with EF Core.
So perfect.
Our order header and order details model are looking great.
Let me continue from the next video.