Announcer: Now that we have added order header
and order details in our model and database,
we need to add that to our repository as well.
So let me copy the category repository,
paste it two more times.
First I will work on the interface here
and we will rename that to be I order header repository
and we have the I order detail repository.
Let me copy the interface and modify things here as well.
Perfect, looks good.
Modify the order header, copy that,
and perfect.
I believe that looks good for the interface.
Let me copy the implementation bar category,
paste it two more times, modify that to be order header
and order detail.
Perfect, let me copy that name
and modify the order detail here.
And perfect, that looks good for order detail.
Let me work on the order header repository.
And perfect, that looks good.
Let me close everything here.
And we need to add that to unit of work and I unit of work.
First, we will add the order detail here
and I have the I order header, looks good.
Work on the unit of work, public.
I order header and public I order detail.
We will also initialize them.
Order header is equal to new order header and order detail.
That looks good.
With that, we have configured our unit
of work to use the order header and order detail repository.
Let me continue from the next video.