Instructor: Let me run the application here
and let me navigate to the shopping cart once that loads.
Perfect.
Now when we hit on the summary page,
here what we see on the left side is basically order header
and on the right side that we see can be order details,
or it can also be the shopping cart information.
If we have to think about a view model
for this particular view, we have order header here,
and right here we will get all the product details
inside the shopping cart.
If I go back to the application and where we have
the shopping cart view model, where was that?
Whoops.
In the models.
Inside here, we had the order total
and list of shopping cart.
There, we can add one more property, which is order header,
and that can act as a view model.
So, perfect.
We have order header here.
Now, if you examine order header,
we have one property order total.
So, rather than having order total here and inside
the order header, we can use the order total that is
inside order header and we can remove this one.
When we remove that, things will be broken in our website.
Let me build and show that.
Build fail here.
And if we go back where we are accessing the order total
now, we will have to access that inside
OrderHeader.OrderTotal.
We will have to modify that in the view as well.
So right-click, go to the view.
We will displaying the order total here
so we will navigate to OrderHeader.OrderTotal.
With that in place, if I run the application,
the shopping cart will work exactly the same
but, this time, it will be using a view model
with order header, and we have an exception
because I believe the order header is null here.
So, where we have the shopping cart view model
we can say order header is equal to new,
and that should fix that.
Let me run the application once again.
We go to our cart here and perfect.
That is working.
Let me add one more item to the shopping cart here,
and we have two items.
Perfect, looks good.
Now, when we click on the summary here, the model
for this page will also be the shopping cart view model,
and we will have to populate the card details.
Let me do that in the next video.