Instructor: When we are working here,
we basically need to populate all the details.
If I go to SQL Server real quick here,
and if I examine the "AspNetUsers", if you go to the right,
I believe we added more properties for user.
So when we have to populate this information,
we can go to the database or "AspNetUser"
and try to retrieve the information from there.
They can of course edit that if they want.
So let me go back here and stop the application.
We are in the cart controller.
In order to navigate to the application user,
let me copy everything that we have
in the index and paste it in summary here.
We need to populate the shopping cart view model.
What we have here for user ID looks good.
We will populate the shopping cart view model,
and after that, in the "view model .OrderHeader",
we have "ApplicationUser" that we want to populate.
To retrieve that,
we can go to "_unitofWork.ApplicationUser.Get",
and we can get that based on "u.Id==",
we have that inside the "userId".
Once we have the application user here,
we can manually update all the properties which
are in "OrderHeader", like name, phone number,
street address, city, state, and postal code
based on everything from the "ApplicationUser".
So that will populate the defaults,
and then we are calculating the order total.
That looks good.
When we return back to the view,
we will return the shopping cart view model.
With that in place, let me add a debugging point
and run the application to see how the view model looks
on the summary page.
We will go to "cart" here and hit the "summary" button.
Let me examine the view model
in the "OrderHeader".
Perfect.
You can see, name is populated, city,
we have postal code, phone number, application user.
That looks good.
And we have the shopping cart list.
Based on that, we can populate all the information.
If we go to the view here,
and we have to make this more dynamic.
Let me do that in the next video.