Instructor: We need to make
our summary view here more dynamic.
First thing, what will be the model?
That will be shopping cart view model.
Then we have a link here to go back to the cart.
We will basically redirect to the index action.
That will be the homepage for our shopping cart.
Let me run the application
and see the other properties before I make the updates.
So let me go to cart here and summary.
We hit our break point.
Let me remove that and continue.
And perfect.
Next, we need to populate the shipping details.
We will go to summary here
and first we have the name where we have the input.
We will be adding ASP-4 tag helper for order header.name
and I will also add validation.
Let me copy these two for name, paste it here,
and let me paste it actually in all the places.
And then we can change the model property.
That will be much easier.
Perfect.
We have postal code.
Let me fix that.
Next here we have the state.
We have the city.
Scroll up, we have the street address.
We have the phone number.
Let me paste that.
Scroll up.
Perfect.
That looks good.
Let me go back here.
And you can see it is automatically being populated
based on what a user had when they signed up for an account.
They can obviously change that
to whatever they want before they place the order.
Next, we have to display the order summary
and this will be for all the orders in the shopping cart.
So let me scroll down where we have that right here.
Inside the list group here, we will add a foreach
because we will have to iterate
through variable details in model.shopping cart list.
I will close that right here.
Let me save that and go back to the view.
Perfect, we have two items.
First one here is the title.
We will add details.product.titles
and same will be true for quantity.
That is inside details.count.
Now the total here will be price multiplied by the quantity.
So we will be using grazer syntax.
In there, we will say detail.price.
Multiply that by details.count
and we will convert that to a string,
which will be currency format.
Finally, we have the grand total here.
That is inside model.orderheader.ordertotal
and convert that to currency.
Let me save that and take a look at the UI here.
Perfect, looks great.
Now, estimated arrival date, this is nothing fancy.
I want to display a date that
is seven to 14 days from today's date.
So where we have the estimated arrival date
we can display add days,
add seven days there - and we will add 14 days.
Based on that, it'll display a rough estimated date
based on today's date time.
So perfect.
With that, RUI here for the summary page is looking good.
Rather than shopping cart here,
I will display order summary.
You can change that if you want
but I think that looks good.
Now the main thing here is place an order.
Let me continue with that from the next video.