Instructor: Before we work on
placing the order,
let me walk you through
the order status management
of what happens when an order is placed,
how the status will be updated.
So first, what will happen is when a customer
places an order,
they will have to make a payment.
Before they make a payment,
the order status will be pending,
and payment status will be pending.
Once the payment is successful
on the order confirmation page,
the order status will be approved,
and the payment status will also be approved.
After that, admin will start processing the order
so the order status will be updated
to processing,
but payment status always stays at approved
once it is approved.
when the order is shipped,
the status will be updated to shipped,
and payment status will remain as approved.
Now this is the flow that we have
for a customer placing an order,
but in our website,
we also have another scenario
where a company user is placing an order.
When a company user places an order,
they do not have to make any payment
because they will have 30 days
to make the payment.
So they will directly land
on the order confirmation page,
and they will see their status as approved,
and payment status will be approved
for delayed payment.
Next status will be processing,
which is same and shipped that is also same,
but the payment status for all of them
will be approved for delayed payment.
Then let's say after 10 days or 20 days,
whenever the company makes a payment,
at that point,
that payment status will be updated to approve,
and company user will have 30 days
to make the payment after the order is shipped.
So that is the default flow
that we will have when we are placing an order.
If it is a customer,
they will be navigated to make a payment.
If it is a company,
their status will directly be approved,
and the payment status will be approved
for delayed payment.
Now all of these order status here,
rather than having them in a magic string,
it makes sense to add them
to the static detail file.
So let me switch back here,
and navigate to static details,
and I will be creating
all the constant right here.
I have added the constant for order status here,
and here we have the payment status.
With that configured,
let me continue from the next video.