Instructor: Now we want to work on what happens
when we populate the details here
and when we hit the place order button.
In that case we have to do two things.
We have to insert a record
in the OrderHeader and create that OrderHeader
and after that we will have to create order details
with all the products that are there in the shopping cart.
So let me work through that and stop the project.
We will work on the cart controller.
We have the summary get action method.
Let me copy that and paste it one more time.
Next action method will be the summary post action method.
Let me call that and it will be an HttpPost action method.
Now because the action name is different than summary,
we have to be explicit here
that hey this action name is actually summary action method.
We cannot have the name summary here
because we have the exact name in the get
and that way it will conflict.
So we have to call this action something else
and explicitly define the action name
as summary for HttpPost.
We need to think about what will be the model
that we will receive when we are posting.
Let me open the view here,
go to view and we have the shopping cart view model.
In there we want to retrieve the OrderHeader.Name
PhoneNumber, StreetAddress
so we can retrieve that shopping cart view model
and the parameter of post right here.
We can say ShoppingCart view model and give that a name.
But we can do something better.
What we can do is if we go up,
we have the ShoppingCart view model
and that is what we are using in summary as well.
Because when we go down to the get action method
we are passing that exact ShoppingCart view model.
So what I can do here is I can use BindProperty
and that will automatically
bind the ShoppingCart view model.
It'll work exactly the same like it works in raiser pages
and basically what will happen is when the details
will be populated here and when they hit the submit button
this ShoppingCart view model will automatically
be populated with those values.
And that way we do not have to write that
inside the SummaryPOST action method right here.
The ShoppingCart view model will automatically be populated.
Because that is automatically populated,
we do not have to create a new instance of that.
What we would rather do is we will only
populate the ShoppingCartVM.ShoppingCartList
from the database.
Let me remove everything else here.
So we are populating the ShoppingCartList once again
because when we are posting we might lose some
of the details there
because we do not have everything in the input field.
So that looks good here.
After that, I will populate the OrderDate
to be today's DateTime
and I will populate the ApplicationUserId
and the OrderHeader to be the userId that we retrieve here.
Once we do that, we no longer need this mapping
because that will automatically be populated.
We need to calculate the order total,
so that logic looks good.
And right here we are populating the ApplicationUser.
Now when we have the ApplicationUser populated
we can check that ApplicationUser to find out
if there is a company ID that is associated to that user.
The reason I am saying is in ASP.Net user
we have the company ID.
If that is assigned, that means that it is a company account
and we will be using net 30
and directly placing the order
rather than including any payment gateway.
So I can check here if
ShoppingCartVM.OrderHeader.ApplicationUser
.CompanyId.GetValueOrDefault is equal equal to zero.
Now the reason I am using GetValueOrDefault
is because CompanyId can be null.
GetValueOrDefault will handle that scenario.
If that value is equal equal to zero,
that means it is a regular customer account
and we need to capture payment.
In the else part, it is a company user.
So basically if it is a customer account
then what is the order status?
Let me go back to the PowerPoint here.
We have to make both of them to be pending.
So we go back here, we will assign
the OrderHeader.PaymentStatus as pending
and OrderStatus as pending as well.
Then in the else part, if it is a company account
if I go back when the order is placed,
the status is approved and the payment status is approved
for delayed payment.
So right here let me assign both of those status.
PaymentStatus will be approved for delayed payment
and OrderStatus is approved right there.
With that, we are handling everything
and now we can create the OrderHeader.
So on _unitOfWork.OrderHeader we will add
the OrderHeader is inside ShoppingCartVM.OrderHeader,
and we will save the changes.
That will create OrderHeader.
Right now we have only created OrderHeader,
then we have to create the order detail.
For order detail we will have a foreach loop
and we will say variable cart
in ShoppingCartVM.ShoppingCartList.
For each of the item in the shopping cart
we will have to create an order detailed record.
So we will create individual orderDetail is equal to new
and then we have to populate few details
like ProductId is inside cart.ProductId.
We also have to populate the OrderHeaderId
and how will we get that?
Because we have saved the OrderHeader here
the ShoppingCartVM.OrderHeaderId
will be populated inside there.
So in ShoppingCartVM.OrderHeader
ID field will be populated, because on line 101,
the OrderHeader will be created in the database.
Finally, we need the price that is
inside cart.Price and count is inside cart.Count.
And that looks good for one order detail.
We have to save that to the database,
so _unitOfWork.OrderDetail and we have to add a record.
After we do that, we will call _unitOfWork.Save.
That will create OrderHeader as well as OrderDetail.
Once we have created all the details
we need to redirect to a confirmation page.
Let me do that in the next video.