-: Now once the order header and details is created
we have to add one more logic right here.
Let me copy the if condition, paste it here,
and if it is a regular customer, we need to capture payment,
and for that we will add Stripe logic right here.
I will change the comment here.
It is a regular customer and that looks good.
Now the stripe processing, we will do that
in the upcoming videos, but right now let's assume
that it is a company account and once the order is created
we need to redirect them to an order confirmation page.
So let me redirect them
to another action and we will create that right here.
Public eye action result.
Let me call that order confirmation
and we will pass the integer
which will be order ID.
Right now, we will keep things super simple.
Return back to the view with that ID,
and let me create this view.
It will be order confirmation.
Make sure the spelling is correct there,
and what will be the model.
It will be an integer and that will be the order ID.
Now here we do not want return view.
We wanted to redirect to an action and that will
be name of order confirmation.
Along with that, we need to pass the order ID
so we will pass a new object there where we will
say ID is equal to shopping cart view model dot
order header dot ID, so that way it will pass the
ID here and we will return that back to the view.
Let me design a simple view right here.
Let me create two deals there, one with a class
of container, row padding top of four, and the
other one with column 12 and text center inside there
in the H 1, we'll display order placed successfully.
And then let me also display your order number is
at the rate model.
I will add a few lines here.
Let me do that , and after that I want to display an image
inside the snippets folder,
I have that image.
Let me go back in images, I will copy the book
and lawn leaf image and we will add that in www root images.
Open that and we will paste it right there.
Then, right here we can use the IMG tag.
SRC is equal to images.
In there we have the lawn leaf and width.
Let me give that 65%.
After that, let me create one more div with column 12,
text center, and a custom color.
Add a line there, and I will write your order
has been placed successfully.
Perfect. That UI looks good.
We have a spelling mistake here.
Let me correct that and perfect.
Now with that, if I run the application
and try to place an order
for the company account, things will not work.
Right here.
Let me log into the company account that I have.
If you do not have one
make sure to register for a company account
and let me add a few items to the cart.
I believe I had a few items,
and perfect, order total is 450.
If I go to summary and place order,
we will see an exception.
Perfect. You can see an error occurred
while saving the entity. See inner exception
and violation of primary key constraint in ASP Net users.
Pause the video and find out why this is happening.
I have intentionally introduced this bug,
but I want you guys to figure out on what is going on here.
I hope you guys were able to figure that out.
What I did is when we were creating the post action method
I populated application user.
Now typically what happens is when you are
populating a record here
and you are telling entity framework code that, hey,
I want to add the order header,
it will also add all
the corresponding navigation properties.
It will think that okay
you are trying to create a new entity.
If you do not want that
then you should never populate a navigation
property when you are trying to insert a record
in Entity Framework Core, always remember that.
So work around to this particular issue is we
can have a new application user, call that application user,
and then right here we will access that application
user also in this if condition.
So that is one thing that you should always
remember when you see that Entity Framework Core
is trying to add a navigation property,
most likely the navigation property is populated.
If you want, you can explicitly set that to be null as well
but we know that will not be populated here
so this will work now.
With that configured, let me run the application.
We are logged into our company account.
Let me go to the shopping cart summary
and let me add all one here to see if that works.
Place order.
Perfect. We see our order confirmation page and
if we navigate to our database, examine the order header,
order ID is 5 here and we go to the right.
Perfect. We have the details right here.
Inside the order details,
we have three record
because we had three different products,
their account, and their individual price.
Everything is looking great.
With that configured, our shopping cart logic
for company is looking good and we are able to place order.
One thing that you should remember here is for company
the initial order status is directly approved
and the payment status is approved for delayed payment.
So with that configured
let me continue from the next video.