Instructor: Now if the user is not a company
and if it is a customer, we need to process payment.
For that we will be using Stripe integration
In order to integrate that in our project,
first thing, we need to sign up for an account.
If you do not have an account,
make sure to sign up for a free account.
I already have one, so let me continue.
Once you are in the account
you might have an account right here.
We will be creating a new account
that way you can see everything from scratch.
I will call that as Bulky and Create account.
Perfect.
Once we have that here,
right now we are in the test mode and that is sufficient.
If you go to developers here, and if you look
for API keys, we need two API keys for Stripe.
One is a publishable key and the other one is a secret key.
Now, do not try to use the same keys here
because I will be updating them after the videos
for security purpose, but you can sign up for your account
and get your own publishable and secret keys for free.
So make sure to register
for an account before you continue from the next video.