Instructor: The publishable and the secret key
that we have for our Stripe,
we need to add that in our project.
That way we can access them whenever we want to.
Now, when we have to add any connection
or any secrets in the application,
I will be doing that inside app settings dot JSON file.
Now typically in production,
you might be using a secret vault
or other details for your secrets,
but app settings is a good place to get started.
We already added our database connection here,
so I will be creating a new section for Stripe.
Let me call that Stripe.
And inside there I want two things.
One is a secret key
and the next one here will be publishable key.
Let me navigate to Stripe here,
copy the publishable key.
I will paste it here,
reveal the secret key,
and we will paste that right here.
Secret key starts with an SK
and publishable key starts with a PK.
Perfect, that looks good.
Next thing, what we can do is we can directly
get the section by using the eye configuration,
but I want to show you a slightly different way
of fetching some values from app settings.
What we can do is we can create a utility file
for Stripe settings based on the exact property name
that are right here,
like secret key and publishable key.
I think it is better if I show you
inside the utility project.
Let me create a new class.
I will call that Stripe settings dot cs.
It'll be a public class here
and inside there I will create two properties,
which will have the exact spelling
like we have in the name here,
which is secret key and publishable key.
Then what we can do is inside the program dot cs
we can configure in a manner
that secrets in app settings are automatically injected
inside these properties.
Let me show you how to do that.
Right here we can say builder dot services dot configure
and there we want to configure Stripe settings.
Now, next, how do we want to configure that?
For that we will say builder dot configuration
dot get section,
and we have to write the section name,
name of the section, if you remember, that is Stripe,
but it is always safe to copy and paste that.
Now, as long as the property names
inside the Stripe settings match
what is there in the Stripe section in app settings
it'll automatically inject these values
inside the properties right here.
So that is another way
of fetching the values from your app settings.
Now how and when we will use that,
that we will cover in the upcoming videos,
but right now in our packages we have not even added Stripe.
So what we have to do is first
we have to add the NuGet package for Stripe.
Right click on the project, manage NuGet packages here,
and in the browse tab we will search for Stripe dot net.
Now, when it comes to Stripe
I do not want the pre-release package.
So let me install the stable one,
which is 41.9 as of this recording.
Perfect, it has been installed
and with that Stripe has been added in the project.
When we are using Stripe,
one thing that we have to configure
in program dot cs is the API key
and that API key is the secret key
inside app settings dot JSON.
So scroll down where we have the middleware here.
We have to configure Stripe configuration,
type that,
and if you press control dot,
we have the using statement for Stripe.
There, we have to configure the API key.
This API key is the secret key in app settings dot JSON.
Now we have already populated the Stripe settings,
but that we will use in controller.
Right now we have the builder object,
so on builder dot configuration we have get section.
We will write Stripe here.
That will retrieve the complete section,
but inside the section of Stripe,
we found secret key.
So let me copy that and we will separate that by a colon
and paste the value.
That will actually go inside Stripe, get the secret key,
and on there we will say get
and type of the value is string.
That will fetch the value
and assign that to the Stripe configuration.
With that, Stripe has been configured in our project
and we have also configured the connection strings
for secret key and publishable key.