Instructor: Now before we work
on actually processing the payment through Stripe,
what happens is when we go to Stripe, it creates a session.
And if that session is successful,
it gives us a payment intent ID.
If we examine our models here for order header,
we have a field to store the payment intent ID,
but that is only created if the session is successful.
So we also need to create one more property here,
which will be string, and that will be session ID.
Now how do we get the session ID or payment intent ID?
We will cover that in the upcoming videos,
but right now let me add a migration,
add session ID to order header,
and let me update the database.
Perfect, let me update the database.
And great, that looks good.
Now we know there will be some columns
with session ID and payment intent ID.
So what I will do is I will add some custom helper methods
in the order header.
When we go to the order header repository,
let me open that and the order header.
Perfect, now we update.
It typically updates the complete order header,
but what if based on the ID,
we only want to update the order status or payment status?
For that, let me create a method update status
where order status will be required
but payment status can be empty
because every time when we will be updating the status,
most likely the order status will get updated,
but payment status, once it is approved, it stays approved.
That we saw in the slide.
Let me bring that up here.
You can see the payment status.
Once it is approved, it stays as approved.
And same applies if it is approved for delayed payment.
It stays for that
while the actual order status is being updated.
So order status will be required,
but payment status can be null.
So based on the order header ID,
we can also update only those two fields.
Now we need to implement these two in the order header.
Let me do that for both of them.
We will have to retrieve the order header,
or order from database, based on the ID.
Then first we are working with order status.
If order from DB is not now,
we can update order from DB dot order status,
and then we have to check
if string dot is null or empty payment status.
If that is not null or empty,
then we will update the payment status.
That looks good here,
but when we are updating the session ID
or payment intent ID, at that time,
we need to first check
if not string dot is null or empty session ID.
In that case, we will update order from DB dot session ID
is equal to session ID.
Now a session ID gets generated
when a user tries to make a payment.
When it is successful,
then a payment intent ID gets generated.
So let me copy this and paste it again.
If the payment intent ID is not null,
that means the payment was successful.
In that case, we will update the payment intent ID.
Along with that, we want to update something else,
which is the payment date.
That will be date time dot now.
So that looks good for updating the payment intent
and updating status in our repository.
Let me continue from the next video.