Instructor: Now, if we go back to our BulkyWeb
in the CartController, let me open that,
and close everything else here.
Inside SummaryPOST,
we have to capture a payment using Stripe,
but we have no idea how to do that.
So, best thing is to Google,
and go to the documentation stripe session.net.
We have create a checkout session for Stripe,
and let me see how the documentation looks like.
First thing we have to set the API key,
that we already did inside program.cs,
so that part is covered here.
Then we need to create option,
and we have service.Create.
Let me copy all of this and let me paste that right here.
Let me align this a little bit.
Perfect.
One thing you'll notice here,
is we need a SuccessURL
in case everything is successful where it should redirect.
We have an OrderConfirmation,
but we need the complete URL here.
So let me run the project here,
and get the local host URL.
I will copy this, close that.
And we will create a variable DOMAIN is equal to,
paste that,
let me make it a lowercase, perfect.
So what will be the SuccessUrl?
We want to go to domain, and on top of that,
we want to navigate to customer area,
we have the cart controller,
and the action name is OrderConfirmation.
Let me copy that to avoid spelling mistake, right here.
And there, we have to pass the Id,
that we will get using order header.
So let me escape this here,
and we will get that
from ShoppingCart ViewModel dot OrderHeader dot id.
Now here, we have a forward slash,
so let me remove this one, and that looks good.
On top of that, we also have a cancelUrl,
in that case let me redirect them
to customer and the shopping cart index page.
Perfect.
So success and cancelUrl looks good.
Then we need LineItem,
which will basically have all the product detail.
Now rather than clustering everything here,
let me create new List of SessionLineItemOptions,
and we will configure the LineItems right here,
after we have the Option, let me do that.
To get all the items,
we will have to iterate through the shopping cart list.
So variable item
in ShoppingCart ViewModel dot ShoppingCartList.
And you can see it is a list of LineItemOptions.
So let me copy that,
it is a built-in class Stipe package,
and we will have to create
SessionLineItem is equal to new SessionLineItemOptions.
There, we have to configure a few things.
Now, there are two things you can configure.
You can configure a price or you can configure a price data.
Price data is basically data used to create
a new price object.
So that is exactly what we want here, is equal to new,
and that will be of the type
SessionLineItemPriceDataOptions.
Again, this is built in with Stripe,
and you can see IntelliSense already displayed
that class file to me.
In there,
we have to configure a few things like UnitAmount.
Now UnitAmount is in long, it is not in decimal here.
So what we will have to do,
is what we have in item dot Price.
We will have to multiply that by a hundred.
So basically if something is $20.50,
we have to convert that to be 2050,
and that is what we are doing right here.
Now after unit item,
we have to define the Currency here, that is USD,
and we need to add ProductData.
In ProductData this will be
of new SessionLineItemPriceDataProductDataOptions.
pretty long class names here.
But there, we can give things like images,
name and description of each item.
I will give that to be item.Product.Title,
that looks good for the product data.
Now, with that we are generating the price data,
and that is for one item.
But we also have to define the quantity
like if there is one item, what is the quantity for that?
Based on that,
Stripe will automatically determine the final price.
With that configured,
the sessionLineItem looks good for one item right now
because we are inside the foreach loop,
we have to add all the items in the LineItems right here.
So we can access them from options.LineItems.Add,
and we will add the individual sessionLineItem.
So if there are 10 items in the shopping cart,
it'll iterate and add all of those 10 items.
So now we can remove this logic here,
and we will create a list that looks good.
Next, the Mode is payment, that is the default Mode.
With that we have configured the options here.
And finally, on line 140,
we are creating a new SessionService.
And on the Service,
we are creating that with all the options.
These are all default methods
that we had inside the Stripe documentation
and we have to use them exactly like that.
But when we create a session here,
we can expect a response back from the server.
So let me get that in a session variable of Stripe.
Now, when we get a response of session inside there,
we have both the Id and the PaymentIntent Id.
If I do F12 and examine the Class,
you can see there is an Id.
You scroll down
or if you just search for that,
you will find a PaymentIntent Id, there you go.
So we can get both of them
and we have to update that in our table
before we redirect back.
So we will say unitOfWork.OrderHeader on there,
we want the UpdateStripePaymentID,
where we have to pass the Order Id that is inside
ShoppingCart ViewModel dot OrderHeader dot Id,
and the session Id is inside session.Id,
and PaymentIntent Id is inside session.PaymentIntentId.
Now one thing I will tell you right now is
PaymentIntent Id will be Null right now.
PaymentIntent Id in a session object is only populated
once the payment is successful.
Right now, the payment is not successful.
Right now, we are creating a session,
and after that we will redirect to the Stripe website.
So right now, the PaymentIntent Id will be Null,
but that's okay.
With that configured, let me say if the change here,
and then we have to redirect to Stripe to process payment.
Now what is the URL where we have to redirect?
That is also present in session object that is returned.
So right here, we will say Response.Headers.Add,
and we will set location with the new URL
that is inside session.Url.
And finally we will redirect,
so we will say return new StatusCodeResult of 303,
that basically means that we are redirecting to a new URL
which is provided by Stripe right here.
So with that in place,
we have added quite some code right here
provided the CompanyId is zero.
Now let me run this and see what happens.
We are logged in as a company here,
let me log out and I will log in as a customer user.
I believe I have few items in the shopping cart already,
let me see.
Looks good, the total is 330.
Now let me place order.
And when we hit PLACE ORDER,
you will see it automatically redirects us to Stripe.
And great.
You can see the total price.
We have the item quantity,
and we have a nice checkout session right here.
Now when you work with Stripe,
they have test credit cards like you can use all four two,
and a valid CVV and expiration.
And let me uncheck this and click the Pay button.
What will happen when we hit the Pay button,
it'll actually redirect me back
to the SuccessURL right here.
But before I do that,
let me go to the database
and see if the session Id has been populated.
We have the new OrderHeader here,
you can see OrderStatus and PaymentStatus are pending,
that is good and perfect.
We have the session Id that has been populated,
so things are looking great.
Now, if I select Back button here,
and if I leave, it takes me back to the index page.
So that means that we are back from the Stripe here
and we are back on our page.
If we hit PLACE ORDER,
it'll only take us to the OrderConfirmation page.
But on that page,
how will we know whether the payment was successful or not,
let me show you that in the next video.