-: Now when we go to summary and place order
it takes us to the Stripe and there we have
to enter credit card information and hit "PLACE ORDER."
Once that is successful,
it will take us to this particular page.
But when we go to this page, how will we know
that whether the payment was actually successful or not?
For that, we will have to get the session again
from Stripe and check its status.
So if you scroll down
where we have the order confirmation,
right here we will have to add some logic.
First, based on the ID, we will retrieve
the complete order header.
After that, we only care about payment
if the payment status is not delayed payment
because if that is delayed payment
that we see in the first order
then we do not care about Stripe right now.
So we will add the if condition.
If orderHeader.PaymentStatus is not equal to SD.,
we have the payment status delayed.
If that is not the case, then this is an order by customer.
In that case, we have to go and retrieve a Stripe session.
Doing that is super simple.
Let me create a variable with the name of service
and that will be of type new SessionService
that is a built-in class in Stripe package.
And then we want to retrieve a session object.
Using the service, we can invoke a built-in method,
get inside there, and there,
we basically have to write the session ID.
Good thing is we are saving that session ID
in orderHeader so we can retrieve that session ID
and then we can check the payment status.
So we can say if session.PaymentStatus==
and let me go to stripe documentation
stripessession.net.
And right there let me search for payment_status.
You can see the possible enum values
for payment_status is paid, unpaid, or no_payment_required.
We care if the payment status is paid.
That means everything was successful.
So right here we can convert this to be toLower,
and if that is equal-equal to paid,
that means that actual payment went through.
In that case, this session object
will have the PaymentIntentID.
So let me copy this line, paste it again, and we want
to update the PaymentIntentID and that will work.
Now when we update the PaymentIntentID,
we also have to update the order status.
So OrderHeader.UpdateStatus.
The ID is inside directly the ID.
Copy and paste that, comma...
And the new status will be status approved
and the payment status is also done.
So SD.PaymentStatusApproved.
After all of that, do not forget to do
_unitOfWork.Save or else things won't work.
So perfect, we are updating the payment status here
and everything is completed at this point.
Before we move forward,
what we can do is remove the shopping cart
and make that empty.
So List of ShoppingCart, retrieve all the shopping cart,
_unitOfWork.ShoppingCart.GetAll.
We want to get them based on the user ID.
So u=>u.ApplicationUserId == orderHeader.ApplicationUserId
and we will convert that toList.
Let me break that out so it's easier to read.
Perfect.
Once we have the list,
we need to remove that from our database
so _unitOfWork.ShoppingCart.
We have a RemoveRange there
and we can pass all the shopping cart there.
Finally, we will save the changes and that should work.
With that, we have added quite a few logic
in the order confirmation page
and let me restart the application and test everything
in the next video.