Instructor: I believe everything is complete.
Before we test, let me add a debugging point
in the order confirmation, and let me go back,
let me add one more item
to the cart here, and we'll log in as the customer.
Whoops, I forgot to add that.
Perfect, we go to our card here.
Summary, let me place order.
Perfect, the total looks good.
Let me go back here.
We have the seventh order, and looks good.
We have the session ID.
Let me go back,
enter the dummy credit card number,
and we will select the Pay button.
It is processing that completed.
We got the ID here.
Let me debug one line at a time here
and we create a new service with the session ID,
and perfect.
You can see the payment status is paid,
it went inside, and we got the PaymentIntent ID,
that is populated.
It updates the status and redirects us
to the order confirmation page.
Let me remove the debugging point,
and if we examine this line again,
now the status is approved and we have
the PaymentIntent ID.
Now because the payment was successful,
if I go to stripe.com,
I should be able to see that as well.
We are on the correct account.
Let me go to Payments, and perfect.
You can see this was successful
and the status is also complete.
So with that, our payment has been posted on Stripe,
and our order has been placed successfully.