Instructor: When we have the utility
we have the static details where we created a few roles.
Let me spend a little bit of time to
explain the first two roles that we see right here.
Customer is a basic customer who comes to the website
register for an account and places an order.
But we will also have some special user
which will belong to a company.
Now, the advantage a company user will get is
they do not have to make the payment right away.
They will have 30 days, which technically we call net 30
which means they will get 30 days to make payment
after the order has been placed.
So for them, we will have a different functionality
and a company user can be registered by an admin user.
Now all of those registration complexities we will work on
in the later videos, but right now those are the two roles.
And then we have admin and an employee role.
Employee will have access to maybe modify the shipping
of a product and other details.
But admin will be able to perform all the credit operations
on product and other content management.
That is the reason behind four roles that we have created.
Most of the time,
we will be working on the three roles in the top here
but I wanted to spend a minute to explain you
why we have a role of company.
If a user is given a role of company,
they must belong to some company.
So we need to manage a list
of all the companies that are authorized
in the system as well,
or that we have to perform credit operations
on a company model.
So let me show you what you have to do to accomplish
that as an assignment in the next video.