Instructor: We want to enhance our application,
and it is time for third assignment
where you have to do something
that you have already done before.
And what I mean by that,
is you have to create a new model
or a new table in the database
with the name of company.
And table name will be companies.
That is what we have been using so far.
And inside there, these are all the properties
that you have to create.
Name will be the required property
and everything else will be optional.
You have to add Company
to Repository and UnitOfWork.
And finally, you will have to perform
CRUD Operations on Company using DataTables.
So good luck with that assignment
and I will show you
how to do all of that in the next video.