Instructor: I hope you were able
to complete the assignment.
Let me switch back to the code here
and first we have to add a new model.
I will do that.
Name of the model will be company.
Let me add that.
It will be a public class
and I will be adding all the properties
and name will be required.
Everything else, we will make that optional,
and that looks good.
Once we configure our model here,
we have to add that to our DP set.
So I will open application DP context here
and I will create a DB set where we will have companies,
where the table name will be companies
and we have to add a migration.
Default project.
Make sure it is data access
and we will add a migration, add company table.
Perfect, that looks good.
We have the migration here
and we can update the database to push this migration.
That looks good.
Next we have to work on repository
so copy the category repository, paste it one more time.
Rename that to be company repository.
Let me do that.
We'll copy the name, change the class name here
and the constructor.
The interface will be I company
that we will implement very shortly
and that will be company model.
This also will be company and underscore company.update
the OBJ.
Great.
Company repository looks good.
We need the interface.
Let me copy category and paste that.
Rename that to be I company repository.
Copy the interface name
and modify things here to be company.
And perfect, that looks good.
The error goes away.
Finally we have to add that to our unit of work
and unit of work.
Perfect. Our unit of work looks good.
Let me update the unit of work here.
Copy and paste it for company
and it will be I company repository.
We will initialize that so company is equal
to new company repository and pass underscore DB there.
With that, our unit of work is looking good
with the company model.
Final thing that we have to do is
work on all the current operation
and we want to use data table.
So maybe we can copy what we have for our product
and we can just paste that once again,
controller, whoops, and the admin here, controller.
Copy and paste the product controller
and I will rename that.
So this one will be company controller.
That looks good.
Let me modify things in this file as well.
I will press control shift dev.
I have the company controller open
and inside there, find and replace.
Wherever I find product I will replace that with company.
Let me do that.
Not in the entire solution, inside the current document.
Always make sure to check this when you are replacing.
Let me replace all.
Perfect. That is done.
Let me also see if there is any lowercase product.
Replace that with company.
Replace all.
We did not have any.
Let me see if anything is missed here.
The controller name looks good.
Get all, it is including category that is not needed
and the unit of work will be company here.
That looks good.
We do not have a view model for our company.
So here directly we will be returning a company object.
Let me remove everything here
and we will just return a new company.
That should work.
If it is an update, then we will get a company here.
Let me call that company OBJ and we will return that back.
Perfect.
And upsert, we will retrieve a company object
and nothing else.
Company OBJ, we do not have any file.
Remove that and we will remove the if condition
for our file here.
That is not needed.
We can directly check if company OBJ.ID is equal to zero.
Then we want to add that company, OBJ
Also we want to update the company OBJ.
Whoops. There we go.
Let me hide that here.
And if the model state is not valid,
we return back to the view with company OBJ.
Perfect, looks great.
We do not need the I-web host environment,
so let me remove that from the dependency injection.
Great.
Lastly we have the API cards that are needed for data table.
We do not want to include properties.
That looks good.
When we have to delete, we do not care about the image here
and we can delete the company.
Perfect. Looks great.
Let me save everything.
Close the controller here and we have to modify the view.
So let me copy the product folder
and paste that once again here.
Rename that to be company.
The folder name must match the controller name.
So that is why it has to be exactly like company.
We will go to index here and we do not have any model here.
We can remove that.
Rather than product list, it'll be company list
and it'll be company controller.
Create new company.
Perfect, that looks good.
Next we have the data table.
Here we will modify all the properties
with all the properties that are related
to our company model.
If you want you can remove the address from here,
that way you will get some more width,
but I will keep that here.
That is okay.
Finally we need to create a Java script.
So we will call that company .JS,
and that looks good for index.
We need to modify the main one that is upsert here
and the model here will be company itself.
We do not need any view model.
We can directly check if model .ID is not zero
then update else create and this will be company.
We will have a hidden ID.
We do not have image.
That looks good.
I have to modify all the properties.
So let me do that quickly.
I do not want you to wait and watch.
So let me fix that.
We do not have a text area.
I will remove that one and I will modify
everything else right here.
Perfect, that looks good.
We will remove everything else that is not needed here.
And finally, we have model .IT for update or create pattern.
We do not have the image, I can remove that,
and this can take up the complete column 12.
With that saved here,
I need to add that to underscore layout.
So inside the underscore layout
we will have to add one more item here
and that will be company controller.
Call that company here.
And where I have the role here, let me comment this out
for now because we are developing things.
Right now we will give access to all the content management.
So what we can do is go to company,
well category controller,
and comment out the authorized keywords as well.
When we deploy the application, we will come back
and we will make sure that everything is looking good.
But right now when we are developing things,
let me keep things super simple.
With all of those changes, I believe everything is complete.
Let's see and validate.
Oh, we forgot one thing.
We did not add the java script for our company.
So let me do that real quick here.
JS, copy product, paste that for company,
and there we have to modify the property names here.
So let me do that and change the name, street address,
city, state, and phone number.
We have to follow the camel casing here.
If you are not sure, then see what the API
is returning back.
And based on that you can modify.
The route here will be admin, company, get all.
That looks good.
Then for the upsert here, it'll be company again
and same will be valid for delete.
I believe that looks good.
Let me run the application and see if that works.
We will navigate to company here
and nothing is there in the data table.
Let me add a company.
Now I can create a company from here,
but what I want to do is I want to see the database
and you saw when I click the back button
it takes me back to product.
That is because in upsert here,
I am sure it is product controller,
where it should be company controller.
Perfect.
But basically, I want to seed our company table
with let's say two companies for now.
So let me do that real quick.
We will go to application DP context here.
Let me hide this and copy what we have for our category.
Paste it one more time.
We want to see our company table.
Let me create a company record here.
Perfect. I have added three records here
for ID one, two, and three.
Next thing that I have to do is add a migration.
I will call that, add company records,
and once that is done we have to update the database.
That looks good.
After that, let me start the application again.
This time we should see the three records in company.
I will try to perform red operation as well.
That is category, we have to go to company.
Looks good.
We have the validation test.
Let me try to create that.
That worked.
Let me try to delete.
Let me try to edit that first
and let me try to delete.
Perfect.
So all the current operations on company
are working as expected.