Narrator: We have added company
and we are able to perform the current operation,
but when a user is registered,
we have to assign that user that hey,
this user belongs to a company.
For that, we need to add a foreign key relation on our user.
We will go to data access.
Well, we first have to go to model here
where we have application user
and we have to add that foreign key relation
to the company table.
So first, we will add an integer and this will be nullable
because it is possible that the user is a customer user
and if it is customer, then they will not have a company.
But if it is a company user,
only then, they will have a company ID assigned
to their profile.
So for a fact, that looks good.
Next, we need the navigation property.
We will have to add the foreign key.
And there, we have to say that CompanyId
is the navigation property for this company that we have.
And we do not want to validate this company
because that will not be populated
when we are creating a user or anything else.
So that way, we have added the foreign key relation
on our user.
Change that we have made is in our core model.
So we will have to add a new migration.
I will call that addCompanyToUser.
And once that is done, we will have to update the database.
Perfect, you can see AddColumn.
Nullable is true.
That looks good.
Perfect, migration has been applied.
With that configured, let me run the application once again.
Now, if we go to register here,
if we select the role of company,
then right here, I want to show another dropdown
where I will display list of all the companies.
So let me modify that in the register.
I can search for that.
We want both the page model as well as the page.
First, we have to populate that registered dropdown
and pass that on to the Razor Page.
In order to access that, we will need unit of work
using dependency injection, so let me add that.
And then, we have to add CompanyId inside the input model.
Let me do that right here.
And we need a dropdown.
So copy the role list here
and modify that to be company list.
We have to populate the company list on the OnGet here.
So where we have the role list,
copy that, paste it for the company list.
For that, we will go to underscore unitOfWork.Company
and on there, we have GetAll.
Then, we will have the select statement
where we will transform that to a select list item.
Text will be i.Name and value will be i.Id.ToString.
Perfect, that looks good.
And we have the input.
We can go to our page here
and where we have the role here, let me copy this,
paste it one more time, and this will be company list,
and asp-for will be CompanyId.
We will display select company here.
And that looks good.
With that configured, let me switch back here
and we will have to restart the project.
Let me do that.
We go to register here, and great.
We have the dropdown to select a company.
With that configured, let me continue from the next video.