Instructor: Now the dropdown
for our company should not always be visible.
I want it to be visible,
if the selected role is company.
We will quickly achieve that using JavaScript.
Where we have the dropdown here,
we will say Style display, none, and we scroll down.
We have the section for script.
Inside there we will be adding a script tag
and we can add custom JavaScript.
We will add that when the document is ready
and there what we want to do is when row is modified
we wanted to trigger that section.
If I do F 12 here and examine this,
you will notice that it automatically gets
an ID of input underscore role.
So I can use that here.
And I will say, when input underscore role
dot change is triggered,
then I want to invoke a function.
In that function we will have to get what role
has been selected.
If that is company,
only then we want to toggle the dropdown.
So we will say variable selection is equal to dollar,
and there we can get that using hash, paste the input roll,
and then we can get option which is selected
that will give us the value that has been selected
and we will call the dot text down there.
Finally, we can check if selection is equally
equal to company,
what do we want to do in that case?
In that case, we want to show the dropdown.
Now which dropdown do we want to toggle?
Let me get its id.
That is input underscore company id.
These IDs are generated automatically based on
the A S P four that we have.
So right here we will add the dollar sign
and I will say hash,
input underscore company id dot show.
In the L spot here,
I will hide that.
I believe that looks good
but JavaScript is a tricky business.
So unless and until we restart the application,
or see that in action, it is hard to believe
because there are chances of a spelling mistake.
We select company that comes up and perfect.
If I select anything else, then the dropdown disappears.
Perfect, that looks good for our dropdown.