Instructor: Final thing that is remaining here is
if we have company and we select a company here,
we need to populate the company ID
when we register the user
and this company ID should only be populated
if the role is company.
So let me switch back and we will go to the page model
where we have the on post.
Before we create the user, we have to check here
if Input.role is equal equal to SD.role_company,
in that case, we want to assign user.CompanyId
is equal to Input.CompanyId.
With that configured, let me restart and see if that works.
I will also open SQL server
to test the user that has been created.
We will select company and let me give that
Vivid Books, register.
Perfect, that is done.
Let me switch back to our database,
bulky and let me examine the ASPNET user's table.
Where is the new user?
Right here. We go to the right and perfect.
We have the company ID that has been assigned
and that looks great.
With that, we are able to register company users
in our application.