-: We have made great progress with our project.
We have products where we have categories.
And now what we should do is on the homepage
of the application we should display all the products.
And for that you need to think
about what we will do in controller and action method.
Let me close the project here.
The controller that we will be working on for that
is inside "Customer".
We have the home controller Index action.
Now we will be working in the "Customer" area
because the homepage will be accessible
to all the users and not just admin user.
In the homepage you need to think
about what we need to display.
We will be displaying all the products.
So basically we need to get all the products
from database and for that we need unit of work
using dependency injection.
So let me add private read only unitOfWork and inject that
like we did in product and category controller.
Then in the Index here we will get an IEnumerable
of Product and let me call that productList
is equal to _unitOfWork.Product.GetAll.
And when we are getting, we want to include "Category".
So do not forget that.
When we retrieve the productList here we can return back
to the View and we will pass the productList here.
Next we have to go to the View and design that view.
First thing that you should think of is what will be model.
That will be a lowercase,
and that will be IEnumerable of Product.
We already have the using statement in the import.
That's why we can directly write Product right there.
In there, let me add a div, give it a class of row pb-3
and then we need to iterate through the IEnumerable.
So I will add a foreach loop variable product in Model.
For each one of them I will add a div,
give it a class of col-lg-3
and col-sm-6
bootstrap classes.
In there I will add a class of row p-2.
I need the closing div here.
Perfect.
There I will add a div, give it a class of "col-12 p-1".
Let me close that div as well.
I don't know why the closing divs are not working
as expected, whoops.
Let me align them, ctrl+A, ctrl+KD.
Perfect, then I will add the final div
which will be a bootstrap card layout.
And there I will give class of card, border-3 p-3 shadow
and border rounded.
Within there I want to display the image.
So img src is equal to
that is inside product
which is the local variable that we have here.
Dot we have ImageUrl and I will give it bootstrap classes
of card-img-top
and rounded.
Let me save that and run the application.
We should see six images here.
It might take a second but perfect.
I can see all of the images loaded right here.
That looks great.
After that I can add a div,
give it a class of card-body,
padding bottom of 0,
add the closing div as well.
It is annoying when the closing div does not add itself.
And I will add a div with pl-1.
Inside the pl-1, I will add two paragraph tag
and basically it has bootstrap classes for designing.
First one I will display product.Title,
and next one will be product.Author.
Save that.
Let's see how that looks here
and perfect.
Looks great.
Let me go back to the code, copy the pl-1,
paste it one more time here.
And we don't want the card-title.
We will have text-dark opacity, looks good
text-opacity and text-center.
At there I will display the lowest price.
So I will say as low as
and in a span
we will display product.Price100.
That is the lowest price that we will have.
Dot ToString and we will format that in a currency.
So we will add "c".
And let me go back to the UI here.
Perfect. Looks great.
So our currency looks good.
Let me copy this, paste it one more time
and let me also display the list price.
I think before we should display the list price
and then the lowest price that makes more sense.
Perfect, list price and then the lowest price.
Let me see.
Perfect. Let me go back here.
And before the span, well
inside the span I will add a class
text-decoration-line-through,
that will make sure that it adds a line there.
And before this,
I will display list price.
Let me break it out in separate lines here.
Perfect, that looks good.
Let me organize this as well
and great.
We go back to the UI
and that looks much better.
I want to remove the margin here.
So where we have this, I will say mb-0.
Let's see how that looks
and great
I like how the homepage is coming along.
Final thing that I want is a link to go
to the product details here.
So let me go back.
After we have the div of card-body,
I will add one more div here.
In there I will have an anchor tag
and we will display details,
Href, let me keep it as hash for now and see how that looks.
Whoops, we have an error there.
I forgot to double quotes
and that should fix it.
Perfect, so homepage of our application looks great.
Now in the next video, let's work on the details page.