-: When a user clicks on the detail page
we want to display all the product details on that page.
So what will be the model for that page?
It'll basically be a single product.
So what we should do is go back
to the code here in home controller where we have index,
copy and paste action method.
We will call that as details
and we will require an ID.
Based on that ID, we will get all the details
and not get all because it'll be a single product.
We will call that product and we will return
that to the view.
Let me do that.
Perfect, that looks good.
Now when we are getting a product, we need to add
the link operator u goes to u dot id is equal, equal to id.
Based on that it will retrieve the product details.
Once that is done, let me add that view.
I can directly click add view here and add that.
Change the name to be details
and let me make sure it got added in the right area.
Yes, it did.
Perfect.
So with that we have added what should happen
on the details, but on the homepage or the index
we need to add that redirect.
Now because we are in the same area and same controller
I can only write the action method that call
the action details.
It will by default use the same area and same controller.
But on top of that
when it is being calling that if we examine the controller
we need to pass the id.
So if I go back here
we will say ASP route and name is id.
We will use the exact same name.
If you want to call that as product id, then we will
have to use the same name right here and that should work.
So how do we get the product ID that is inside
product dot id,
Perfect.
That should work.
Let me run the application and see that in action.
Let me click here.
Perfect, product id one, go back.
Product ID three.
And that works.
So perfect.
Now we are able to navigate and that is working as expected.