Instructor: Now we need to design the details page.
If we go to the homepage,
we have all the products, and that design looks good.
But when we go on the details page,
we need to display image, category, price,
and much more.
Rather than spending time in writing Bootstrap and CSS,
I have provided that in snippets.
Make sure you have downloaded them,
and then, in the snippets here, in Section 6,
in Section 7, we have the details UI.
Copy everything there,
and I will paste it inside our details view right here.
Now, whatever I have here, it is purely HTML and CSS.
You can see there is no tag helpers,
or anything related to .NET programming.
It is all HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
Save that.
And if we go back and navigate to the details page,
we have a fancy design template that is ready
with only HTML and CSS.
We need to populate this with all the dynamic data,
so let me do that one thing at a time,
starting with the title.
If we go to the top,
in order to get anything here,
we need to add model.
What will be the model?
In details here, we are passing a product,
so that will be our model.
Where we have the title here,
where we'll say Model., we have Title.
Let me copy the model here.
Next we have Model.Author.
When we have to go back to the homepage,
we can add asp-action.
It will be Index action.
Then we need the image here,
that will be, I have to write Model.ImageURL.
Scroll down.
We have Category, that is inside Model.Category.Name.
ISBN, ListPrice is Model.ListPrice,
and we'll convert that to currency.
Then we have Quantity here,
we have Price twice here.
Let me see what is going on in the template first.
We need the first price here,
and then we need to toggle all the price.
So here, we will have Model.Price.ToString,
and currency format.
Paste that here.
Let me copy .ToString.
And let me see how the UI looks like.
Perfect. Looks good.
After that, we need the description.
Now before I work on description,
let me go to product,
and make the description a little fancy.
I will just go to Lorem Ipsum,
and let me generate something there.
I will copy that,
paste it here.
And let me make some things bold,
some things italica,
and underline one word.
Let me copy that update,
and I will save that for all the description.
Now, the reason I want to do that for all of them,
is that the UI looks a little consistent.
So, let me do that real quick.
Because of all the scrolling,
I think it was best if the back button was at the top here,
so that could be updated later on.
But perfect, description looks good.
Now if I go to the homepage, DETAILS here,
and let me modify the description here
to be Model.Description,
you will see something ugly here, which is HTML text.
That is because we have the rich text editor,
and if we have to convert that,
we have something called as HTML.Raw,
and we need to pass Model.Description inside there.
And perfect.
You can see,
it translates that exactly back to what we wanted.
So, BACK TO HOME should work now, let's go there.
Go to another DETAILS,
and we have a Count button, which you can ignore.
We have an ADD TO CART as well,
but that is coming soon,
we do not have that in our functionality right now.
I can go to the top here,
and I will add margin bottom of 4 as well.
And perfect, that looks better for the details page.
Now we will ignore the Count here, and ADD TO CART,
but basically, on our website,
we have the homepage and details page
that is working as expected.