Instructor: Now we want to work on repository pattern
but when we are working with this,
if things are confusing, do not worry.
By the end of this section
everything will make much more sense.
But stick with me,
and I will explain you everything that we are doing here.
Let me close everything.
Inside the data project we have the data access.
There we will be creating a new folder
that will hold all the repository.
We will have a repository folder,
and in that folder we will have the interface for that
which is IRepository.
Repository interface that we will be creating
will be a generic interface.
So we will create an interface here
and I will call that IRepository.cs.
Perfect.
Now typically when we are working with generic
we do not know what the class type will be,
so I will call that it'll be a generic class T.
And we will say where T will be a class.
So when the IRepository will be implemented,
at that time we will know
on what class the implementation will be.
Because right now we have category
on which we want to implement repository.
Down the road we will have product
and many other tables like order header, order detail.
And because of that we are making this generic here.
Then we need to think about what will be all of the methods
that we want right now.
Now of course I do not expect you
to think about all of them,
but basically what will be the basic ones?
And then if we have to update our repository,
we will of course do that as we proceed with the course.
So here, first thing that I will comment, T will be category
or any other generic model on which we want to
perform the CRUD operation, or rather,
we want to interact with the DB context.
For an example I have written that T will be category,
and then think about what will be all the operations
that we need right now
when we are performing the CRUD operations on category.
The first one that I can think of is we need to retrieve
all the category where we are displaying all of them.
So we can say the return type will be IEnumerable of T,
and we can call that method as GetAll.
The one after that will be if we have to retrieve
only one category,
because many times like on the edit page
we have to retrieve the details of one category
and then we have to pass that or display that on the screen.
So in that case the return type will be a single category,
and let me call that function GetFirstOrDefault.
Now you can call this as get as well if you want.
I like to call it GetFirstOrDefault,
that way I'm a little bit more explicit.
But if you only want to call that get, that is also fine.
And the name of the function, we can call that get
because we are fetching only one of them.
And that's fine here.
What will be the parameter?
Now if you examine what we are doing
in the controller, CategoryController
where we have to retrieve one category and edit.
You can see there are multiple ways to do that.
We can use find, we can use FirstOrDefault
we will be using the FirstOrDefault approach.
But there we need something special.
We need a LINQ operation.
The reason we will not be using find
is that only works on the ID,
but if you want some other condition to get one record,
you can pass that using the LINQ operator.
So basically in parameter
we will be getting a LINQ operation like this.
How do you write that here?
For that we have something called as an expression,
and there we will say function type will be T comma boolean.
So what we will be getting will be a function
and the out result will be a boolean.
We can call that as filter when we are fetching
an individual record.
Now, do not try to spend too much time on why
I have to write it exactly like this.
You can think of that
when you want to write a LINQ expression
that we have in FirstOrDefault,
this is the general syntax for that.
So perfect, we have GetAll and we have get individual.
Then we have to create a category, remove a category,
and sometimes it is possible
you want to remove multiple categories in one single call.
So we will say void here, we will have a add method
where we have to pass the object that needs to be added.
We have an update as well and we have a delete.
Then I also want something called as DeleteRange
which will delete multiple entities in a single call.
The parameter here we will receive an IEnumerable
or a collection of entities.
Rather than delete, I like to use remove,
so let me make them Remove and RemoveRange.
Now if you remember when we were working
with EF Core and we were updating or adding anything,
we always had to call the save changes.
When we work with a repository pattern,
we do not like the update or add method
directly inside the genetic repository.
The reason is simple, when you are updating a category,
logic might be different
than what you are doing when you are updating a product.
With EF core, you only use the update statement
so it could be same as well.
But typically I have seen that update is more complicated
because sometimes you only want to update a few properties
or you have some other logic.
Because of that, I like to keep the update
and save changes out of the repository,
and when we will implement like category repository,
we'll implement the generic repository.
On there we will have the update and save method.
So in the generic repository we will only have add
and not update.
We will have add, remove, and remove range.
Perfect.
With that, we have the generic repository
and interface is looking good.
We still need to implement this interface.
Let me do that in the next video.