Instructor: Now we are getting into the fun part
of implementing our repository.
So, in the repository folder, I will add a Class,
call that Repository
and that will implement the IRepository.
I will make that a public class.
We need to implement the interface here
and it's not finding that.
Maybe it's internal.
Change that to be public here.
If I press Control Dot, I am facing some issue here
and the reason is because I have Repository and IRepository.
If you want, you can rename that,
but I will add the using statement
for Bulky.DataAccess.Repository.IRepository.
With that, we will get the IRepository,
but one thing that we have to define in IRepository
is what is the Class?
Right now also, we are working with generic here,
so we will say T where T is Class
and, with that, the repository class
is implementing IRepository.
If you press Control Dot, we have the implement interface.
When we are adding the generic here,
we need to make the Class generic as well
and perfect, that works.
With that, we have all the methods right here.
Let's implement that.
When we were adding an entity,
we used to add that on _db.ad
and then we used to add the entity.
So, we will need that using dependency injection.
I will have the private read-only application dbContext
and in the constructor we will get application dbContext
and assign that right here.
But now, one thing will be different.
Previously, when we were working on something,
we had _db.Categories and then we had add,
but right now we don't know that
and here we cannot use the generic like this.
So, we cannot say db.T, because it does not know
what that stands for.
We want to make sure we use generic.
That way, we can access the dbSet directly.
So, right here, I can create an internal dbSet
on the generic type T and contact S dbSet
and then we can say this.dbSet is equal to _db.
We can set the current one, that is the generic one
that we get here, and that will be set to the dbSet.
So, when we create this generic class on category,
the dbSet will set to Categories.
So, in simple words, where we have _db.Categories
this will be equivalent to the dbSet that we have.
So, when we were saying _db.Categories.Add
and we were passing some entity here,
now all we have to say is dbSet.Add
I hope that makes sense here,
so where we have the Add, we will say _dbSet.Add
and we have the entity.
That way, we are able to use the dbSet
and it will be generic based on the type.
Repository here is implemented.
So, perfect, and it looks good here.
Next, what we have here, let me remove this,
and add a using statement.
It is much cleaner.
We have the individual Get and, for that,
we will be working on an IQueryable of T.
We will call that query
and we will assign the complete dbSet here.
So, basically right now, we have the complete dbSet
that we have assigned here.
Then, on the query, we can apply a Where condition
and I can pass the filter.
Whatever we get here, we will assign that
back to the query.
So that way, whatever condition we have,
it will apply that on a Where condition
and it will have the query ready for that.
Now, Get must always return one entity.
So, when we return back, we can say from query,
we want the FirstOrDefault
What we did here is exactly the same that I had
in the comment right here.
First, on the dbSet, we have the Where condition
and then we are getting the FirstOrDefault from that record.
That is the logic that we have implemented right here.
Then, we have the GetAll
We can copy the IQueryable there
and we can return back query.ToList
because dbSet will basically have all the records
like Categories in our example.
We have to convert that and return back.
Finally, we have Remove,
that is on dbSet, we have Remove,
and we can pass the entity.
Similar to Remove, we also have a built-in method,
which is RemoveRange.
Let me add that and that is also inside EF Core.
That RemoveRange expects an IEnumerable
and it will remove all of those Categories
that are passed to the IEnumerable.
So, perfect, with that our repository interface
has been implemented and this looks much cleaner.
Let me continue from the next video.