-: We have the category controller where we were
using application DB context
but now we do not have to use this directly.
We can access the category repository.
How will we do that?
Rather than application DB context, we will say
that we want an implementation of category repository
and we are asking dependency injection
to provide that implementation.
Then on the underscore DB
we have all the helper methods that we have created.
Well, rather than underscore DB
it makes sense to call this category repository.
That way it makes more sense when we are consuming that.
Perfect.
So when we have to retrieve everything
we have underscore category repo dot get all.
We created that, scroll down where we had to create,
we had the underscore cat repo dot add method
and when we have to save the changes
we will say underscore cat repo dot save.
Great, that looks good.
Let me scroll down further.
When we had to retrieve the category for edit
we will go to underscore category repo dot.
We have the cat and we will pass the link
operator u goes to u dot ID is equal, equal to id.
That way we are using category repository here.
Next we have update.
Let me copy what we have for add here, paste it right here
and we have update.
That looks good.
We have the find again, let's copy the edit one,
paste it here and we have the find again,
paste it right there and we have the underscore category
repo dot remove and save changes.
Perfect, so you can see with this we have our repository
in place.
If we save everything, we no longer have application
DB context right here.
When we run the application, we will run
into an error message.
I want to show you, because this is a common error message
many times.
You can see I click on category and it says
unable to resolve for type I category repository
while attempting to activate the category controller.
Whenever you see unable to resolve service
for type, the first thing you should
-: Think about is there is some issue when
registering that service to the container.
Because here you are asking dependency injection to
provide an implementation of the I category repository.
But have you even registered that service
in the dependency injection container?
We have not.
So that is one thing that you should always remember.
If there is any service
you have to register that to dependency injection.
Now what will be the lifetime?
Typically scoped is the most common one
and that should be used so that for one request
it'll use the same service.
So here we have the interface as I category repository
and implementation is in category repository
at the using statement there and perfect.
Now we have added the category repository
in the dependency injection.
So in controller, when we want the implementation
the program knows that I have to give the implementation
of category repository.
Let me run this
and everything will work exactly the same like it used to.
With application DB context
we can see all the categories here.
If I try to create one, that worked, I can delete that
and perfect.
All the grid operations are working.
But now we are doing that with our repository.