Instructor: In the last video,
you saw we were able to perform all the grad operations
on category using our repository.
But before the last video and current video
something has changed on my machine.
And what I mean by that
is if I go back and examine the appsettings.json file,
you remember the server name was a dot?
Now if I go here
and if I connect using dot, it does not work.
Well, I had to reset my laptop for some reason
and because of that, I encountered this issue.
So now what is the solution?
The LocalDB/MSSQLLocalDB,
I'm able to connect to that particular server.
For that, I can press the connect icon here and copy this
and we will update that inside the server right here.
If we examine that
you can see rather than one backward slash
it automatically added two backward slash,
and that looks good.
But now you might be wondering that,
hey, we had our migration,
we had our data inside the database.
What happens to all of that?
Well, because we are using Entity Framework Core
things are super simple.
We do not have a Bulky database here.
To create that inside the Package Manager Console,
all we have to write is the command update-database.
We do not have to add any migration.
We only have to update-database
because all the migration are already present in our code.
With that one line
if I run the application now
everything should work the same.
You can see category and we have the three categories
that we were seeding our database with.
With that, I want you to analyze
the importance of migrations
and how easy it is to get started with a project.
For an example, if a new developer
had to set up this code on their laptop,
they just have to clone the repository
and press the command update-database.
Right now it is a local SQL server, but if it was Azure SQL,
then they just have to run the command update-database
and the code should work automatically on their machine.
And that reminds me of my good old days
when I had to spend almost a day to set up a code
on my machine because back then we had many dependencies
and we had to handle all of them.
But with Entity Framework Core,
you can see if a database is different,
it does not take much time.
We only have to update connection string,
run the command update-database,
migrations get pushed automatically,
and we are up and running.
So I wanted to quickly show you
on how you can easily update connection string
and again bring your project with all the categories.