Instructor: Now in our project we have
category repository
and that is handling the CRUD operations for category.
Category repository looks good but it is not perfect.
And what I mean by that is
let me go to controller here and let's think
that in a controller you have many action method
and you are using about 10 different repositories.
You will have to inject all of them.
That is completely okay.
That actually gives you the freedom that hey
you only inject the repository that is needed.
But one drawback here is if you go to repository, and
if we go to category repository, we have the save method.
Now this save method will be there
in all the individual repositories that we will have
down the road like product, order, shopping cart
and everyone else.
But the save functionality is not relevant
to the repository or the model.
It is a global method that is being used.
So the correct way of doing things is to have the save
and something called us unit of work.
But before I implement that, I do want to tell you
that if you only want to use the category repository
in a project, that is completely okay.
Adding a unit of work is not always required.
I like that personally because it gives a clean approach.
But with that there are some drawbacks as well
which I will cover as we proceed with the goals.
But before that, we have the big question
on how will we have the unit of work.
Inside the IRepository here, let me add a new item.
Let me stop the project first, right click, add a new item.
And with the new version of Visual Studio
they have implemented a compact view.
I do like that when I have to add the CS file
but for interface, we can click show all templates here
interface and rename that to be IUnitOfWork.
Let's add that and we will make this a public interface.
In here we will have all the repositories
so ICategoryRepository
and we will only have the get inside there.
Next we can implement the global method here, like save.
Now the implementation
of how we will get the category repository.
That will be done in repository folder.
We will create, I can use the compact view.
I need only the class file.
I will call that unit of work.
This will be a public class
and it'll implement the IUnit of work interface.
We will press CTRL dot and implement the interface.
Perfect.
We need an implementation
for the category repository here.
Let me add a getter and a private setter right there.
Now like in the category repository
we had application DB context using dependency injection.
We will do the same thing
and that will be done in unit of work right here.
We will have the class name as unit
of work here and we do not have any base clause.
We can remove that, right here where we have
the category repository.
We can add that in the constructor.
Let me cut and paste it here.
I will call that category and we will say category is equal
to new category repository.
And we'll pass the DB context right there.
And we have an error here
because in interface we call that category repository.
We change that to category here
and perfect, the error goes away.
So now in unit of work
we have something for category repository where
we are passing the DB context as well.
Lastly, let me modify the save here
cut that and paste the implementation here.
And we do not need the save method
inside the individual repository.
I'll have to remove that from the interface as well.
And perfect.
Looks good.
So with that, our unit of work looks good
and it has the implementation for our category repository.
Let me close both the files here
and in the next video let me work
on category controller, not the repository.
I closed that accidentally.
We have category controller here.
We do not want to use the category repository.
We want to use the unit of work that we configured
because it internally has category repository as well.