When we are working with a new website, typically we have a database and inside there we have multiple
tables.
And based on that table we perform some operation and display some data.
Before we get into all the complexities here, when we are working with Entity Framework Core and MVC
application, we do not create tables directly in the database.
Rather, we create a model in our project and we tell entity framework that, hey, based on the model
that I have created here, I want you to figure out and create table inside database and do that automatically.
Now, that might seem magical right now, but it is the power of entity framework core that will allow
us to do all of that.
Before we do anything like that in our models, we have to create a model.
So in the bulky web here we have the models folder, right click there and we will add a new class.
Now it does not have to be inside the models folder.
There are no rules about that.
It is one of those things that models we typically add them in the models folder.
You can rename that folder if you want, but I wanted to point out that models is not something that
is required, like we have the controllers and views folder.
Those names cannot be updated.
They have to be exactly the same name, but models.
You can change it if you want.
The first model that I want to work on is the category model, so I will write category .CS and
press the enter button.
Perfect.
It creates a class here.
And inside this class of category, we will be creating multiple properties.
Now, all the properties that we will create in the category class, they will basically be all the
columns that we want in category table.
How that mapping works.
Do not worry.
Right now I can write prop here and press tab.
It is a code snippet.
We have to press tab twice and it automatically creates a property.
I will call that as ID.
I have defined ID as the integer property and this will basically be the primary key of the table.
Next thing we have another property which will be string and let me call that name, which will be the
category name.
And last property that I want right now is display order.
If we have multiple categories, which category should be displayed first on the page that will define
the display order.
So perfect.
We have created a category class here.
In there we have added three properties.
Next item that I want to focus on is I already said that ID will be the primary key of the table, but
how can we explicitly define that in our model?
For that we have to use something called as data annotation.
Let me walk you through them in the next video.