Now is the time to see some magic.
Well, it is not magic.
It is basically the power of entity framework core that we will see in this video.
We want to create a category table and we want to add these three columns.
Before I do that rather than ID here, let me call that category 21 ID and remove the key data annotation
that we added because I want to show you an error message before we continue on with the video.
Now, I have said before, if you use key data annotation, that is how entity framework core will know
that this column will be the primary key of the table.
But right now it is not defined.
And the column name, if it was category ID, which is basically the model name, followed by ID, or
if it was only ID, then also it will automatically default that to be the primary key.
But intentionally, I am calling that category 21 ID.
With that configured, we want to create this table in our database.
Now, where is our database?
If we have to find that in our files, where do you think it is?
Anything that we have to do with our database is inside application.
DB Context, because that is where we have.
DB Context, which uses entity framework core.
When we have to create a table here, we have to create something called as DB set inside application
DB Context.
So I will write prop here press tab and the type here will be DB set.
And there we have to define the entity which is a class.
So what is the entity of this DB set?
We want to create a category table, so I will add category here and then my property will basically
be the table name that you want for that table inside SQL Server.
If you want to call that categories, then you can write categories here and that will be the table
that will be created in database.
This simple one line will automatically create table, and that is the power of entity framework core.
In order to create table, we have to do something called as a migration to add that we have to go to
tools NuGet Package manager and package Manager console.
Here, we will have to write a new command, which is add migration, and then we have to give our migration
a meaningful name.
In this migration.
We know what we are doing is we are adding category table.
We will give our migration the name of ADD category table to DB and we will press enter.
Now, when you press enter right now, you will see an error message because we do not have a primary
key.
And perfect.
You can see if we expand this here, the entity type category requires a primary key to be defined.
We do not have that defined here.
Because of that, we saw that error message.
If I write key here and then run the migration, it will create a command to create table with this
particular primary key.
I do not want that.
I want to call it an ID, so I will change that to be an ID and then we will run that same command once
again, which is add migration.
Perfect.
This time something just happened.
We can see build started, build, succeeded.
And we have to undo this action.
Use remove migration.
But what exactly just happened?
And in the back end here, a new file has been created.
If we go to Solution Explorer here, let me pin this for a second here and show you what happened.
If you examine, there is a new folder that has automatically been created with the name of migrations
and there we have some random entity here which is basically date, timestamp and then name of the migration,
which is add category table to DB.
That is the file that is open right here.
Now, what exactly is this file?
Well, if you examine here, entity framework core has written some code in its own language to create
our category table.
You can see there is something called as migration builder.
And on there there is a command create table.
It is creating a table with the name of categories, and then in columns it is creating three columns,
ID,name and display order.
In the constraints.
Here we have something like table Primary key will be the ID column that you can see right here.
And another thing is we have something called as up and we have something called as down.
So if everything is successful, we want to create this table.
But if something does not go right in the down method here, it says drop the table that you were trying
to create.
So down is basically rolling back whatever we were doing inside the up function right here.
Now, again, you might be thinking that, okay, we have something with Migration Builder, but how
will this table be created?
We do not have a SQL statement of create table and we do not have anything to define the identity column.
There is just something called as SQLServer.identity.
That is where entity framework core again comes to picture.
Now that we have added the migration here in the package manager console, if we run the command update
database, what entity framework core will do is it will check, hey, are there any migrations that
have not been applied to the database?
The answer will be yes.
The new migration that we added has not been applied to the database yet because if we go back to the
database, we do not have that table now, even though this is related.
More on the entity framework side, I want to spend a couple of minutes to explain how it will figure
out which migrations have not been applied.
If you see in the table it created if migrations history table.
If I do select top 1000 here, I did the edit by mistake, but if I do select top 1000, that is empty.
It means no migrations have been applied on the database.
Because of that.
When we apply the command update database here, it will check in that database that what was the last
migration that was applied since nothing was applied, it will go to the migrations folder and whatever
migrations are there, it will apply that on the database.
So it will take this code here, convert that to the equivalent SQL code and it will create that table.
Let me see that in action.
So we go back and we will press enter here and it does something perfect we have done here.
Once it is done.
If I go back to the server and if I refresh here now, you can see in the migrations history, it is
tracking that this particular migration at category table to DB has been applied.
If I refresh the table here, you will see the new table of categories has been created and there are
the three columns.
Table name is categories and that is what we have as the DB set property name.
Right now, if you are confused and if you think that some magic just happened and it created the table,
do not worry, you are just getting started with entity framework core and it is the power of entity
framework code that you can accomplish using migrations.
As we proceed with the course, you will see this in much more detail and you will fall in love with
migrations.
That way you do not have to deal with writing the SQL commands or working directly with the database.
You will be doing one thing that you love, which is writing code, and that code will automatically
do all the heavy lifting for your database.
But before I end the video, let me summarize what we have to do when we have to create a table.
We first have to create a model inside there.
We will have few properties.
Next in the application DB context, we have to create a DB set for that.
Then in the package manager console, we have to add a migration.
Once we add migration, then we have to run the command update database and that will push the migrations
to your database.
And with that we have created our categories table in our database.
Let me continue from the next video.