We want to perform CRUD operations on category.
That basically means we want to create a category, get all categories, delete a category and update
a category.
And for that we will be requiring a controller because right now when we run the application, we only
have the home controller.
You can see we have the home and privacy here.
Similarly, we want a category controller where we can manage all the categories.
So let me stop the application here and where we have home controller in the controllers folder, right
click Add, we have a controller now you can use the other templates that are there, but we want to
start fresh.
So I will use MVC, empty controller and we have to give it a name.
Let me call that category controller.
Now remember when you add a controller, you must have the controller keyword at the end.
That is how the code will know that this particular class file is a controller.
Let me hit the add button here and perfect.
It adds a controller inside there.
It has one action method which is index action method.
Now how will this endpoint be triggered?
Let me add a debugging point here and let me run the application.
In the application.
If we want to go to category controller, how will we access that?
For that.
We will write category here.
And next, what is the action method?
The default action method that got added.
It is index, so we can say index here and press enter.
Perfect.
It hits our debugging point here and if we continue we will see an error message.
An unhandled exception occurred while processing the request.
The view index was not found because here you see when the action method is called, it returns back
a view.
Typically when we were working with Homecontroller, we had views in the home folder, but when we are
working with category controller, we added that controller, but we have not added any view.
If you go back, it also displays which were all the locations that were searched.
It will first look for a category folder and try to find index.html.
If it does not find that, it will also look into shared folder, which is a shared location for all
the partial views.
What we have to do is we have to create a folder with the name of category and add the view inside that
folder.
Let me do that.
We will close it here in views.
We will create a folder.
It must match the name of category.
And inside there we will be adding a view.
Now when you are working in the view, if you right click and go to the add button, it automatically
displays that hey, default thing that users typically add is a view.
So that is what it displays at the top there.
Let me select that and we will be adding the empty view.
Now you can select the razor view here or the empty view.
We will go with the empty view name Index.cshtml.
That looks good.
Let me add that we do not care about anything here.
Let me remove that and I will just add an H1 here and I will say category list right here.
With that, let me run the application once again.
Perfect.
Let me navigate to category controller.
We have the index action.
We will press continue and perfect.
It takes us back to the view and it displays the category list that we added.
So great.
We have added our first controller in the application and we have also added the corresponding view.
And on this page we will be displaying all the categories that we have in our database.