We want to display all the categories on category list page that we added.
But every time when we run the application, we do not want to go here and type this in the URL.
Rather, I want to add something like category here.
When we click there, it will take us to this URL.
Now, where do we have this header that you see on the screen?
If you set underscored layout, you are correct.
Let me stop the application.
If we go to the shared folder, we have underscored layout there and there we have UL and LI elements
where we have the LI with the anchor tag.
Now, this anchor tag might seem a little different because in this anchor tag, we have something called
as ASP areas.
You can just delete that for now.
We don't care about them, but we have something called as ASP controller and ASP action.
These are tag helpers and they are useful when you are working with the.
.Net application.
You can think of them as helper function or helper entities that are available to you when we have the
anchor tag rather than having an href here and saying that okay, take me to forward slash home and
then index.
We have the helper tags here where we can say on the anchor tag, take me to the controller, which
is home controller, and in there take me to index action.
And if you look at that, it is more explicit that which controller, what action is being invoked when
we click on this anchor tag.
Let me copy this and paste it one more time.
Next thing that we want to go is category controller and action is index action.
What we want to call here is category and perfect.
That looks good.
These are just the bootstrap classes, so we will ignore them.
But basically we added another element right here.
With that configured, let me run the application and see if that works.
Perfect.
We have category and when we click there, it will hit our debugging point.
Let me remove and continue.
And perfect.
In order to remove, you just have to click that once again and it will remove that debugging point.
So perfect.
Now we can go to category and navigate between pages pretty easily.