Now when we are creating a new category, we want validation.
One validation could be display.
Order cannot be less than one and category name is required.
We can also add some validation that category name must be less than, let's say, 20 characters.
Typically in .net when we had to use validation, we had to use JavaScript and we had to write all
the code.
But with .net core, we have those validations built in and the support for jQuery is already added in
the project.
Let's see how we can use that and add validation.
We will go back to the project here.
And first we will be working with server side validation, which is in the controller.
When we are adding a category, we want some validation.
Inside the category model, we added some data annotation like name is required, but next for display
order, we want a range validation and we have that data annotation as well.
So with range we can provide the minimum value.
It has to be one and for maximum we will add 100.
That means we will have 1 to 100 for the display order.
After that for the name here, we will add the max length data annotation and we can say max length
will be, let's say 30 characters.
With that configured, we have added the validations that are needed in category.
But how will this validations be implemented on the create page?
.net core has built in tag helpers for that.
Where we have the input here.
Let's say if there are some error message with the name, then we want to display that right here.
But even before we display, let me go to the category controller.
Here, we will add an F condition and there is something called as model State.
. is valid.
This basically will check if the model state that we have, which is the category object here, if that
object is valid, that means it will go to category and examine all the validation.
If it is required, then whatever is being populated here in the name must be populated.
If it is not, then the model state is not valid and it will not go to the database and save the category.
Let me run this and see what happens.
We go to category create.
And if we hit create now, it takes us back to the page but does not add a category.
If I have display order here does not work.
Similarly, if I have name here, but if display order is zero, it will not work because we have the
range validation.
If we add a debugging point here, you will also notice the model state value.
Let's hit the create here.
The is valid is false.
If you examine model state here, you will notice in the result view it will display what exactly is
it checking.
Name is valid, but display order is invalid.
If you expand that further, it will display the exact error message as well.
So perfect.
Our validations are working in the project, but right now, if something is not valid, it is redirecting
to the index page and we are not able to see those error message.
For that.
What we will do is stop the application.
If everything is valid, create and return back to the index.
Else we want to return back to the view itself.
With that, let me run the application and this time it will stay on the page here.
But we will not see any validation or any error message.
We already saw in Model State.
We have the exact error message displaying that is super simple and we should be thankful to tag helper
for that.
To display error message inside.
Tag helpers.
We have something called as ASP validation for and it will evaluate everything against the current model.
So ASP validation for this is the validation for name model.
We can give it a bootstrap classes of text danger for the red color.
Copy that.
We will have to add one more span for display order.
So now, if there are any errors with the name, it will be displayed here.
If there are any errors with display order, it will automatically be displayed here.
And that is the power of tag helpers.
Once you save that, we will have to restart the application.
Let's go to category here and create a category.
Perfect.
If we try empty here, it displays the validation.
And if we have the range one.
Perfect.
That looks great.
Now we have server side validation.
But what if we want to change the message that is being displayed here?
Super simple as well.
With data annotation, we go here and with range we have a custom error message field.
And we can provide the custom error message here.
Here we had the end.
We are replacing that with hyphen.
Let me restart and see if that works.
We go to category here create.
And perfect.
We have the custom error message.
So perfect.
With that we have seen tag helpers and server side validation.