Last video we added validation summary all because of that, along with the individual validation that
we have.
It also displays all the validation in the summary right here.
But on top of that, for our custom validation, if we make both the values same and press create,
we see that in the validation summary as well.
That is great.
But now if we go to category controller, I added that custom error under the name or under the key
value of name.
Let me add one more validation here and not restart.
I want to stop the website.
And in the controller copy and paste it one more time.
This time.
If the value of name is equal equal to test.
In that case, I want to display another validation or an error message, but that will not be under
any key name.
It will be empty and I will display test is an invalid value.
And I can convert this to be lower here.
Perfect.
So with that configured, let me run this and try that.
We go to category here and we have the category name, We put that as test display order as zero and
perfect.
It displays both of the validation.
But you can see because we did not validate or because we did not have the name here inside the key,
it did not bind that to the category name, but it displays that validation in the global summary that
we have.
And that is because in ASP validation summary, we have that as all.
Now let's see what is different if I change that to be model only.
So rather than all, if this is model only and if I restart the application, when we say model only,
it will only display the values that have error in model but not any properties.
So let me try test here and zero and it will only display the error.
That test is invalid value.
You can see it does not display property related validations in the validation summary.
So when it says model only, it will not display any error messages related to a property like name
or display order.
The other error that we have is not related to any properties.
Because of that we are able to see test is an invalid value.
And the final option that we have is none here.
And that is self explanatory.
It will not display any error message in the validation summary.
Let me show that.
We have an exception here because that is not set.
I can just add obj.name.
Is not null and perfect.
Let's try that.
We go to category here?
Create and try that and perfect with none.
It does not display any error message.
So perfect.
With that you can see the difference between all model only and none.
Now one real time use case is on the login page.
What you can do is username and password.
Both will be required fields.
So in that case, if they do not input that you can display them right here.
But if the input that and something is not valid, then you can add a custom error message and display
that using model only in the ASP validation summary.
But for now we will go back to the application and let me remove this custom.
I only added because I want it to show the model only difference.
And in the create here we can make this as model only.
Perfect.
Save that.
Or rather, I do not need the validation summary.
For now I can just comment that out.
We have the individual validation and that should be sufficient.
I can comment out the custom validation as well.
With that.
If I restart the application, we still have the basic property validations that are being displayed.
So with that in place, let me continue from the next video.