Now I want you to think on what will be there on the edit page.
Basically, edit page will be exactly same as the create page, but the category name and display order
will be populated based on whatever category the user wants to edit.
On top of that, when we create a category, we do not care about what category it is, but when we
edit a category, we need to know which category the user wants to edit.
Based on that, we will retrieve that category in the Get action method and pass that to our view to
display that.
But first let me design an empty view where on the edit it will basically display the same view that
we have for Create.
We will go back to our code here.
Stop the project.
First, we need to add that action method inside the category controller.
Let me close everything else and we will have both get and post action method.
When we do not define anything here by default, it is a get action method.
So we can copy both get and post action method for create and paste it one more time.
Rename that to be edit here.
And we have the edit post as well.
Now when we are working with edit Like I said before, we need the ID that user wants to edit.
So that we will retrieve in the parameter ID right here.
We can make that nullable here and then we can add a validation that if ID is null or if ID is equal
to zero, that means it is not a valid ID so we can directly return back.
Not found.
What you can also do is you can have an error page and you can return back to that view, which will
be an error view displaying that something is not valid.
But I will keep things super simple right now.
Then if the ID is valid, we need to retrieve that category from database.
Now, when we were retrieving all the categories, we were doing that by using underscore DB dot categories
similar to that, if we have to retrieve one category entity, framework core has helper methods for
that.
Now we have multiple ways of doing that.
So let me spend some time and show you the multiple ways.
It will be a category object and I will call that category from DB is equal to underscore DB.categories.
. we have a method which is find find will basically work on primary key of that model.
We know ID is the primary key of categories, so if I pass the ID here, it will automatically find
that and assign that to category from DB.
We have a warning here that it can be null.
And that's okay, because after we find that, we will check here if category from DB is null.
In that case, we will again return.
Not found.
But if it finds the category, then we will pass that to our view and display that.
So perfect.
That is one way of retrieving the category.
Let me see if that works.
We will worry about the post action later on.
But before that, in order for this to work, we need to pass the ID when we are calling the edit action
method.
If I go to the index action of category where we are invoking edit we are not passing an ID.
How can we pass an ID when we are calling a link here?
Because if we were using something like an href here, we can say we want to go to category forward
slash edit and then we can pass the ID that the user selects here.
But when we have tag helpers, we have something called as ASP route ID.
With ASP route.
We can pass any property right here.
We can pass something called as category ID is equal to and that will be the ID in OBJ.
So we have to use the @ sign obj.id.
You can call this anything you want.
I will call that ID, because if we examine the category controller, I have ID right here.
That way it will automatically map that.
Perfect.
With that configured, let me see that in action.
We go to category here and we will edit the scifi.
We have the id that is two when we press F10 here.
Perfect.
It retrieves that category.
So find is working as expected.
Now, as I said before, there are multiple ways to retrieve a record.
Let me also show you the other ways.
I will copy this.
Paste it about two more times here.
And I'll call this one and two.
For different variable name.
The next method we have something called as first or default.
What that will do is it will use a link operation and we have to say u.id is equal equal to the ID that
is being passed right here.
You can make this a nullable field and the warnings will go away.
There we go.
But first, our default will basically try to find out on whether there is any record.
If not, it will return a null object.
And that will be assigned right here.
First, our default will work even if the ID is not primary.
So if you want to search on name, you can say where name is equal equal to or you can also do . contains.
So you can be fancy with first or default.
But when you are working with find it only works on the primary key.
So you cannot do any modifications in there.
So that is the other route.
And finally, on categories, we have a where condition where similar to first or default, we can use
the link operation and say u.id is equal equal to ID, and once we retrieve that on that, we can add
first our default.
Now, typically I like the first or default approach, unless some situation is there where you have
to do quite a few calculations or filtering and then get first or default only, then I will use the
last approach here.
But if we add a debugging point and if we run the application, we will see all three of them works
exactly the same.
I will do edit for the test here.
It hits our breakpoint and populated db1.
Populated db2.
Populated.
Perfect.
So with that we have seen multiple ways to retrieve one of the category from database.
I will comment out the later two here and that looks good.
Now that we are passing categories to the view, we can work on the view and display all the category
properties.
Let me do that in the next video.