-: We are parsing the category
that we retrieve to our view.
We need to create this view,
so we can right click here, add view, empty view.
We will have to rename this to be added here,
and we will remove everything right here.
Now let me also show you one thing different.
Let me delete this view and let me add that once again.
We also have something called as Razor view.
Let's add that and see what is different.
Now, when we add this, there are quite a few properties
that needs to be scaffolded.
First, we have the view name, which is added.
Now, I have changed the default font of visual studio.
Because of that, it is enlarged and difficult to read,
but here we have the view name of edit,
and with the Razor view,
we can have different template for create, details, edit,
and much more.
We will go with the empty one here,
and if you go with create or something else,
you have more configuration,
which we will see in the upcoming videos.
Now this is not a partial view, so we will skip that,
and you can also skip the underscored layout page
because it already gets added by default.
When you add that, it will scaffold few things
and sometimes I have seen the scaffolding is corrupted
and it does not works and gives you random error message.
Now, because we selected the underscored layout as null,
you can see it rendered like a new HTML page.
That is not what we want.
So, let me delete that again
and let's try that once again.
Add view, Razor view,
Razor view, and we will say use layout page.
When we use the default layout page,
you can see that is more close to what we have
and it got added in the right place.
Now of course, we will remove everything.
We will leave the edit here,
but actually what we can do is copy everything
that we have in create, and paste it for edit
because it will look exactly the same.
Rather than create category, it will be added category.
With that configured, let me change this from create
to update and let me run the project.
We will come back and modify this added page,
but let me see how the application looks right now.
Perfect. To your surprise, when you hit edit category,
it automatically populates the name and display order.
The reason behind that is the category model
that is being parsed from the edit
already has those populated,
and in the edit we are using tag helpers,
so if name has some value,
it will automatically be displayed.
And same applies for display order,
so that is great news.
We have validations that were already added,
so if you try to remove display order,
we have the client side validation.
So with that configured,
our edit category view is looking good right now.
We will have to change one thing,
but I will show you that in the next video.
But what we have to focus on is the post-action method
in category, where we will retrieve an object
and we have to update the category.
We have seen how to create a new category
using entity framework core,
but now how do we update that category?
We will remove this validation, that is not needed.
When we are updating, we will do the client side validation.
That looks good.
On top of that, rather than add, EF Core has a method
for update and there we have to parse the obj
and it will update that category.
Now, how will that update?
Based on the ID that is populated in the object here,
it will automatically update all the other properties
that are there for that category in the database.
It is super simple,
but you can see how entity framework goal
has reduced all the heavy lifting
that we have to do when we were updating a record.
With that, let me continue from the next video.