Finally, we will work on deleting a category.
When we delete a category, we want to display everything that we do in edit, but everything will be
disabled.
So let me copy what we have for edit cat and post action method and paste it one more time.
Here we will rename that to be delete.
Now in the delete post, you can get the complete category object or you can just get the ID that user
wants to delete.
In that case, we cannot use the same name for the action method because then the parameters are also
same for get and post.
So we will have to rename this to be delete post and we have to explicitly tell here that name is delete
for this endpoint.
Because in the form when we are posting it will look for the same delete action method.
In order to do that with HTTP post, we can explicitly say that this endpoints action name is delete,
even though we have a different name right here.
The get action method looks good.
We want to retrieve that category.
But how do we delete that category?
Now when we have to delete, we first have to find that category from database.
So we will say category OBJ is equal to underscore db.categories.find based on the ID and then
if OBJ is null, we will return not found.
If OBJ is not null or an underscore db.
We have categories and there we have remove method which expects the category object so we can pass
the obj that we retrieved from the database and pass that.
Finally, we will have to save the changes and return back to the index action.
And perfect.
That looks good.
With that, we have the get and post action methods for delete.
Let me continue from the next video.