We have the CRUD functionality that is working, but whenever we create, edit or delete a category,
what if we want to display a notification here?
That record was created, updated or deleted successfully.
For that we have something special in .net core, which is temp data.
If you assign a value in temp data, it is only available for the next render.
So basically, let's say on the create button, we say if everything was successful, we can add a message
to temp data, then it will only be available to the next page that is rendered.
When we create, we redirect them to the category list so it will only be available on this render.
If you refresh that page, then temp data goes away.
Temp data has been created in the.
.Net framework with that sole purpose that if you have to display a notification on the next page, then
you add some value in temp data.
Let me show you on how that will work.
Let me switch back to the code here.
Stop the application and we have the index page.
Before we do that in the controller, we will assign something on post.
Once it is successful, before we redirect here, we can add something to temp data and there we have
to give that a key name.
Let me call that as success message.
In there we will add a message category created successfully.
That is the key name that we have given to something in temp data.
And based on that key name, we can access its value.
Let me copy that and do that in edit post before we redirect.
We will say category updated successfully and when we delete before we redirect, we will say category
deleted successfully.
Now we have added the message in our temp data with the key name of success.
But where do we display that?
We will display that on the index page at the very top here.
What I can do is add an if condition and check if temp data with the key name of success.
If that is not null, then we want to display that, let's say in an H2 for now.
To display that we will again use the razor syntax at sign and we can access the success.
Simple as that.
I have an extra s here.
Remove that and let's run that.
We go to category here?
Let me try to create a category.
Test category for.
And perfect.
We have category created successfully.
Now if you refresh here, that goes away.
So temp data only stays there for one request and then it goes away.
If you try to edit this to, let's say 44, we have category updated and if you refresh here, that
goes away.
So with that, we have seen temp data in action and that is a great feature when you have to display
notification.