We have used temp data to display the success notification.
But what if we had more than one page?
Let's say in our website we have category.
We have something called as cover type products and we want to perform CRUD operations on all of them.
Then rather than adding the same logic or same code that we have in one page, we will be reusing that
on multiple pages.
And right now it is success.
You might also have temp data for error and display a corresponding error message.
Rather than adding the same code in all the places, it is best to use partial views.
We have already seen one of the partial view which was validation scripts partial.
But this time we want to move our temp data logic in its own partial view.
How can we do that?
Well, doing that is super simple.
Again, in the solution here where we have the shared folder.
We will right click add a new view.
We will go with the empty view and the name for partial view.
I typically like to write underscore that way.
Looking at that, I can tell that this will be a partial view.
will call this underscore notification . css html.
We go to our index.
Let me cut the if condition.
Paste it right here.
Then let me copy this, paste it once again and we will display error here.
So if temp data of error is not null, then we display that error as well.
We do not have this error right now, but I just added that code.
Now, how do we consume this partial view inside our index?
That is simple.
We have the partial tag here and we need to give that a name.
And for the name, make sure there is no spelling mistake.
Else it will not work.
Perfect.
So that way we have added or consumed the partial view that we just created.
With that in place, let me run the project.
It should work the same.
Let me try to edit here.
And perfect.
We have category updated successfully.
So with that very small example, we have seen how to create a partial view.
And then on any page where we have to consume it, we can do that by adding just one line of code.
On top of that, if we have to change the implementation of notification, we do that directly in the
partial view and all the views that are consuming this partial view will get that update.
If it was not the case, then we will have to update it individually in all the places.
So for all the reusable components in your page, you should be using partial views.
With that basic idea.
Let me continue from the next video.