Now we have the bulky project and there we are able to perform all the CRUD operations on categories.
And right now what we are working on is an MVC project.
But when it comes to .net programming language, there is also another way you can write the same code,
and that is using razor pages rather than using models, views and controllers.
And the approach to razor pages is somewhat similar to what we have been working in older .net days where
we have a back end and a front end page.
So let me spend some time and try to replicate the same project that we have built using MVC, using
razor pages.
That way, within a short time you will have a brief idea of how razor pages actually work.
So in our existing solution here, we can have multiple project.
One project that we have is bulky web.
Let me add a new project here and that will be of the type razor pages.
If you type razor here, you can see we have the ASP.NET Core Web app.
And this is not the one with model view or controller.
It is using the razor pages content.
So we will select that.
Hit the next button project name.
Let me call that bulky web razor, underscore temp and select the next button.
Again, authentication will be none here and everything stays the same.
We will hit the create button and that will add one more project in our solution, which will be bulky
web razor.
Now, if I set this as a startup project, it will run this particular website rather than the other
one.
And let me try to run that.
When you run the project, you will see the default page looks exactly the same like we had for an MVC
project.
But this time you will notice some things are different.
If you notice, the URL here is directly privacy.
Previously it was home, which was the controller and then privacy, which was the action method.
But when we use razor pages, we do not have any controllers.
In the next video, let me first show you what is the differences between both the project type.