Before anything else we want to see.
What are some things that are similar between both the project?
So let me expand the project here.
And perfect.
You will notice in the Razer project we have app settings .JSON.
This is exactly same like we have in the MVC project and all the connection or settings.
We will place them in the app settings.JSON file.
After that the program.cs is also exactly same.
Well, the functionality is same, but the files will be different.
You can see in the MVC one it added controllers with view, but in the razor pages it added builder.services
.razor pages to the container.
That way the application will know that it will be using razor pages as compared to MVC, which is controllers
and views.
If you scroll down the default route.
Also, we had controller and action in an MVC application.
But when it comes to razor pages, the routing is straightforward and we have map razor pages.
Now the way routing works in a razor page application is whatever is inside the pages folder that will
be the route.
So if in pages folder there is an index page, you directly type index and that will be the default
page.
If you type privacy, we have the privacy page right here.
So basically whatever the folder structure is there in the pages folder, that will be the exact routing
that we will follow in the URL.
And we will, of course, see that pretty shortly in the upcoming video.
But we will come back to the pages folder in a second.
Other than Appsettings and Program.cs, we have www Root, which is also exactly same as the MVC application.
And then the property stays the same, dependencies stays the same.
The only thing that is majorly different is we do not have controllers, models or views.
We only have one thing, which are pages.
And these pages are different than what we had for controllers or views.
Here we have the index page, which is index.csHTML.
If you double click that, it still has that razor syntax where you can use the at sign and use C#
code.
But on top of that there is something called as @page directive.
This add page directive is used for the razor pages.
And if you expand the arrow here we have the .CS file.
This .CS file is not the code behind file that we had in traditional .net application.
It is a complete rewrite and it is basically a page model for the razor page that we have.
You can see it extends from the page model, which is inside the .net core package.
Page model will have all the get and post endpoints that we typically had in the controller that we
saw in the first project.
So you can see on Cat is the default handler for cat action method.
The naming here must match.
So basically on is required and then if it is a get, it will be get.
If it is post, we will have the on post handler.
Now I will not go crazy deep into razor pages because it has its own course and it can be lengthy.
But I will give you a brief idea on how to perform CRUD operation in razor pages.
That way you are comfortable with razor pages.
Now inside pages, you will see something common in shared.
We have the underscore layout and validation scripts partial exactly the same as MVC.
We have view, imports and view start exactly the same and we have an error page to display error message.
But before we do anything else here, like working on the razor pages or anything, I want to configure
entity framework Core in this project.
Configuring that will be exactly the same.
So for that, what I will do is right click here, add a new folder which will be for models, and I
will actually copy the model that we have for category.
Let me copy this.
Close that in the models, add a new class.
Do not copy the class and paste it here because then the namespace will be copied over.
Rather we will paste that here and perfect.
So with that we have added the category model in the Razor project.
What your assignment is to configure entity framework core in this project.
It will require the exact packages that we did in MVC project and you will have to create an application
DB context class that you will do inside the data folder.
So configure all the steps.
Configure program.cs.
Make sure to seed the category as well.
The last thing that I will do before I end this video is in app settings.
Let me copy this connection string from MVC.
Paste it right here and I will change the database name from bulky to bulky_razor.
Perfect.
So you have the connection string in the Razer project you need to configure entity framework core.
Create the database seat the category table with three categories, just like we did with the MVC project.
That will give you a hands on practice on setting up entity framework core in a project.
So complete all the steps, but do not update the database or add the migration.
Do everything for the configuration.
And when you are at the step of adding a migration, follow along with me in the next video.
That way I want to show you one thing that you have to be careful about.
So good luck with that assignment and I will show you how to do that in the next video.