Instructor: We are able to display all the categories.
If I run the application again
and if I go to Categories there,
if I click the Create New Category,
you can see it is not able to route to that page.
If it was an MVC application
you will see an error message, Page not found.
But in Razor pages, if it does not found
I have noticed it does not even redirect.
So next we have to create these categories
and the create page.
We will open the solution explorer inside categories.
I will add a new Razor page
which will be empty and we will call that as create.
Perfect.
We have the corresponding page model.
Now the UI will be exactly same
so we can go to views, category create, copy, close that
and also minimize this, paste it right here, go to the top.
We do not have a model for category
but we will have to create that in page model.
So when we go to create cshtml.css in the Razor project here
we will have to create that.
On top of that we need application DB context.
So let me copy these lines, paste it here.
We will have to change the constructor name to create model.
Let me add the using statement here.
And we do not have list of category.
When we are creating, we will be working with one category
add the using statement and perfect.
If we go to the Razor page here, we do not have name
but we have category.name.
We will have to replace that in all the places.
So let me do that
and perfect.
We do not have controller.
We have asp-page,
that will be categories/index
and that looks good.
Let me run the application and see if that works.
We go to category here, create, and it is not working
in index.
We need a forward slash here
and perfect, that works.
It loads the empty category.
When we hit create, we have the validation as well because
in create here we have validation script partial
and that is also present by default in Razor pages.
So you can see everything is the same.
When we hit back to list, that doesn't work
we need a forward slash there.
And let me modify in index right here.
This will be categories.
Yep, that looks good.
Perfect, so we can go back now.
Edit and delete.
We have not added those pages, so that will not work.
But create new category is working.
If you type something and hit create, nothing happens.
Because what we have right now
in the page model is only the get handler
and that is not even doing anything
because when we create a category
we want to load the empty page and display the text box.
So that is okay, but how do we add a post endpoint here?
So when we hit the submit button
we want to create that category.
Let me show you that in the next video.