Instructor: Now we need to add a post endpoint here
and how will we do that?
Well, adding that is super simple.
We will say public, return type will not be void here
because when we create a category
we want to redirect to fund razor page,
like let's say the index page for category.
So return type will be the same I action result
that we saw in MBC application.
Then what will be the name?
On will be required.
But if we have to post something,
then we have to write post keyword
and that is how we create post handlers in razor pages.
Now when we post, we will get the category object here.
So we will get that and let me call that OBJ here.
Next what we want to do is on DB.categories
we want to add the object and_DB.save changes.
After that, we want to redirect, so return.
Previously we have redirect to action,
but in razor pages we have redirect to page
and we have to give it a name.
We will call that the index page
because we are in the same folder that will work.
With that configured, if we restart the application,
things will not exactly work like we intend.
Let me add a debugging point on the post here
and let me wait for the application to come up again
and let me go to category, create a new category,
populate something there.
Hit the create button.
You will notice the OBJ here is null.
Why is that?
In category we have the post here
it should populate at listcategory.name.
That category is right here,
but if you examine, that is also not populated.
When we are working with razor pages
if we want this property to be available
when we are posting that,
we have to add an attribute here, which is bind property.
That will make sure that it binds this property
and when we post that, it'll automatically be bind it
and available in the post handler.
Once we do that, we no longer require anything
in the parameter.
Here we can directly access the category
because that will be populated.
Now let me run this and show that as well.
We go to category here, create, type something here,
and we examine the category.
Perfect.
We have display order as well as name
and we continue here.
Great.
That category has been added successfully.
So when we work with razor pages
we have to explicitly bind properties that we want to access
on the post of the form.
If you have more than one property,
you can bind them individually or what you can do is
at the page model level here, we have something called
as bind properties
and it'll bind all the properties that you define
in the page model.
With that, if you run the application,
it'll work the same way.
Let me try that as well.
We will have test two and we examine category.
Perfect, that is populated.
So those are the two ways to bind properties
when we are working with razor pages.
Now with that brief overview
you know how to create the get handlers and post handlers.
With that knowledge that you have,
I want you to work on edit and delete functionalities
as an assignment.
So good luck with that assignment
and I will see you guys in the next video.