Instructor: We want to work on
edit and delete functionality.
So let me create those Razor pages in categories.
Add a Razor page, empty and I will call that edit here.
Next one that I want to create, whoops, right here.
Add a Razor page and that will be delete.cshtml.
First, let me pin this here and where we have the create.
Let me copy everything
and we will paste it in edit right here.
We will also have to bind the properties
because we will be posting some data.
I will change the constructor name to be edit model
and add the using statement for category as well.
Perfect.
Now, when we are editing
we have to retrieve the category that a user wants to edit.
And right here we will get the ID.
Based on the ID that we receive here,
we can check if ID is not known and if ID is not zero.
In that case we can populate the categories here
and let me make this nullable.
That's okay.
So we will load the category else.
We do not want to do anything,
so we'll load category on the get handler
and on the post here we have to update.
If I go to the web project here, category controller,
on the post we were checking model state.
We can do everything exactly the same
while we are in create.
Let me copy the one that we have for edit here
and paste it right here.
So if model state is valid,
we want to update, we have bind property
so we will have that category here and perfect.
That looks good.
Let me comment out the temp data for now.
We will redirect to the page and perfect.
That looks good.
In the else part here, we can just return back to the page
if the model state is not valid.
So our edit logic is looking good.
Let me work on the edit UI.
So let me copy what we have for view.
Close this and the controller, minimize the web project,
go to edit here and paste that.
Remove the model here
and everything will be inside category.Id.
Let me modify all of them.
Now we have all the warnings here.
I can fix that real quick.
But we need the page here.
ASP page will be categories and then index.
Perfect.
That looks good.
If we go to edit page model, I can remove this
and then we will have only one warning,
if that is not found, but that's okay.
We can fix that, but it is a warning
and we know ID will be correct.
If not, we can show a not found.
But with that configured, let me run this
and see if edit is functional.
We will try to edit test with test 33
and great, that is working.
We should also have validation here.
That looks good.
I think in the UI I have a mistake here.
I will have to stop and restart.
Category edit.
Perfect.
Let me see if I have that same mistake in the MVC project.
We do not have that here, so that's okay.
But everything is working.
We have too many files open.
Close all of them and let me work on delete.
Copy the view from the MVC project here.
Where we have the Razor project open, delete.
Paste it right there.
Before we work on anything else here,
let me stop this and I will work on page model.
I can copy what I have for the edit model.
If you do copy and paste,
make sure to change the class name to be delete model.
It must exactly match or else things will not work,
because the binding will not work.
Here it is looking for that delete model.
So we have that at the using statement
and the constructor name, delete model.
When we are deleting, we will have to find that,
but on the post here
we first have to retrieve that category and then delete.
So let me copy that from the controller
rather than typing it all over right here.
Copy that and I will paste it right here.
Perfect.
That looks good.
Let me validate the ID.
We will get that from Category.Id here.
If that is null we return not found,
else we remove and save the changes.
Perfect.
We have redirect to page.
That also looks good.
Let me save that.
And now we will fix the delete UI.
Let me minimize the web project.
Perfect.
Everything will be inside Category.Id.
So Category., I will append that.
And we need the ASP page here,
which will be categories/index.
Great.
With that, let me see if everything is functional.
Category.
Let me try edit again.
3, 3, 3.
Let me try delete here.
That works.
So our category functionalities are working.
Now for the next assignment,
I want you guys to complete the toaster notification
and implement the partial view.
So good luck with that
and we will complete that in the next video.