Instructor: Finally we have to add toaster
in our project.
That will be straightforward
to what we did with M B C as well.
So we go here, we have the partial view,
copy that
and we will create the same partial view
inside
razor project, shared
add razor page
and we will call that underscore notification.
Right here you see it added the page and model
but that is not needed with partial view.
We can delete the dot CS file
and remove all the code, paste what we copied
from the M V C project.
We need to add this to our underscore layout.
So let me do that before render party here.
That looks good.
In underscore layout, we also need to add toaster U R L.
So let me copy that from here.
We will close the M V C project and add that here.
Perfect.
So toaster is added.
Now we need to configure
or rather set temp data on the post handlers.
For that, let me make sure
we are in the razor project in the create.
Before we redirect, we will set temp data
of success category created successfully
delete category
deleted successfully.
Edit will be category updated successfully
and that looks good.
Let me run and see if that works.
Go to category here,
try to edit history and Perfect.
We see the notification.
Let me update that back here.
And if we delete test two,
perfect.
All the toaster notification
and everything is working as expected.
Now with this, we have quickly learned crud operations
on both M V C and razor pages.
The reason I introduced you razor pages is
moving forward when we add identity,
using the dot net identity class library
that is built on top of razor pages.
So when you have to edit the page, you know
that razor page will have a page model where you will have
get and post handler.
With the practice that you have in this section
with razor pages, you should be able to update everything
with the identity pages that we will cover
in the later sections of the course.