Instructor: Now what I want to do is
in content management I want to create a section
for user management.
In there I want to display all the users in data table.
Let me do that first.
I will close the application here,
we have application user that is okay
but we need to create user controller.
I will add that in the admin section, controller, copy,
and paste the company controller because that has data table
and let me call this user controller.
We will copy that name
and I will paste that in the class and constructor.
That looks good.
Now in the index here,
we do not want anything we can directly return back
to the view because we will be using data table.
Let me remove the absurd here that is not needed as well.
We have API calls, we want to retrieve list
of application user, let me do that here
and that will be unit of work dot application user.
But now when we are working
on user controller rather than using unit of work,
let me directly use application DB context
because I want to show that route as well.
So if we want a combination
of that for some reason, that is also possible.
Now I would not recommend this
but you can add that right here.
At the end of this section,
I will also explain on
why exactly I used application DB context initially
for this controller.
We directly have the application DB context.
We can use that to retrieve all the user.
On underscore DB we have application user
and there when we have
to get everything we will be using the where syntax
but if we want to get all of the user ID,
then we do not need any where syntax.
Right here, we want to include the company.
So let me do that.
U dot company, convert that to a list.
Then we will return that list here and let me
call that OBJ user list, that sounds good.
If we think about that, all of our user
will not be company user.
So if a user is not company user, we have
to manually do something else we will see an exception.
Let me correct that.
Once we see that exception,
then we do not have any delete features here.
Let me remove that and we will come back to this.
So get all is looking good.
We have the index.
Next I have to add the index view, raise our view.
Let me add that here and perfect it got added.
Let me double check.
I have the area of admin, that looks good.
For the view here,
let me open the view that we have for product index.
Copy that and paste it here.
We do not have any model.
We can remove that and we'll display user list here.
I do not want to create anything.
We can remove that.
Perfect.
Now here we want to display all the user properties.
So let me add name, email, phone number, company, and role.
Do not worry about company and role right now.
Do not worry about role of the user right now.
We will cover that in the upcoming video.
We need to add the JavaScript file,
change this to be user dot js, that looks good.
Finally, we have to add the Javascript.
Let me copy the company, paste that again,
rename that to be user dot js.
Then we need to modify the JavaScript right here.
Name that is valid, what is the next one?
We have email and phone.
Email, phone will be phone number.
We have that at the end.
Let me type that here.
Then we have company and role.
Company is inside company dot name, but role,
I do not know where that is
so let me keep that empty for now.
With that configured here, let me remove the delete.
I do not need that and perfect, looks good.
Let me go to solution, views, shared, underscore layout,
and I will copy the create user, paste it one more time.
Well, let me copy the area much easier.
Admin, user controller, index action,
and I will call that manage user.
Let me run the application and see if that works.
Let me go to content management.
We have manage user
and we can see the error message with email.
Let me see why that is the case.
If you see here, we forgot to change this.
It'll not be company, it'll be user and get all.
Let me refresh here and perfect.
Now if you see here, we are only looking at one user.
If I go to database
and examine the ASP.NET users, we have three users.
Why do I only see one user here?
Try to pause the video and analyze on what is going on here.
I will walk you through the solution in the next video.