Instructor: I hope you are able to figure out
what is going on.
Let me switch back here
and add a debugging point in the user controller,
right here.
Now if I go back and refresh here
it will hit my break point.
If I press F10,
you can see it only retrieves one record
and it has to do something with the in blue statement
because it is trying to include company.
But if it does not find, it is excluding that user as well.
Solution to that is, let me stop the application.
If it go to application user here,
company is required.
So make that allowable field
and then it will not care if that company is present or not.
If it is not present, it'll still retrieve the user detail.
With that configured, let me log in here
and let me go to Manage User.
We hit our break point press F10,
and now it retrieves 10 records.
The database that I was examining,
that was of a different account.
That is why I had three records.
That was my bad.
Let me open this
and ASPNet users,
perfect.
We have all the records there.
And if we continue here it will load the page
but we will see a warning with company dot name.
Now even though it loads the page completely okay,
we see the issue with company dot name.
Why is that?
Well, the reason behind that
is when it is joining
if it does not find that company will be known.
And in here we are trying to access company dot name.
So what we have to do is before we return back here,
we have to iterate through all of the user,
variable user, end user list here
and we will have to check if user dot company is null.
Then basically we have to say user dot company
is equal to new.
And name?
We will just add that as empty string and that should work.
With that configured, if I save this and go back
and let me remove the debugging point,
continue here and perfect.
This time the other message that we are looking at
is in column four
because what was happening before is
if I remove this if condition that we added,
and if I save that,
the column if you notice here was column three,
which is company dot name.
So now when we add that,
the next issue is with role
because it does not find any value for that role.
So in the next video,
our task is to find out
the role of each of the customer here and display that.
Let me do that in the next video.