Instructor: Now we have a bit of a challenge.
How will we display role of the locked-in user?
If we go to the database here,
we know that roles are inside AspNetRoles table,
but the table that joins the roles
and the user table is the AspNetUserRoles table,
where we have the mapping.
So basically, we have to combine all three of those tables.
When we have to access any of the built-in identity tables,
we can access them from DB context
by removing the 'AspNet' before the table name.
So if we want to access an AspNetUserRole,
it'll be UserRole.
If we want to access ASPNetRoles, it'll be RolesTable.
So what we can do is,
for each user inside the user list here,
we can find out the role ID of that user.
We can do that with the help of,
I will say the variable 'roleID' is equal to.
Now what we can do here is go to _db
and navigate to the user role table.
But that means in the for each loop,
it will go to the database every time.
So rather than that, what makes sense here
is we can say the variable 'userRoles'
is equal to _db.UserRoles.ToList.
That way, we will have the mapping table.
Then let me also get the roles table _db.Roles.ToList
with both the tables here.
Inside the user, we have user ID.
Based on that, user ID,
we can find the role ID from the UserRolesTable.
So right here we will say UserRoles.FirstOrDefault
and we want to find 'u => u.UserID == userID'.
And from that record, we only care about the role ID.
Once we know the role ID from the UserRolesTable,
where is that?
Let me open that.
From here, we will know the role ID.
Based on that,
we can find the role name from the roles table.
So next, what we can do is we can have 'role' here
from 'Roles.FirstOrDefault' u => u.ID == roleID'.
Now this role that we find for the user,
we have to pass that back in the data.
But in the application user,
we have nothing to store that role.
So we can add a column here,
but we do not want to add that to the database.
So I will be Using '[NotMapped]'
and I will add a string property of 'Role'.
That will make sure
that this is not pushed to the database.
Let me continue editing here and close this.
Where we are storing the role here,
we can store that inside user.Role is equal to and perfect.
That way, 'user.Role' will be populated,
and from 'RoleTable', we want to retrieve the 'Name' column
and assign it right here.
With that configured, user will now have the role.
If we go to 'User.js', name of that column will be 'Role'
and that should work.
Let me rebuild and apply the changes
to make sure we are not missing anything out.
To make sure that we are not missing anything out here,
and let me see how that looks.
I will have to log in again and let me go to 'Manage User'.
We might have an exception.
Let me see.
Yes, we do.
Let me see the ID.
That is valid.
Well, I believe this ID does not even have a mapping
in the role table.
It might be one of the faulty users.
So we will have to clean our table.
Let me see.
'AspNetUsers' Where ID is equal to,
and that is application user.
If we go to 'AspNetUserRoles' where ID is equal to that,
well, it's user ID.
We don't have any record.
So what we can do is I can just delete that record.
It is a record that we don't care about, and perfect.
That should work.
Typically, when we are testing,
there will be many fake things in the database,
so it makes sense to clean up our database
when we are ready to publish things.
Now, if I go to content management here,
Manage User, and perfect.
I can see all the roles here,
and everything is looking great.
With that, let me continue in the next video.