Instructor: Next thing. What I want to add here is
based on the user id, we want to lock any account and
unlock any account in dotnet core.
Now, doing that is super simple.
In the ASP Net user table,
we have a column for that which is lockout end right here.
If the value in this column is populated for any user,
and if that date is in a future date
their account will be locked till that date.
So that is the simple logic.
If we want to lock any account,
we have to set the lockout end to be the future date.
Until that date, the account will be locked.
So let me switch back and let me work on that right here
in the controller.
I will rename this to be locked
unlock here and I will make that an HTTP Post.
We will get the ID here, but that will be user id
which will be string, and we will get that from body.
Based on that id,
we want to retrieve the user record from the database
and we will return JSON back if that object is empty.
Now, when we get the record, we will be using
same method to lock a user and unlock a user.
So if the date is not empty and if the date is future
that means that user is currently locked,
we have to unlock them.
So if OBJ from DB
lockout end is not null,
and OBJ from db
dot lockout end is greater than today's date.
So it's greater than datetime dot now.
That means that user is currently locked
and we need to unlock them.
So here we will say OBJ from db dot lockout end
is equal to datetime dot now.
What that will do is from this point onwards
the user will be unlocked.
That looks good, but if the user is already unlocked,
we want to lock them.
So lockout end is equal to datetime.now
and we want to add years.
Let's add a thousand years.
So that user will be locked
out for the next thousand years.
We have to save the changes.
Right now we are not using unit of work.
We are directly working
with entity framework core with underscore db.
So when we have to make a change,
we can directly retrieve that record
update something in that record and save the changes.
This will work right now
because the record that is retrieved is being tracked
by entity framework core.
So the post method looks good here.
We need to consume that from the user dot js.
Let me do that in the next video.