Instructor: Now we need to display a button
in the data table here
based on if a user is locked or unlocked.
So we have to do some calculations right here.
And when we are working with the data along with the ID,
we also need the value of the lockout end.
Because based on that we can tell whether a user is locked
or unlocked.
So in data, if we want to retrieve more than one values
we can do that by separating them.
So ID will be inside ID.
We want another variable which is lockoutEnd,
and that will be from lockoutEnd.
So perfect, I believe that looks good here.
Great.
So data is now an object and it has two values.
When we are in the render function here,
we want to get today's date.
To do that we will say variable today
is equal to new Date.getTime.
Then the lockout end date that we have,
we will have to convert that in getTime.
That will basically convert that to an integer value.
And based on those two integer values, we can compare.
So we can say if lockout is greater than today,
that means that user is currently locked out
and we need to display them a button
to unlock their account.
So let me copy the return statement for HTML here,
paste it right here, and we have to make this more dynamic
and change few things inside there.
First thing, rather than div here, let me make another div,
give it a class of text-center.
Inside there I will add an anchor tag
to unlock any of the account.
I have added a bootstrap icon here and that looks good.
Next, let me add one more anchor tag here,
which we will use in the later videos to update permission.
So that looks good for locked.
Let me copy this and paste it again in the else part here.
And that will be, if a user is unlocked
then we want to a display to lock them.
Lock button, we can display them in danger like that.
Let me rebuild and apply the changes and see if that works.
By default, everything should be unlocked
so we should see the lock button.
If we go to manage user, perfect,
everything is unlocked and we see the lock button.
But I think it should be other way around.
If a user is unlocked,
we should see the current status of unlocked here.
So let me cut this from here,
paste it here, and flip that other way around.
Save that, and perfect.
Right now user is unlocked.
You can click here to lock the user and that looks good.
Then for the permission here
let me make that 150 pixels.
And perfect, that looks good.
So now that we have unlock here, we want to work on
when we hit the button here, it should lock the user.
For that we have to call the same endpoint in both of them.
We will add an onclick here.
And let me call that method as LockUnlock.
There we have to pass the ID.
That will be a string.
I will pass that in a single quote,
and that will be data.id,
because now in data we have two properties.
Let me create this function at the end here.
But before that, let me copy this onclick,
paste it for the other one as well.
Then we will scroll down.
Right here I will create that function of LockUnlock.
And inside there we will have an Ajax request
where we have to POST an admin user controller.
We have LockUnlock, that looks good.
Along with that, our data is inside ID,
but we have to stringify that.
So we will say json.stringify.
And the contentType is application.json.
Now, when it is successful, we want to add a function.
And we will get the data back in JSON.
We want to display this message in a toastr notification
and reload the data table.
On data, if we notice it is passing success,
so we can say if data.success is true
we want to display toastr notification
and we want to reload the data table.
With that configured let me restart the application.
Let me go back and add a debugging point right here.
And let me see if that works.
We press unlock here, it hits the break point.
We hit continue and nothing happens.
Well, if you refresh the page here, you can see the user
is locked indeed.
So basically data table is not getting refreshed here.
Let me see if we have that in a variable, data table.
We indeed have that, but for some reason,
let me press unlock here, open the console window.
Whoops, toastr is not defined.
I thought I added that in the main layout
but let me examine that.
Notification.
I can copy both of this in the main layout
and let me see if that works.
Perfect.
With that, everything is working as expected.
But we are displaying delete successful.
Something is not right.
This will not be delete successful.
Let me say operation successful.
We unlock here, that worked.
We lock the account, we unlock that.
Perfect.
Let me see if the lock actually works.
We locked customer at Gmail here.
Let me examine here.
Where is customer at Gmail?
Right here.
Perfect, you can see the lockout end date is 3023,
so 1000 years from now.
If I log out here and try to log in with customer,
I should see the error message,
locked out, please try again.
So great, our functionalities of lock and unlock
are working as expected.