Instructor: Now I want to show you your final assignment.
I want you to work on the permission field.
When a user clicks here, it opens a new page,
which is inside the user controller
and action method with the name of role management.
There, it will expect a user ID.
Based on that, it will populate name of the user here
and we will display the current role.
If a user is company user,
they will see the company name that is attached here.
I have some dummy company names as you can see.
But basically, if you want to validate that,
you can go to company,
and you can see I created some dummy names here.
So in user, if we go to individual user,
we see that role here
and we can change that to be a company account.
If we change that to be company,
we need to select a company and hit the Update button.
You can see that it got updated.
In the permission, if we change that to individual,
the company goes away, and that is reflected.
Now, when a company is being updated,
it should be updated in database as well.
So think about what will be the view model for this page.
To give you a hint, we need application user
and then we have two dropdowns.
We have a dropdown for role
and we have a dropdown for our company.
Along with that, we need something to store
what is the current role of the user,
so that will be the view model,
build that view model, and then build this page.
I want you to complete that assignment
and then see the solution in the next video.