Instructor: I hope you were able
to complete the assignment.
If not, let's do that together.
I will switch back to the application, stop that,
and we will be adding a view model for the permission page.
I will call that role management view model.
It will be a public class.
And as I said before,
we need four properties in this model.
Now, rather than adding a current role here
in application user,
we already have a role,
so we can use that.
So we should be good with these three properties.
With that configured in the user controller,
I need to add an action method.
That action method will receive userId in the parameter,
so from user on click here,
we should invoke the action method,
which is role management with the userId.
So right here,
let me add the href for that
and pass the userId.
I will do that in both the places.
Perfect, that looks good.
After that, we will go back to the user controller here,
and based on the userId,
I want to retrieve the roleId,
so that I can do from the user roles table.
When we are in there,
we have to populate the role management view model,
and inside there we need ApplicationUser.
We will get that from ApplicationUsers.Include.
We want to include the company,
and we will do first our default based on the userId.
Then next we have to populate the dropdowns
for role list and company list.
We have done that in the past using projection,
so that is exactly what we will do.
After all of that,
inside the role view model,
we have ApplicationUser,
and there we have role of the user
that we will populate using _db.Roles
based on the roleId that we retrieved here,
and we want to extract name from there.
With that configured,
when we return back to the view,
we have to pass the role view model.
That looks great.
Let me create this view.
It will not be an index.
What is the name?
Role management.
For the view here to be consistent,
let me copy that from category create,
and I will paste that right here.
First thing, we need the model here,
but it is not detecting that.
Let me open that once again,
and for some reason it is not detecting that.
Let me copy and paste role management view model.
Let me save this and open that again.
Now, when things don't work in the IntelliSense,
it is time to restart Visual Studio.
I will open the project again and I hope that works.
Great, now it is being detected.
First thing first,
we will change that to be Manage User Role,
and we want to display the name here,
so ApplicationUser.Name.
We will display that.
It will be a read-only.
When we will be posting,
make sure you have the userId in the hidden property.
That way we can retrieve that userId.
Finally, we need a select dropdown here,
so select asp-for.
That will be ApplicationUser.Role.
We will save it there
and the dropdown will be Models.RoleList.
We will give that a class of form-select,
and that should be good.
We need another dropdown for company.
Asp-for will be CompanyId
and items will be CompanyList.
Now we need to toggle this dropdown dynamically,
but let me worry about that later on.
Let me call this Update Role here
and back to list.
Remove the controller.
Perfect.
With that, let me run the application and see if that works.
We go to log in here as an admin.
Content management.
We have managed user.
Test employee, perfect.
We see the company dropdown here,
but that should be only visible
if the dropdown here is company.
So what I can do is right here I can add a eraser code
and we can set a variable companyVisible display:none,
and if the role is company,
only then we will set display block in the asp-for here.
Let me add that dynamic style using companyVisible.
With that, if I save this,
now if a employee opens that up,
it does not display.
If a company opens it, we see the company dropdown.
But finally, we need to toggle that based on the ID,
because right now if we go to permission
and if a company is selected,
that dropdown should be visible.
We have that logic in the register, I believe.
Let me open that.
And whoops, it's in the CSHTML right here.
Copy that.
Go back to the role management.
And we will paste it right here.
We need to get the IDs, so let me do that.
F12.
The role is ApplicationUser_Role.
Let me modify that.
And where we have the company,
that one is ApplicationUser_CompanyId.
Perfect.
Let's go back here and if it is company, it is visible.
If anything else, that goes away.
Perfect, so the view is looking great.
In the next video, let's work on the update button.