Instructor: The final thing that we want to work on
is when we hit the Update Role
it should update the role.
So let me switch back here and copy the RoleManagement.
Paste that one more time here,
remove everything, and this will be HttpPost.
What we will be getting here
will be the RoleManagementVM model
because we did not bind that property.
In order to get the RoleId
we will have to go to roleManagementVM model
.ApplicationUser.Id, and then the RoleID.
Now this RoleID is the current role.
So let me retrieve the oldRole from the database,
that way we know what is the old role.
We will check here if not, and if the current role
which is inside roleManagementVM model
.ApplicationUser.Role is not equal to oldRole,
that means a role was updated.
Now, when we have to update anything,
let me retrieve the application user from the database,
and then I will check one thing.
If roleManagement.ApplicationUser.Role
== SD.Role_Company,
that means along with assigning the role,
we also have to assign company to that application user.
So we can set applicationUser.CompanyId
= roleManagementVM model
.ApplicationUser.CompanyId.
Then if the oldRole was a company role,
then we have to remove that CompanyId.
So ApplicationUser.CompanyId will be null.
So that is everything that we have to update
with applicationUser, so let me save the changes.
Now finally, we have to remove the old role
and assign the new role to our user.
For that we have helper method inside UserManager.
Let me retrieve that using dependency injection.
Perfect, now if we go down,
we need to remove the oldRole.
So _userManager.RemoveRoleAsync,
and we have to pass the user object,
which is applicationUser, and the oldRole,
we have to provide that, which is in oldRole.
It is an Async method,
so we will call GetAwaiter.GetResult.
Copy that, paste it one more time.
Once we remove the oldRole, we have to AddToRoleAsync
and we have to add the new role
that is inside VM model .ApplicationUser.Role.
Finally, let me Redirect to the "Index" action, and perfect.
With that, let me go back,
and we will have to restart the application
to test everything that we have.
Perfect, let me log in as an admin here.
And we go to Manage User,
we have a company account.
Let me go back in the database,
and if I examine that email is company@gmail, where is that?
Right here, it should have a CompanyId.
If I change that role to be Employee, Update Role,
perfect, that is done.
And if I execute the CompanyId should be gone, perfect.
If I edit that again to be a company,
change that, let me execute here,
and perfect, the CompanyId is getting assigned
and the role is also back to Company.
So with that, you can see how easy it is
to manage roles dynamically from the portal in .NET Core.