Instructor: Now the Razor project
that we implemented was only
for learning purpose.
We do not want that
in our main project for Bulky,
so let me remove that project here.
and perfect.
It is no longer there,
and in the Bulky, let me create more project.
Typically, when we are working
with a real-world project
we do not like to cluster everything together.
Like right now,
you can see we have the data here.
We have all the models here.
If we have any constants, we will add them here.
But in a real-world application,
it is best to keep everything
separate in its own project.
So we will be creating
class projects in solution.
Select a new project,
and we will search for a class library.
First one that we want to create
will be Bulky.DataAccess.
This project will have everything
related to database.
Like we have the DB context,
we will move that in the data access
along with the migrations.
So let me select that with the .NET framework.
Perfect.
Next one, let me create
the same class library here,
and that one will be Bulky.
Let me make sure the name.
Yep.
It will be Bulky.
And then we will move all the models
in its own project.
Select that and create.
Finally, I want to add one more project,
which will be Bulky.Utility.
For all the utilities that we will add
in our project,
like email functionality
or maybe constants for our application,
we will have all of them in the utility project.
Let me create that project as well,
and I will remove all the class files.
We will be creating new class files
when needed but perfect.
Now back to the MVC project.
We have the Bulky Web.
Bulky Utility.
Bulky Models.
And Bulky Data Access.
In the next video,
let me remove all the logic that is bundled
in the Bulky Web
to the individual class libraries.