-: Before we work on anything else
I want to modify the basic designs that we have
on the Bootstrap theme that is being used in the course.
We are using Bootswatch for our project
and if we take a look at the themes,
there are multiple themes that are available.
What I want to do is switch from the luxe theme
to the sandstone here, and doing that is super simple.
We can download the Bootstrap file here
and let me open that.
We will copy everything here.
Let's go back to our project here and www root CSS.
Well, we updated that directly in the CSS here.
We have the luxe theme.
Let me remove that
and paste the new theme right here, which is sandstone.
With that, if I run the application
you will see the new theme in action
but on top of that I want to change the button
colors that we have by default.
Now rather than typing all of that HTML and CSS
what I have done is I have provided all the snippets
and you can download them from .NET match suite.com.
There if you go to course detail,
you can get all the snippets
so make sure to download all of them.
And in the attachments we are in section four.
We have site dot CSS inside there.
If you open that, there is quite a few CSS right here.
But mainly what I'm doing is changing the BTN outline
the BG success and main Bootstrap classes that we are using
like BTN primary and BTN Success.
So copy all of that here.
We will go to our solution.
We have a site dot CSS inside our CSS folder.
Delete everything that is there and paste all the classes.
Now I am not introducing custom classes.
I am basically overriding the classes that are there
in Bootstrap so that way we will not be using new classes.
We will be using the old classes,
and it is like a Bootswatch theme and perfect.
With that you can see new design is
in effect, and we have a nice color palette right here.
I like this color palette more than what we had before.
And I also want to change some designing
with the create category and all the other pages.
Let me do that real quick.
So we'll go to create category
we'll go to views category create right here.
Let me start fresh.
We'll add a div, give it a class of card and shadow.
Along with that we'll say border zero
and margin top of four.
Inside the main card here we will add another div
which will be for card header
and let me add the closing div.
Perfect, that looks good.
Then we will add the header here.
Inside the class of row,
we will set div, class column 12, text center.
And in the H 2 we have create category.
Let me cut that, paste it here
and give it the class of text white and padding Y of two.
After that, when the card header here
we will add another div for the card body.
So Bootstrap classes, card body here and padding four.
Perfect. Let me cut the form
and paste it right here.
Inside the form, let me give it a Bootstrap class
of row and see how the UI looks right now.
I do not see the site dot CSS coming into picture.
So let me see underscored layout.
We have site dot CSS after the Bootstraps,
so that should work.
But let me move it
at the very end here and let me restart the project.
Let's go to category and create new category.
Perfect. This looks much better.
Exactly what I want.
Let me go back again
and I do not want the HR here, remove the first row as well.
And I do not need the margin top four as well.
Where we have the class margin bottom three and row,
we already are inside row in form.
So what I can do is add a class
of form, floating, padding Y 2, and column 12.
Where we have the input element,
I will modify the class from padding zero to form control
border zero and shadow, and where we have the input element
I will say MS two, that looks good.
Let me copy the classes
and apply them for display order as well.
Again, all of them are Bootstrap classes nothing fancy.
Rather than BTN secondary, let me do BTN outline primary.
Let me save that, and let's see the difference now.
The hard reload for some reason is not working.
You can see it is not checked again for some reason.
So let me restart.
Perfect. It is checked now, category
and let me go to create category, and great.
The category name looks good here but something is off.
Let me go back.
When we use the form floating here,
the input will come first,
and that will have all of these classes.
So let me switch that around.
I added them to label by mistake and perfect.
We can copy and paste it here
modify the ASP 4 to be display order.
We will have to rebuild. Let me do that.
Category create, and perfect, category name looks good.
Let me see. Something is off with the display order.
We do not have the form floating.
Add that here and it will refresh, and perfect.
That looks good.
So with the row here, let me add padding top two.
And that looks much better for the create category.
Let me apply all of these changes to the other pages
in the next video.