Instructor: When you are working
with Entity Framework Core
and you are just getting started,
it is very common that you might run into some issues
with a migration
and some things might not work based on what you expect.
And migrations are something
that are very easy to be corrupted
if you do not pay attention.
You can always roll back a migration.
You can make more changes, create a model,
add new migration, but for some reason,
if everything is corrupt and you want to start fresh
while learning, how do you do that?
Doing that is pretty simple.
So let me show you how to do that in this video.
First thing, we will go to SQL Server here
and everything is corrupt.
So we will delete the database, which is Bulky right here.
Let's delete that.
Next, we will go back here.
Inside the DataAccess, we have Migrations.
Now our migrations are corrupt and we want to start fresh.
You can delete the migrations altogether.
Perfect. Now there are no migrations.
There is no database.
To start fresh you can go to Tools Package Manager Console
and add a new migration.
We know right now we are only adding the category model,
so we can say AddCategoryToDb
and we are also seeding the category table.
So we will say AddCategoryToDbAndSeedTable.
Now when you execute this, you will see an error message.
And there you go.
The target project is BulkyWeb.
Now we have moved our data to a DataAccess project.
So the default project must be updated to DataAccess.
So default project will be DataAccess
and the default startup project is BulkyWeb.
With that configured, if I run this, it will add migration.
Now, right now, there were no previous migration.
So what it will do is it will identify all the changes
that it has to push to a new database.
It has to create categories table, it has to insert data,
and that is all we have right now.
With that configured, we can hit the command update-database
and our database will be populated.
Perfect.
If we go back and refresh the database here,
we have Bulky, Tables,
and we should have Categories populated.
Great.
So the only disadvantage this time
is if you have added some new categories,
those will not be available because we are starting fresh.
But basically anytime in the video
if your migrations are corrupt
and you don't know how to reset your database
this is the video that you should look for.