Instructor: In this short video,
we will see the different service lifetimes
when it comes to dependency injection in .NET Core.
Now, you do not have to program this along with me.
I just want you guys to watch the next 10 minutes,
and understand what are the different service lifetimes
in dependency injection.
Before we take a look at any example,
let me quickly give you a rough idea
on what each lifetime is responsible for.
Transient lifetime is the simplest one among all of them,
and it is also one of the safest one.
Transient basically means
that whenever we want any implementation,
create a new object, and give that new object.
You never have to reuse an existing object.
Every time a service is requested,
a new implementation is created.
After that, we have the scoped,
where it depends on the HTTP request.
So whenever an HTTP request is sent to the server,
that time for that scope, one lifetime will be created,
and then the same object or same service is used
wherever in that request the service is requested.
So let's say for one single page load,
we are calling a service 10 times.
It'll only create that object one time,
and it'll use that same object 10 times in that one request.
But then if a next request comes in,
then a new implementation is created.
And finally, we have singleton,
where one implementation is created
for the lifetime of the application.
So once the application starts,
we create an object of that service or an implementation,
and that is used for all the upcoming request
unless you restart the application.
So to give you a rough idea, again, transient,
new service is created every single time,
for scoped, new service will be created once per request,
and for singleton, new service will be created
once per application lifetime.
Now, scoped is one of the most recommended approach
for web application.
Because of that, a service will be created on each request.
But even with all of this overview,
things might be a little complicated.
So let me explain that a little more
with a real world example.
Let me switch to Visual Studio,
and we will be creating an MVC application.
I will give it a name of DI_Service_Lifetime,
and let me create that.
In the project here, let me create a new folder
for services.
In there, let me create three interface
for the three service that we have.
So the first one will be IScoped.
Let me add a new one here, that will be singleton.
And finally, we will be adding the transient.
These are just the interface name.
We have not added any functionality.
In there, let me add a method, GetGuid,
which will return a random guid.
So the return type will be string.
Perfect, I will add that
in all the three interface that we added.
Now we need to add implementation of these three interface.
Implementation will be pretty simple.
Let me add a class here for the SingletonGuidService
that will implement the ISingletonGuidService,
implement the interface.
Here, let me create a private read-only guid
with the name of Id, and in the constructor,
Id, we will say Guid.NewGuid.
In the function here,
we just want to return Id.ToString.
That looks good.
Let me create the same implementation
for the other two interface that we have.
Let me add a class which will be ScopedGuidService,
and that will implement the IScopedGuidService.
I can copy everything here, paste it,
and we will change the constructor name.
Looks good.
Let me add the last one, which is TransientGuidService.
Let me copy and paste it in here.
And this will implement the ITransientGuidService.
So now we have three interface,
and their corresponding three implementation.
That looks good.
But when we register the services to Program.cs,
we have to write the lifecycle to which we want to register.
So in the add service here,
we will say builder.Services.add,
and then we have to write what lifecycle we want to use.
We have scoped, transient, and singleton.
In singleton, we will have the interface,
which is ISingletonGuidService,
and implementation is inside the SingletonGuidService.
That is how we register a service
to the dependency injection container.
We will also register the transient and scoped service.
Perfect.
So it is exactly same
like if we were registering DP context to the container,
and then when we have to use that,
we will do that inside the HomeController.
Before we start using that, right here,
let me create six private fields.
Two will be for the scoped service,
two for singleton, and two for transient.
We have scoped one, two, singleton one, two,
and transient one, two.
Next, what we want is implementation of these interface.
We registered that in Program.cs right here,
so basically we are saying
that when someone asks for an implementation
of ISingletonGuidService, we are telling the .NET framework
that provide them the implementation that is there
in the SingletonGuidService.
But there we are telling that use the AddSingleton
that is the lifetime.
So when we want to use the implementation
inside the constructor here, we can directly ask .NET Core
that we need the implementation of IScopedGuidService,
and we will call that as scopedGuid.
Then we want another implementation of that.
So scopedGuid1, comma, we will have scopedGuid2.
And similarly, we want the implementation
for singleton and transient service.
So these are the implementation
that .NET framework will provide
based on what we registered in Program.cs.
Then we have to assign these implementation
to the local variable that we have right here.
For that, we will say _singleton1 is equal to singleton1,
and same for everything else.
I can change this to be scoped1
rather than scopedGuid here.
Perfect, looks good.
So we have this implementation.
On there, we can call the method, which is GetGuid.
Rather than making anything fancy,
let me use a string builder for messages here,
and I will append to that message
using string interpolation.
So first, I will say Transient 1,
and then we will display the value
using _transient1.GetGuid.
We have that method, and after that, let me add a new line.
So perfect, that looks good.
For the first transient, copy and paste that once again.
We want to display the transient2.GetGuid.
And let me add one more new line there.
Copy these, paste it two more times.
Next, we want this scoped1.
scoped1, scoped2, _scoped1, _scoped2.
And finally, we need singleton.
Perfect.
When we return back,
we do not want to return back to a view,
we just want to return okay
and display the message, .ToString, on the screen.
So now we need to think about what will happen.
All of them have basically the same GetGuid method
which returns a random guid,
but the only thing that is different
is on how the lifecycle have been registered.
So let me run this, and see that in action.
And perfect.
We have something right here.
You can see when we are working
with the transient request here, the guids are different,
but when we have scoped or singleton,
they are the same.
As we know, singleton stays same
for the lifecycle of the application.
So even when we refresh the application,
scoped and transient will be different,
but singleton will always stay the same.
You can see when I'm refreshing here,
transient is getting updated along with scoped,
but singleton always stays the same.
And then for scoped here,
you can see every time for a single request,
it gets a new value, but for one request,
the value stays the same in both of them.
But in transient, for any time a guid is requested,
it calls a new guid.
So that means every time when a transient is called,
it basically gives a new implementation of that service.
When it comes to scoped,
the implementation stays same for one request.
If in that one request, we are calling this 10 times,
we will get the same service,
but for the next time, it will get you a different service
when you are working with scoped.
So with that, you can see how transient, scoped,
and singleton are different
when it comes to dependency injection service lifetime.