Now that we have seen routing, we know how the views are being displayed based on the URL.
But if I run the application again, that is not the only thing that is being displayed on the page,
because if I open the index.cshtml, you can see there is a welcome text and a learn about that we see
right here.
But what about this header that we have on the top and we also have a footer.
How is that getting loaded?
And for that we have to go to solution in Views folder.
We have seen what is there in the home view, but we have something called as shared and we have something
called as underscore view imports and underscore view start.
If you have worked with older .net application, you might remember something called as Master page and
a child page underscore layout is the master page of your complete application.
If I open underscore layout here you can see we have doctype html.
We have a head here with some styling.
We have a body and there we have the header.
In header you can see we have the home and privacy links here and we scroll down, we have something
called as render body.
This render body is a built in helper in the MVC and that will display anything that we want in the
body.
Now what that body will be, that will be determined by what is returned from the controller.
If we return the index view, it will display that view right here.
After the render party.
We have a footer here where we are displaying the bulky web.
If we go back to the application, that is what we have right here.
So underscored layout will be the master page of your application or the main page of your application.
Always remember that.
And in underscored layout, we will add all the JavaScript, all the CSS that we want to use globally
in the application.
With that, we have something in the anchor tags like ASP controller, ASP action.
These are called tag helpers, but ignore them when the time is right.
I will explain you why we need them right now.
Underscore layout is the master page of your application and whatever view we return from the controller
that will be displayed in the render body content of underscored layout.
After that, let's go back and we have something called as validation scripts partial.
There we have basically included to JavaScript.
Now when we progress with the course, we want to add client side validation and for that we will be
using this JavaScript because of that on all pages, validations are not needed.
So what the .net team has done is it has added some of the basic JavaScript here and then on the pages
where validations are needed.
It has separated that out in a different file and we can use them in our file only if needed.
We will see that in action down the road.
But here we have something called as validation script Partial.
Now, one thing that you notice here is in validation scripts partial.
We have an underscore.
This underscore is not required in layout or validation scripts partial.
But typically, if that is a page or component that is used throughout the application, then we typically
like to add an underscore.
That way, when we look at the name, we can know that, okay, this view will be used throughout the
application and there is also a special name for that, which is partial view.
Partial view basically means that they cannot be displayed on the page by itself.
They will be incorporated as a part of some main view, but that is a little too technical or a little
too early for now.
But just keep that terminology in mind that there is something called As View and there are partial
views by the name.
Partial views are basically the views that you do not use by themselves.
They will be consumed inside the main view.
The next we have a view for error.
Dot Cshtml.
This is the view where we display the error message.
If anything is encountered and we can ignore that for now.
Now, one main question that I had when I was learning MVC was how does the application know that this
underscored layout is the master page of the application?
That is simple.
We define that inside the file which is view start dot cshtml.
There we are telling that the layout of the application is underscored layout.
If I change this to be layout here, let me stop that and run it.
Things will not work.
We have an exception here.
The layout cannot be located and you can see where it is actually looking for the layout.
To fix that.
What we can do is I can rename this to be layout and then it will start working again.
Perfect.
So you can see that is how the application is configured to know what is the default layout or master
page of your application.
Let me revert back the change here.
I will keep it underscore layout.
That is the name you should be familiar with and not layout.
Perfect.
Let me run the application and it should work the same.
Great.
So you start will define what is the master page or what is the layout of your web application.
Then we also have something called as View Imports.
Here we have defined bulky web and bulky web models.
We have added using statements here.
If you are working with .net, you know the using statements are used rather than typing that every
time.
If not, do not worry.
When the time comes, I will show you why using statements are needed.
But on top of that it has added something called as tag helpers that also we will cover in upcoming
videos.
But view import, you can think about that as a global import file.
Rather than importing or writing the using statement in all file, you can add that here and that will
automatically be available in all the views.
Now again, the view import or the using statements that we have added here will only be available in
the views and not in controllers or models.
When the time is right in the future videos, I will show you the importance of view imports and we
will also be adding more imports in the file.
Let me close all the tabs here.
And with that, I believe we have covered all the files in the views.
We have a model controller and perfect.
Now, with the overview that we have covered with all the files and folder, it is the perfect time
to get our hands dirty from the next video.