Instructor: Now we have worked
on performing current operations on category,
but in our website we will be selling books
and basically we need product that will contain all
of the books of our website and that will have a category.
So we need to create a model for our product
which is bulk and perform credit operations on that.
First thing that we have to do for that
is actually create a model.
Let me close all the tabs here.
We will do that in the bulky book dot models here,
right click, add a new class,
and I can call that as product.
We will make this a public class
and what will be all the properties of product.
If you recall, inside category, we used data annotations
and we had the IT as the primary key.
We can copy those two, paste that in product here
because we will have ID and rather than name.
When we work with a book, we have title.
We do not want max length there.
This looks good.
After that, let me add description,
ISBN and author for our product.
Now our store is a bulky store
where we will be selling books in bulk,
so if they buy more books, they will get more discount.
For that, let me add first property,
which will be list price
and I will add a display property here
because if you notice here it has a list price.
I want to display that with a space.
So for that, we have the display data annotation
and I will call that as list price.
And of course I forgot the name here.
That looks good.
On top of that, I want a range validation.
That price must be between, let's say,
one and thousand dollars.
Looks good for the list price
but our store is a bulky store,
so based on the different quantity,
we will have different price.
Let me paste that three times.
The first one, let me call that price.
Next one, I will call that price 50,
and last one will be price hundred.
Price hundred will be price of the book
if they buy more than a hundred quantity.
Price 50 will be the price for more than 50 quantity
and it will be price for one to 50.
So list price will be a different price
and price here will be the cost
of product for the quantity one to 50.
If they buy more than 50,
then we will give them the price 50.
For more than a hundred, we will give them price hundred.
Now this looks good for all the properties
that we want right now.
Of course, we need category inside our product
and we also want to add an image to our product
but we will do that later on.
First I want to keep things super simple.
Right now our model has few strings and few double.
Kind of similar to what we had for our category.
And with that in place, I want you guys
to practice CRUD operations on product
similar to what we did with category
and that will be your next assignment.
Let me walk you through that in the next video.