Instructor: We have added the product model
to our project.
Now, we have not added all the properties,
but I have added the basic properties for now.
Before we add this product table to our database
we will have to add that
to application DbContext inside the data access.
So, let me copy this Db set for category
and we will rename that to be product and the table name,
I will call that as products.
Now, that looks good.
On top of that, I want to see the product as well.
So let me copy the has data here, paste it one more time
and then we will have to create new products here.
When we see something, you can write whatever you want,
but, for consistency, I have provided that inside snippets.
If you open the resources and snip it,
section six, we have seed products.
Let me open that, copy everything
and I will paste that inside the has data.
There I am populating six products,
and these are all the properties that we have added
in the product model,
so it should match perfectly.
With that configured,
now we have the data and we can see our table.
So with that, you can work on your first assignment.
Inside there, I want you to push product to the database
and when you create the product stable, along with that,
all the six records will also be created
because we added inside the has data.
Once you create the product stable, then you have
to implement the product repository for data access.
You will create the product repository interface
and implement that.
And after that, you will also add that to UnitOfWork.
That is the basic configuration that you have to do
for your first assignment.
So, good luck with that.
And we have already done that
with the category repository and the category table.
All the steps are exactly the same.
So, I hope you have good practice
before we move forward in the next video.