Instructor: I hope you were able
to complete all the grad operations with product.
I do not want you to see me typing everything here.
Because of that, what I will do is copy what we have
for category and paste that for product
and modify that real quick.
So, let's go back to our code here
where inside the areas here, Admin, Controller,
copy and paste the Controller
and I will rename that to be Product Controller.
Let me copy that name
and I will modify the class name and the constructor name.
Everything else looks good here.
Wherever we have category
I will have to replace that with product.
So I can Ctrl + Shift + F, Replace in File.
And in the current file
I will replace Category with Product.
I will match the case here and Replace All.
Now here, make sure you are only doing that
in the current document.
Once you complete that, let's take a look here.
Perfect, on unit of work,
we are going into product and retrieving all product.
Where we have the create
we do not need the custom validation
so I can remove that and this looks good.
Inside the Edit get action method
we are retrieving the product here and rather than category
let me also rename this.
So lowercase category
we will rename that to lowercase product
in the current document and that looks good.
Perfect, in the added post here, we are updating.
Inside the delete we are fetching that, looks good.
In the delete post here where the product and remove that.
So with that, the controller looks great.
Now we need to add views for our application.
If we go back
we need to create views for the CRUD operation.
We already have the views for category,
copy and paste that again.
The complete folder.
I will rename that to be product
and let me see what we have in index.
In all of them we have to replace category with product.
So an easier approach is
let me open all of them here, close the product controller.
We only have the four view open here, Ctrl + Shift + F,
Replace in File and we will replace
that in all the open documents
which are all the views for our product.
Replace All, did not find any with the lowercase.
Let me do that with uppercase here and perfect, that worked.
Now we have a different properties inside product
so rather than name we have title.
Let me rename that and paste it two times.
After title, we have description.
Let me modify that and paste it here.
I will copy and paste this about five more times here.
And then we have the ISPN, let me modify that.
Next we have the author.
After that we have the price.
First we have the list price.
Next we have the price 50.
Well, we first have the price.
And then we will have Price50 and Price100.
So copy and paste that two more times here,
we have Price50, and finally we have Price100.
Great, that looks good for create.
Let me copy this and go to Edit here, paste it here.
Perfect, inside delete as well,
we will have to paste that
and we will remove the validation.
On top of that, let me disable all the input fields
when we are deleting.
Perfect, that looks good.
Finally, we have the index here, scroll down.
And in index I want to display five properties, title, ISPN,
the list price here, author and category.
Where we have the for each here
we do not need any order buy.
And first we have the title.
Next we have ISPN, whoops, not that, just ISPN.
Copy and paste that three more times.
We have the list price.
Next we have the author.
And finally, right here I want the category.
But in our current model we do not know what is the category
of a book or product.
We will cover that in the upcoming videos
but this looks good, with that in place,
let me add a navigation to that
in underscored layout, Views, Shared, underscored layout.
We have the dropdown, copy the ally, paste it one more time.
This will be for product and that looks good.
I believe that is all that was needed.
But let me run the project and make sure that works.
We will go to CONTENT MANAGEMENT, PRODUCT here and, great,
we have the product list here.
Let me try to edit.
Perfect, that looks good.
Whoops, description is two times and Edit.
Let me remove one.
And rather than input here
let me change that to be a text area.
When we have text area, we need the explicit closing tag,
else it will not work when we save that.
Let's go back.
The hot reload kicks in and perfect.
We have a text area.
Now of course this is not perfect right now
but we will modify that in the upcoming videos, right now,
if at try to update something here,
it should work and perfect.
That is working.
Let me revert it back here.
Let me create a dummy product here.
Create, that works.
Let me try to delete that
and perfect, all the operations are working as expected.
Only thing that I will change right now is add
a little bit of space.
So let me go back and in all of the views here
where we have margin top of four
let me make that margin y, save that, it was in the Edit.
Perfect, that looks good.
So I will add this margin y four in all the places.
Delete as well.
I need the margin y, create, margin y, index, margin y.
Perfect, let me save all.
Go back here and perfect.
Now everything is looking much cleaner
but basically we have the product grad operation.
Those are working as expected.