-: Next thing that I want to work on here
is when we are working with product,
we need an association between product and category.
If we go to category, it is action, sci-fi, and history.
Basically any product that we have
will belong to one of the category.
So that will be a foreign key relation
between product and category table.
How can we accomplish that with EF Core?
Now, if we did not have EF Core,
we will basically have a column of category ID
in the product table and then,
we will have a constraint on foreign key,
which we will add in SQL server.
But thankfully because of EF Core,
we do not have to touch our database.
All we have to do is define some constraint in our model
and entity framework will take care of everything else.
So how can we accomplish that foreign key relation
between category and product?
Let me close all the tab here
and let me open the model here, which is product model.
There we basically need a column for category ID.
So prop integer, I will call that category ID.
Now if I add just this column, table will not
know that this is a foreign key to the category table.
In order to explicitly define that,
we need a navigation property to the category table.
So right here, we will have a navigation property
to category table and I will call that category.
And on top of that we have to explicitly define
that this category property is used for foreign
key navigation for the category ID.
And for that we have a data annotation of foreign
key and we can say that this category table has
a foreign key which will be category ID, right here.
That is all that we have to write.
And then entity framework core
will take care of everything else.
So you can see how powerful entity framework core really is.
With that configured, let me save that
and I will add a migration.
So we will add a migration
and I will call that add foreign key
for category product relation.
Now when you change anything with the core model,
if it requires a database change,
entity framework core is smart enough
and it does all of that.
You can see it is adding a column here
and it is updating some data.
But when it is updating the data,
you can see it is setting all the value
to be zero for category ID.
That is not what we want because we are seeding our data
we need to actually pass category in that seed data.
So this migration that got added,
I am not happy with it because I am going to change
something in the seed data and create a new migration.
Now, only because this migration has not been
pushed to the database,
I can directly come here and we can go to migrations
and delete that migration.
You do not want to do that directly here.
You can go to package manager
and you can write the command, remove migration
and it'll remove the last migration that was added.
You can see in the migrations folder
that migration does not exist anymore and it got removed.
So now we can add a new migration.
But before we do that, we have to fix our seed data
that is inside application DB context.
Here we have to pass a category ID.
You can pass anything you want.
I am going to be random about it.
Some of them I will say one.
The other one I will say two here,
and last one, I will say three.
So perfect.
We have assigned some value to the category ID
and when we are seeding,
make sure that you use the category ID that exists
and not something random like 11.
That will not work.
With that configured, let me go to package manager
and I will add the migration once again.
Perfect. Let me see the values.
Yep, we have the correct value this time
and that looks good.
So our migration is looking good.
Let me update the database
And perfect. That is done.
Let me go to SQL server.
We will do select top thousand and great.
We have category ID.
On top of that, if you expand that and examine the keys
you will notice a foreign key relation
between product and categories.
So with that, if you try to add it here
and if you try to enter, let's say 11
it'll not work because of the foreign key relation.
So with that, you can see how easy it was
to add a foreign key relation between table.
All we had to do is use the foreign key data annotation.
With that configured, let me continue from the next video.