Instructor: Now, before we move any forward,
let me open the product model in the models project here
and I will add one more property
which is kind of critical and that is image URL.
When we work with any product here,
they will typically have an image
so let me call that as image URL.
It'll be a string property right now
and it'll be empty right now.
With that, let me save this
and we will have to add a migration.
I will call that add image URL to product.
The seed entity did not work.
Well, you can go there in the data
and you can add an empty image URL.
That should work right now.
We will fix that as we proceed with the course.
Perfect. Let me add the migration once again
and it should work.
Perfect. Let's update the database
and great. Now, our model for product is complete
and we have added all the properties that are needed.
How this image URL will work,
that we will cover in the upcoming videos.