Instructor: What we want to work on
is when we go to product and we edit a product
or create a product we cannot toggle the category.
So, let me fix that.
First, we need to add a dropdown right here.
Before we even add that dropdown, we need a list
of all the categories that we can display in the dropdown.
So first, we need to retrieve that in the controller.
If I open the product controller,
when we are passing it back to the view,
we are passing list of product.
On top of that, we need to pass list of all the categories
or we can pass a select list that we can use
to populate a dropdown.
Now, there are multiple ways to pass that thing.
But if we want to pass that along with this object,
that is not possible because when we return back,
we can only pass one object.
We will see how to overcome that in the upcoming videos.
But let's say you only want to return a list of product
and not any other model.
In that case,
if we have to pass some additional functionalities,
there are many other ways,
but before we see how to pass that,
we actually have to retrieve that.
So, to retrieve that, I will store that in an IEnumerable
of select list item.
If I press control dot here,
it is inside system.collections.generic,
that is the IEnumerable that select list item
is inside Microsoft.aspnetcore.mbc.rendering.
Now if I press F12 on the select list item,
it'll navigate me to the class here
and you can see with the select list item,
we have text and value
and that is what we will be populating
and using in our dropdown.
So, let me call this category list is equal to.
We need to retrieve all the categories,
so unit of work.category.getall.
And then if we just do that, it will not work
because here, it is retrieving an IEnumerable of category
and we have to convert that to an IEnumerable
of select list item.
How can we do that dynamic conversion,
while we are recreating some things from the database?
In order to do that, we have something powerful,
known as projections in EF Core.
In order to use projections, we will say .select
and there, we will give it a random object.
Let me call that U.
And what object do we want to return from here?
We want to return a new select list item.
So, we will write that and inside there,
what properties should be populated?
Let me break it out in different line here.
We want to populate the text,
which is inside u.Name and value,
we want ID of the category, so U.Id,
convert that to a string.
That way what will happen is each category object here
will be converted into a select list item
and it will have a text and a value.
And that is how we can convert a category
to an IEnumerable of select list item using projection.
Again, this is very powerful feature
because you can see how in a single line
when you are retrieving something,
you can easily pick only some columns
and not all the columns.
You can convert that to a new object
and directly assign that.
With that, we have the category list right here.
But now the question is,
how do we pass that onto our view?
Let me do that in the next video.