-: Now we have to pass some data
from our controller to our view.
And for that, we have multiple items,
or multiple routes, that are available.
First one here is a ViewBag.
ViewBag transfers data from controller to view,
and not vice versa.
And that is exactly what we want.
We want to pass the data that we have in our controller
to our view,
and it is ideal for a situation
in which the temporary data is not in a model.
Like in our example, we need the dropdown list,
and that is not within our model.
We do not have a property to store that.
So in that case, we can store this in a ViewBag,
and pass that to our view.
ViewBag is a dynamic property that takes advantage
of the new dynamic features in C# 4.0.
Any number of properties and values
can be assigned to a ViewBag,
and the ViewBag's life only exists
during the current HTTP request.
ViewBag values will be null if there is any redirection.
Like in our case,
we will be passing the value from controller to view,
and we will not be redirecting,
that is why the ViewBag value will persist.
Last point is that ViewBag
is actually a wrapper around ViewData.
Now, you might think, "What is ViewData?"
But we will cover one thing at a time.
First, let me switch back
and show you how we can use ViewBag.
Right here in the code,
we are getting all the category list,
but I am inside the Index action.
Let me cut this.
We actually need that inside the Create action.
So right here, let me paste that here.
And now, you might be thinking
that we are not passing anything here.
Why don't we pass the category list?
But if I go to the view,
you can see we have defined a model at the top,
which is the Product model.
So now we need to pass this category list to our view,
and we want to use ViewBag.
So far that we can say ViewBag.CategoryList
is equal to CategoryList.
We can give any name that we want,
and this name that we give here
will basically act as a key value,
where key will be CategoryList,
and value will be whatever we assign here.
Once we add this here, then inside the create
we can fetch that and display that in a dropdown.
Let me scroll down, and there we have the Price100,
after that let me copy and paste it one more time.
The label will be for CategoryId,
ASP validation, we can change that to be CategoryId,
but here, we want the select field.
Now when we are using select rather than input,
we cannot use the self-closing tag.
We have to explicitly close that.
And after that, I will add one more default option here,
which will be disabled selected by default,
and there we will display "Select Category."
Now asp-for, we have that as CategoryId,
but we need to display all the items in the dropdown.
For that we have a special tag helper, asp-items,
and this expects an IEnumerable of select list item.
We have that in our ViewBag, so in order to extract that
we will write, ViewBag, dot, and we need the key name.
Now key name, if you write here,
it will not help with IntelliSense,
because it is not dynamic.
You can give any key name here,
and IntelliSense cannot detect what you gave,
so you have to type that and make sure that it matches.
If there is any spelling mistake,
things will not work.
For the class here,
we will give it a Bootstrap class of form-select,
and with that, let me run the application.
We go to Product here,
and we will have to go to Create New Product,
scroll down, perfect.
We have Select Category,
and there we have Action, SciFi, and History.
So our dropdown is looking great with Create Product.
Now that is one way of doing things with ViewBag.
Let me continue and show you the alternative
in the next video.