Bhrugen: We have seen ViewBag in the last video.
Next, we want to see how we can accomplish the same things
with ViewData.
ViewData also transfers the data
from Controller to View, and not vice-versa.
And again, it is ideal for the situation
where the temporary data is not in a model.
ViewData is derived from ViewDataDictionary,
which is a dictionary type.
ViewData value must be type casted before use.
Like, if we go back, when we were using ViewBag right here,
we did not have to cast that data.
It was all dynamic.
But when we use ViewData,
we will have to cast that before we use the value.
And lastly, the ViewBags life only lasts
during the current http request,
and ViewData values will be null if redirection occurs,
similar to ViewBag.
So there are quite a few things that are similar here
but let us see that with an example.
First, we have to go back to the Controller.
Let me comment this out.
Copy that and paste it here.
Rather than ViewBag, we want to use ViewData.
If you use dot there, it will not work.
You have to define that in a square bracket.
And what is the key value? Like in a dictionary.
That is how you assign a value to ViewData.
Now the question is how do you access that inside view?
When we were using ViewBag,
we did not have to do conversion,
but with ViewData we will have to do some conversion here.
So we will use the @ sign and we will save ViewData here.
Write the key name, let me go back and copy that
to avoid any spelling mistake.
And then we have to explicitly convert that.
So we will say as,
and this will be an IEnumerable of SelectListItem.
With that, the errors go away
and you can see how ViewData might be a little inconvenient
as compared to ViewBag.
But with that, everything should work the same.
Let me restart the application and see that in action.
We go to create new product, and perfect.
That is functional.
But there is one more thing that you should be aware of.
ViewBag internally inserts data into the ViewBagDictionary.
So the key of ViewData,
and property of ViewBag must not match
because both of them will go to the same entity.
Now, before I wrap up this video,
previously we have seen TempData,
which are used to generate alerts,
and TempData can be used to store data
between two consecutive requests.
TempData internally use Session to store the data.
So think of it as a short lived session,
which will only exist for one request.
Now, TempData value must also be type cast before use.
So check for null values to avoid any runtime errors.
Finally, as you already know,
TempData can be used to store only onetime message
like error messages or validation message.
And if you refresh the page after that, it will go away.
So that gives you a brief idea on all the differences
between Viewbag, ViewData, and TempData.