Instructor: Now we know viewbag, viewdata,
and we are using that in our application.
But think about that.
When you have an application and if it grows,
you have many more data, what if you have 10 view data
and 5 view bags that you are using?
Things will start getting ugly
because when you will look at the view,
you will not be able
to easily identify where this is coming from.
And the reason I am saying is our view is tightly bounded
to this product model,
but product model does not have all the data that is needed.
So typically I avoid using viewbags
and view data as much as possible.
The alternative to that is to tightly bind your view
to the object that you want.
If object is not a simple object,
you can create a combination of object
and that is called as view model.
View model as the name suggests,
it is a model which is specific for a view.
So let me show you how to do that
and then everything will make much more sense.
In our models folder, let me right click,
add a new folder with the name of view model.
I will have to stop the application here.
And I will call that view models.
Inside there I will add a new class file.
And I will call that product view model where VM stands
for view model.
It will be a public class.
And we will think
about what will be all the entity that we want
for our product.
We want a product object.
So first let me create that property which will be product.
Next, what we want is an IEnumerable to hold the dropdown.
So we'll say prop
and that will be an IEnumerable of select list item.
When we need the select list item here,
we will have to install the NuGet package
Microsoft.ASPnetCore.mbc.view features.
The property name we will call that category list here.
Exactly what we have in the product controller.
Now inside create we were not passing anything to the view.
But if we go to our view, we were using product.
Now what we will be using is product view model.
We cannot access that directly.
So we will go bulkybook.models.viewmodels
dot we have the product view model.
Now view model is something that we will be using
in many of the views.
So it makes sense to add this to our import statement.
Inside the admin area, view import.
Let me add that using statement.
And I will also add this,
copy that to our customer view, view imports.
And we have a global view imports as well. Perfect.
Let me save and close all of that.
And now we can remove this
product view model will be detected.
When we add this here, our title is inside product.
So we will have to add that in all the places.
Let me modify that for all of the properties here. Whoops.
You can see the errors went away.
And then where we have the ASP items,
we do not want any view data.
We want to access that directly from our product view model.
If we go back, we have the category list here.
Now if you try to access category list directly here,
it will not work.
So basically when you have to access something
from the model directly and if it does not work,
you can always access the model by using the add sign.
So we can say add model and there we have the category list.
Now the product here is working
but if for some reason this was not working,
you can access product by writing add model dot product.
Both of them are exactly the same things. So perfect.
We are using our view model. Let me scroll down.
I believe everything else is working.
Let me build the project here and see if that works.
We still have to modify our controller
but let me do that now.
Product controller where we have the create,
we need to pass a product view model.
So right here we will say product view model.
Let me call that product VM is equal to new
and then we have to assign the properties here.
Category list will be inside category list, comma,
we have the product, product will be new product.
So perfect. That looks good.
And then we will be passing the product view model.
If you want you can just cut this
from here and assign that to the category list like that.
It should also work.
We do not want the view data or view back.
Let me remove that. Perfect.
Much cleaner.
With that we have a view model
that we are passing to our create view.
Let me run and see if that works.
We go to product here and create new product.
Perfect. That is working.
But now if you post here,
it will not work because if you examine in the HTTP post,
we said that there will be a product OBJ.
This we have to modify to product VM
and when we are adding something we'll say OBJ dot product.
With that configured, let me save and run the application
and try to create a new product.
I will populate dummy information, category,
let me make it action and create.
And we see an exception.
Now you might be wondering
on why we are getting this exception.
Because the exception here is inside the select field
and it says OBJ reference is not set
to an instance of an object.
That is a common exception when you are working
with C sharp.
Basically anything that is being
accessed here does not have a value.
But why when we are posting it is trying
to access these fields?
The reason is simple.
Something in model state is not valid
and it is returning back to the view.
When it returns back, we are not passing the view model
so dropdown is not populated.
Let me show that.
I will add a debugging point
here and let me hit create once again
and see model state is valid is false.
Now what property is false here we can examine that
in the result view and the category list is invalid,
the image URL is invalid
and the product dot category is invalid.
Now why is it validating all of those properties?
We do not want the validations on them.
So basically we need to tell that hey,
when you are validating our model,
I do not want validations on these three entities.
One way to fix the image URL right now is let me go back
to the create view and let me just copy
and paste this for image URL.
That way we will not be bothered
with that exception and let me show that.
Now of course we will fix image URL as we proceed.
But right now let me show you the issue
with other two entities.
We hit create here. Let me hit create here.
Model state is not valid and now there will be two entities.
One will be category list and another will be category.
So we basically do not want
to validate those two properties.
Doing that is super simple.
All we have to do is add an annotation
on top of the category list, which is validate never.
And that will make sure that it does
not validate this property that we have.
I will also have to add that
where we have the category right here.
And if you want, you can also add that to the image URL.
That way you are not bothered with that as well.
With that configured, let me run the application again
and see if creating a product works.
We go to product here. Let me try that once again.
Well I have description two times. Let me remove that first.
That is annoying.
Save that and the page should reload.
Perfect. Let's try.
Create. We go back.
Now model state is valid. That is good.
And it will create the product.
Great. That works.
But if the model state was not valid,
we do not want that ugly exception.
So how do we fix that?
To do that,
let me just bring back this validate never,
comment it out for just few minutes.
And basically when we are going to the else block,
it expects the dropdown to be populated.
So whatever we have here, if I copy that to the else part
and paste it here and I pass this view model back,
then it will work.
Let me have this return statement in here.
Now if we did this,
then it will create a new product view model.
We do not want that.
We only want the dropdown to be populated.
So right here where we have the obj,
we can say obj.category list and just populate that list,
not anything else.
When we return back, we will return the obj
or I think the better name here will be product view model.
So let me rename that.
Perfect.
With that,
if I remove debugging point and run the application,
it will redirect us back to the product page.
Let me show that.
We select some category, hit create,
and it redirects us back,
but we do not see the error message.
The good thing is we do not see that ugly exception,
but the error message we have already handled that
with validate never.
So let me bring that back.
I only wanted to show you that when you return back,
you have to populate the dropdown once again,
because when it is being posted,
that dropdown will not be populated
if you encounter any errors on the page.
So this looks perfect.
That way we are handling if the model state is not valid,
we make sure to populate the dropdown again.
So we did not see that ugly exception that we saw before.
But with that our create functionality
for product is working as expected.
Now we have a view model for our product.
Based on that we already are binding our category as well.
If I directly press create here,
we have all the validations in place as well.
And with that, we have seen how to add view models.
Now to summarize again,
view models are models that are specifically designed
for a view.
And the advantage that we get because of that is that
a view will be strongly typed to one model.
And because of that
view models are also known as strongly typed views.
So if someone will ask you what is a strongly typed view,
that basically means that there is
a model that is specific for that view, because of that,
because of that the view is strongly typed to a model.
So it is always good to remember that term as well.