Instructor: Right now, we have been working
on create new product.
And I said before, we are only working there
and not on edit because I want to show you
one thing in the scenario.
When you look at the create page,
it looks exactly same to what we have for edit
but the details are populated when you select edit.
Many times in the application,
what user have is they have a single page
for create and edit, and paste on if there is an ID here,
they retrieve and display that,
and the display update rather than create.
That way, there is a single page for create an update,
and that is exactly what we want to do as well.
We have seen the different pages for create an update
when we were working with category,
but for product, I want to combine both of them
in a single page.
Before we work on the view here,
we need to modify the controller.
Where we have the create controller
rather than create a more meaningful name is upsert.
And what I mean by upsert is UP stands for update
and SERT is basically combination of insert.
So if you have update and insert,
you remove this thing and you come up with upsert
and that name is commonly used
when you combine update and insert in one functionality.
In upsert you might have or you might not have an ID.
If you are creating then you will not have an ID.
But if you are updating, then you will get an ID.
The functionality that you have here looks good for create,
but if ID is present,
then basically we have to retrieve that product
and assign it to this product inside the product view model.
So what we can do is right here have an if condition
and if ID is null or if ID is equal equal to zero,
that means it is a create
and we can directly return back to the view.
In the else part,
that means it is an update functionality
because ID is present, this will be equal equal to,
and if we have update,
then we will have to populate product view model dot product
is equal to underscore unit of work dot product dot,
we have the get functionality,
and we need to pass the link operator,
u goes to u dot ID is equal equal to the ID.
We are using get here and not get all
because we know this will only return
or ideally it should only return one record
and that is the product.
Once we retrieve that, we can return back to the view
and return back product view model.
So the first functionality here is for create
and later one is for update.
With that, the absurd controller here looks good.
We need to modify the post action method for absurd as well.
And when we are updating, if you remember,
let me go to create, we added multi-part form data.
When a file is uploaded here,
we will get that here in the iform file.
We will make that another field.
And let me call that as file.
Now, right now I do not want to focus
on what we will do here or rather any functionality in here.
We will do that later on.
We do not need edit.
I can remove them altogether.
Perfect, so upsert post, we will come back to that.
But let me modify the view.
So if I go back to the views of admin, product, create,
we will modify that to be upsert, and we will remove edit.
We do not need that.
Alright, let me open upsert and work on that.
When we are in the form,
we should have the ID in the hidden property.
That way when we post, we always have that populated.
After that where we have the title, create product here,
if ID is present, this should be update product,
so we have to make that dynamic.
We will use the at sign here,
and we can check model dot product dot ID.
If that is not zero, then we will display update,
else we will display create.
We can remove this create product
and that should be dynamic.
Let me run the application.
We will not be able to navigate that directly
because when we go to product,
this is going to the create action.
We will have to modify that.
That is inside and dress code layout here.
Product controller, we have the index action.
That looks good.
Whoops, it is inside index there.
It will be upsert.
Let me scroll down where we have edit.
It will be the same action, upsert.
Save that.
And we need to stop and restart.
Let me navigate to product here.
And we hit create new.
Perfect, goes to upsert here.
If I go back and try to edit, it goes to the same view,
but you can see data is populated and we see update product.
Let me also modify the button text here.
So let me go back to upsert.
We have the button.
Here, we can also add an if condition,
and be like if model dot product dot id,
if that is not zero, then we want update,
else we will keep create.
Copy this, paste it here, and call that as update.
Now, right now I am keeping things super simple
but we have if else condition.
Moving down the road,
we will be adding some more validation on update.
That is why I have added an if else condition
rather than an inline functionality
of just renaming the text here.
So perfect, with that configured,
if I go back, we have update,
and that looks good.