-: Before I work on anything else, if I go to product here
and try to create a product,
you can see the description here is a text box.
I want to convert that to a rich text area.
For that I will be using something called a TinyMCE here
and we have the editor right here.
You can see it is a fancy editor
and you can do quite a few things with description.
Make it as fancy as you want.
For pricing, if we go here, you'll see
that it is free forever, if you use the core version.
And that is good enough for our requirements.
So let me log in here and if you do not have an account
you can always continue with Google.
Once we log in here we have the cloud dashboard.
Now I already have registered for the account
so you can see some other usage that I have.
But if you sign up here, you'll see the cloud integration
and that is what we need to get started.
First thing is the script here.
So let me copy the script that is displayed
and we will go back to our application
where we'll open underscore layout
and where we have the Java script at the end here.
Let me paste that.
Once you do that, if you scroll down
that will be the TinyAPI key.
But that key is already included in the script here
so you can directly use the script right here.
Now that we have the script in place
we have the actual usage right here.
And let me copy the script tag here.
Only thing that we need is a text area on the page
because you can see the selector here is text area.
So let me go back here and in the product I will
open upsert where I have the description.
I will convert that to be a text area.
And with text area we need the explicit closing tag.
Now with description, we do not want any validation
so I can remove that and we have to add the Java script.
If you notice here we have a section for script.
Inside there we can paste the Java script code
and that should work.
With that configured,
let me save everything.
Go back and perfect.
You can see we have a nice editor right here.
Now with that, we do not see the description at the top.
So let me go back here and where I have the description
cut that and paste it and I will remove the form floating
and where we have the class
I will give it a class of text muted for the grayish color.
Perfect, that looks much better.
You can see we have fancy fonts here that could be applied
and our description can now be super fancy.
If we go back here and when we scroll down
you can see in the toolbox and plugins
we have quite a few plugins right here.
We might not need all of them.
We can remove the image here, link here,
media, search replace.
Let me remove that and let me remove the links here.
I guess that should be good enough.
Let me see how that looks like.
Save that, go back and, yep, that looks better.
You can always play around with what plugins you want
but I leave that selection to you.
With that, we have implemented TinyMCE right here
on the product page.
Now finally, what we want to work on is when
we select an image here and hit the create button
we need to save that image somewhere in our code here
and we need to also update the image URL.
Let me do that in the next video.