-: Now when we select an image here and hit the create button
we need to save that image.
All the static files of our code must always go
into one folder, and can you tell me which folder that is?
If you said www root folder, you are 100% correct.
So inside the www root folder, let me stop the application.
We will add one more folder for images
in that folder I will create a sub folder
with the name of product.
With that in place, let me open the controller again
and let me remove this controller's folder
because it is empty.
All the controllers are inside the area's folder.
So let me delete this.
We do not need that anymore.
And we have the product controller where
we have the absurd post action method.
Right now we are not handling create
and edit because we have handled that in the get here
but we still have to handle
both the scenarios when we are absurding.
But inside the I form file
we will receive the file that was uploaded.
So we have to capture that file
and we have to save that inside the images product path.
So now our question is how do we access this root path
of our application, which is www root folder.
To do that we have to inject something called
as i web host environment
and that is provided by default with the .NET project.
So basically we have to inject
that like we are injecting the i unit of work.
But the good thing is we do not have to register that.
That is a built-in functionality that is provided
with the .NET project.
So I will say private, read only, I web host environment
and let me call that underscore web host environment.
We have to inject that using dependency injection
and then using this web host environment we
will be able to access the www root folder.
So if the model state is valid, we can say string
www root path is equal to underscore web host
environment dot we have the web root path.
That path will basically give us the root folder
which is www root folder.
After we get the root path here
we can first check if file is not null.
So basically if file is not null then we want to
upload the file and save that in the product folder.
Now when the file is uploaded
file might have some weird name.
So rather than keeping the same name
we can rename that to be a random guid.
So right here we can say string file name is equal to guid
dot new guid dot to string.
That will give us a random name for our file.
Then right now we have the www root path we
need to navigate to the product path.
So I will say string product path is equal to
path dot combine and I want to combine the www root path
with another path which is images forward slash product.
That will give me the path inside this product
folder where we have to actually upload this file.
The file name here is only a random quid
but we need to preserve the extension that is there
in this file.
So where we have the file name here
I can say plus and we have to get the extension sub path.
Inside there we have a helper method which is get extension
and we will pass file in there.
We have the file name,
so the image that we will be saving will have a guid
and it will have the same extension that got uploaded.
We have the final image name here
and we have the location where we have to save that
with both of that configured, let me save that image.
We will add a using here, we will say variable file
stream is equal to new file stream and there
we have to give the final path as well as the file name.
So basically the complete URL.
So I can do path dot combine there
and we can combine the product path with the file name.
That will give us the ultimate location where
we have to save that file.
When we are using file stream here
we have to pass one more property here
which is file mode and we'll save file mode dot create
because we are creating a new file there
in order to copy the file, we'll say file copy
to and we want to copy the file
to the file stream that we have right here.
That will copy the file in the new location that we added
or configured right here on line 60 and 61.
Now that is great,
but in the product view model, if we examine
we have product where we need to save the image URL.
So wherever in the folder here we are saving that image,
We should save that in the product image URL.
So right here we will say product view model dot
product dot image URL is equal to
and we know that will be inside the images folder.
I will add the forward slash there, we have
the product folder and then I want file name and extension.
Both of them are inside the file name variable
so we will save that.
With that configured, our create functionality looks good.
After that we are adding the product here, saving that
and we have the temp data product created successfully.
Now, right now, even though this is absurd, we are
only handling creation of a product with a particular image.
So let me run the application and make sure that works
before we work on updating any product and
updating their image. We will go to product here
and let me try to create a product.
Let me select an image here
and we will hit the create button
and we have an exception cannot insert null into image URL.
Let me see why that happened because we are
updating that right here.
Let me add a debugging point and see what is going on.
Let me continue.
Go back here, re add the image and hit the create button.
Model state is valid.
Let me see if the file came through.
That did not. For some reason that is null.
Let me go to Absurd and see.
We have the multi-part form data that looks right.
Where is the input form? Right here.
Well, we have type is equal to file
but if we go to controller it expects a file name.
We do not have that here.
We have to give it a name of file as well.
That is how it will bind that to this variable
and we will have to rebuild and apply changes.
Let me try that.
Let me select image again.
Hit the create button, and perfect.
File it came through this time.
Let me debug and also show you
the product being populated in the folder.
File is not null.
We get the new file in with the extension product path here.
That looks good.
File stream. Now once we execute this copy
to the folder here with product,
you can see it already has that image, but
if you open that in File Explorer, it is empty right now.
I can show that, properties.
You can see it is zero bytes because right now
the file stream is open but it has not copied.
Now it has copied that through.
So if we go and see properties, again
we have the size of the product.
Once we do that
we populate image URL and we add that product.
We press F5, product created successfully.
So perfect with that our create functionality
for product is working, but when we edit that product
we need to somewhere see that image.
Let me add that in the next video.