Narrator: Now what I want to do
is where we have the update or rather create,
rather than taking up the full width here,
we will take column 10 and the two rows
on the right hand side
we will reserve that for the product image.
So we have to make some designing changes.
Let me go to absurd.
We have our form here.
Inside there, let me add a div,
give it a class of row.
In that row, we will say div class of column 10.
And I will add one more div with a class of column two.
Whatever we have in the div here,
let me cut that and paste it in class of column 10.
Save that.
And perfect,
it got shifted.
On the right side here, we will display the image.
So let me scroll down here and we need the image tag, img.
Src is inside Model.Product.ImageUrl.
And we will give it a width of 100%.
I will also give it some custom styling here
and let me close that tag.
Let's go back and perfect.
We have the image that is being displayed here.
When we go to create, it will be empty and that is okay.
Now our create is functional and we can see the image,
but in the update functionality,
we have not added anything inside the post method.
If I go back here, controller.
Everything that we have here is for create.
Well not there.
In the post here, we only have Product.Add.
We have not handled how to update the product right now.
So in the next video,
let me manage updating product in the absurd action method.