Instructor: We want to manage updating a product
in the product controller.
But for that, first let's think about
what should happen to the image.
If we go back here and let me go back, let's assume
that when a product is created, they must upload an image.
So next time when they are updating something
let's say they are only updating the description
and if they hit the update button
then we do not want to update the image.
So basically when they are updating
if the image URL is no
then we do not want to update that.
But if they are updating a new image,
then we want to replace the existing image
with the new image.
So if a file is present when they are updating
then we want to delete the old file
and we want to add this new file.
Let me handle that scenario first.
When we have to upload a new file
all the logic stays the same, but the only thing
that we have to add here is we have to delete the old file.
If image URL is present and a new file is being uploaded.
So if the file is not null, and if image URL is present
so we will check here,
if product view model dot product dot imageUrl
and I can say string dot is null or empty.
So if that is not null or empty
that means that there is an image URL
and we are uploading a new image because file is not null.
In that case, we have to delete the old image.
In order to remove the old image
we need the path of that particular image.
So we will say variable old image path is equal
to path dot combine.
We need the root folder, which is inside wwwRootPath
and then if we examine our database here
bulky, table, products,
you will notice
that we have a forward slash in the image URL.
We need to remove that
because we are using patent dot combined.
So I will say,
product view model dot product dot image URL dot.
We have the trim start
and we want to remove the forward slash.
For that, we will have to escape that
with another forward slash.
That will basically combine
and give us the path of the old image.
Then deleting that is simple.
We have that in system dot io dot file.
We first need to check
if anything exists in that old image path.
If it does, then we will delete
system dot io dot file dot delete the old image.
So perfect, we will delete that image.
We will upload a new image and we'll update the image URL.
That is great.
But finally where we are adding here
we will rather have to update.
Now how will we identify whether it is an add or an update?
That depends on if the ID is present.
So we'll say
if product view model dot product dot Id is equally equal
to zero, that means it is an add.
Paste that.
Else, it is an update.
So underscore unit of work dot product dot update
product view model dot product.
Perfect.
Now before we test this
I want to modify something in the update
and let me walk you through that in the next video.