Instructor: Now we want to display
the category name here.
If we only had to display the ID, that was super simple.
If I go to controller here.
And let me add a debugging point on the product controller.
Index action.
Refresh that.
If I examine the obj product list, you will notice
we have category ID that is populated for our products.
But we need to populate this category navigation
property because inside there we have
category name that we can access.
So basically based on the foreign key relation
we need this category to be populated.
How can we do that smartly using EF core?
Or that we have something called as include
that will automatically include the navigation properties
based on the foreign key relation
and it is provided by the EFO team.
So how can we use that?
We will have to add that to our core repository
because that is the method that we are using
in the controller to get all the product.
That is...
Where is that?
Right here.
Now before I add that in the get all logic,
let me show you how that will work
with directly application DB context.
Right here we have underscore db.products.
On there we have something called as include.
And you can see right here it says specifies
related entities to include in the query string.
So let me add that.
And what we want to include, we can write that
by saying U goes to U dot.
And we want to include category.
That is how what will happen is that category
will automatically be populated when it retrieves
all the product based on the foreign key relation.
So this is great, but how can we add this same logic
inside the get all that we have right here?
For that we will have to add a logic.
But I want to show you one more thing.
Right now we only have category that we want to include.
But if you had to include more properties,
you can add multiple include statements.
And rather than category, if this was something else,
you can include that as well.
So include can have multiple variables like category,
category ID, maybe you have cover type
or something else that could also be included.
We want to make sure that our repository
can handle that scenario.
For that what I will do is we can have a nullable.
Include properties.
And that will be string.
Now right here it is a link operator.
When we are saying it will be a string, what do we expect?
Basically we are saying that if someone gives us
category or category ID, based on that
we can build to include properties.
Now category ID is just an ID, so things will not work.
So for an example I am saying
let's say there are two things,
category and cover type, that a user has to include.
So if in include properties they provide that
with a comma separated string,
then we can add that in the include statement
when we are building the query here.
One thing that is very very important here
is this category must match exactly that you see right here.
If you use a lowercase C here, things will not work
because let's say if you try a lowercase
category you can see it is not working.
So it must match what you see
in the include statement that is working here.
And that is exactly what you should pass
in the string parameter right here.
Let me add this inside the interface as well.
We have the interface repository interface.
Get all.
And when we are getting something,
at that point also we want to include properties.
So we will add that logic, input the places.
Then we need the actual logic of adding that.
Basically we will first check here
if include properties is not null.
In that case, well rather than not here
I will rather check string is null or empty.
So if it is not null and empty, we will add a not sign.
Then we want to include properties.
Like what we see on the top right here.
But we will be receiving them as comma separated values.
So we will have to split them.
We will have a for each and I will say include.
Prop in, include properties.split.
And we will split them by a new character.
Which will be comma.
And here I will say string, split options.
Dot remove empty entries.
So if any entry is empty it will remove those.
And let me split this in a separate line.
So it is easier to read and understand.
Then where we have the query we will say query is equal
to query.include, and we want to include
the include prop that we are splitting.
If there is only one, then also it will work.
But we have made sure that if there are more
than one include properties we can add them
as a comma separated list and our repository
is dynamic to handle that.
Same logic that we have in get all.
We will add that to get as well.
So let me add that here.
And we will add the include properties.
Perfect.
We have added the include properties
in both get and get all repository.
With that configured, let me close everything.
Open the product controller.
We do not need anything else here.
And when we are getting all,
we can define the include properties.
We want to include category.
Now right now I am intentionally adding a lowercase
because I want to show you this will not work.
So let me run the application
with a lowercase category and see what happens.
We go to product here and we get
an exception with the include properties.
You can see unable to find navigation category
in the string based include path category.
That is because it does not find that navigation property.
If you correct that case here and run it, it should work.
Perfect, no exception this time.
And if you examine the result here,
category is populated and we have the category name.
So finally we can display that in the absurd.
In the index here.
Let me go to the view.
Where we have the category.
We can navigate them by obj.category.name.
Save that and continue.
And perfect.
Our category is being populated
and everything is working as expected.
But with that we have learned an important concept
in entity framework which is how to populate
the navigation property using .include.