Instructor: We are using a table layout
with the product list here.
But what if we want something fancy with the product?
Like what if we want search functionality
in the table, we want pagination,
we want sorting, and all of those basic feature.
Rather than implementing all of that,
we have third party plugins that we can use
like we have data tables.net where you can see it comes
with all of those basic functionalities
and getting started is super simple.
First thing that we have to do is include the CSS
and JavaScript file.
So let's do that.
We go back, stop the application here,
open underscore layout in views
and we will be adding the CSS file first.
Link REL is equal to style sheet href.
Let me paste what we copied here and that looks good.
Scroll down.
We need a script tag.
Copy and paste it one more time here.
And we need the SRC, let me go back here.
Copy the CDN, paste it right here.
Perfect, both of those steps are done.
And last step here is initialize the data table.
In order to see that, let me click on get started here
and we will be using Ajax call
to load all the data.
Inside here, you can see we have a basic Java script
where it is looking for an API endpoint to load that data.
Now you might be thinking that will I
have to add an API for this?
Of course not.
When you are working with .net and if you
create an MVC project, API support is already added
in the controller.
So whatever we were doing in index,
we will have to do that in the API call.
So we can just copy this line here and let me scroll down
at the end right here.
I will add a section or rather a region,
call that API calls, have an end region.
Within here, let me create an HTTP get request.
In there we will say public i action wizard get all
and that is already supported because we
are using MVC architecture.
There, let me paste the code that we copied here
and the product list here.
We basically have to return back,
so we can say return Json here
and we will return a new object.
So we will say new data is equal to OBJ product list.
Simple as that.
Now how do you test that?
Let me run the application here
and we do not need the IT in the parameter.
Let me remove that with get all.
Run that one more time.
Now we need to navigate to the controller and endpoint.
It is inside admin, product, and name is get all.
If I type that, you can see it retrieves the data here
and we have all the product.
So our API is up and running in less
than one minute because we are using MVC project
and it has the support for API.
So perfect, our API endpoint is functional.
Now we need to call that API
in an Ajax request and load our data table.
Let me do that in the next video.