Instructor: When you are working with data tables,
you have to be careful about one thing.
Number of columns that we have
in product.js here cannot exceed the number of
table header or DH that we have
inside the CSS HTML.
Right now you can see we have six columns right here
in product.js.
We have five.
If you have less columns than the (indistinct)header,
that is okay.
But if I add more columns here
let me copy and paste that once again.
And if I go back here, that is also functional.
It populated the same data here.
But if I copy that one more time,
now we have seven columns right here,
and we have six columns in the view.
If I save that, you can see it does not work in the console.
We have an error right here.
So always remember that columns must match.
One column that I have left here is for
edit and delete buttons.
So basically we should only have five columns
in product.js.
Let me revert back the change here.
If you want to add one more column here,
you will also have to add a th element right here.