Instructor: Now we need to add the delete logic.
So where we have the get all in product controller
let me copy that, paste it one more time here
and let me call that HttpDelete here.
We will name this as delete.
When we are deleting, we need the ID.
Based on the ID here, we will retrieve our product
and let me store that to be product to be deleted
rather than OBJ.
If product to be deleted is null
in that case I will return Json
where in the object I will say success is false
and message error while deleting.
But if that is valid, then before we delete the product
we need to remove its image as well.
So we will say variable old image path is equal to,
and if I go to absurd where I was combining
the path, that logic, I can copy this
and we will paste that right here.
Perfect. So we will delete the old path here.
We need the wwwRootPath,
which we can get from webHostenvironment.WebRootPath.
Image URL is inside product to be deleted, .ImageUrl.
Let me break this out here. Perfect.
So we delete the image here.
Next we will say unitOfWork.product.remove.
We want to remove the product to be deleted
and underscore unit of work.save.
Finally, where we have to return the Json here,
we will say success is true and message delete successful.
Let me stop the changes.
We have an error, let me see what that is.
It says delete already exist.
Let me see where that is.
And yes, of course we need to remove
the existing delete functionality that we have
and I will also remove the delete view in area.
We have the delete.
Let's remove that.
With that, let me add a debunking point here
and go to product.js.
Now there, if I copy this, paste it here rather than absurd.
If I say delete here and I can just pass forward slash I'd.
Let me run and show you what happens.
We go to product here.
We have the fake product here.
If I hit delete here, the EPA will not be invoked
because that EPA has HttpDelete there.
But if I remove that HttpDelete, let's see what happens.
We go to product and the delete should work now.
Perfect. It hits our breakpoint.
It will remove the image
and it will also delete the product.
If I continue here, perfect.
It says success is true and message delete successful.
If I go back here, that product no longer exists
so our EPA is actually being invoked and it returns Json.
But typically what happens is when we are deleting,
we like a confirmation.
For that we will be using SweetAlert.
And let me show you how to add that
to our project in the next video.