I hope you were able to complete the assignment.
Now when we have to use SQL Server.
First thing that we need here are the NuGet packages and we can do that in multiple ways.
We already have those NuGet packages in the bulky web project, which is MVC.
So if I right click on the solution here and select Manage NuGet packages for solution, well you can
notice here that Dotnet eight Preview two has been released, but we will continue with the first preview
that we have.
That's okay.
But what I want to tell you here is on the right side, you can see on bulky Web the version is installed.
If you select the other project as well, then it will install the same version inside the razor project
as well.
So if I install that, accept this.
Perfect.
That package is installed inside the razor project as well.
Now you can see that right here.
The other packages here are not installed in the razor project.
So we can install them using the same method, but we can do something better.
We know that we want the same packages that are in the web project so we can right click, edit the
project file and I can copy all of the NuGet packages.
We have the version here as well.
Close that and I will open the project file for Razor page.
Inside there we only have one.
We will remove that and paste everything that we copied from the MVC project.
What that will do is it will automatically install all of the NuGet packages.
Let me show that right here so you can see.
Everything is done automatically and we do not have to do much things.
This is another way of working with NuGet packages because if you directly add in the project file,
that is the ultimate location where a NuGet package is added and from there it will be installed and
available in your project.
Our packages are installed now.
we need to work on adding the application DB context here.
So let me add that.
And then we can go to the data application.
DB Context, copy everything and paste it right here.
Now I hope you did not copy and paste everything and you manually typed that because you have to learn
on how to seed the data, how to overwrite the on model, creating, how to add DB set and so on.
When we add the using statement, do not add reference to bulky web we need from the current project
which is bulky web razor.
Perfect DB Context looks good.
Next, we need Program.cs.
There we have to add the connection string.
Copy this line.
Close that.
Go to program.cs here and we will add that we will add the using statement as well.
And perfect.
That looks good.
Finally, the last thing that we have to do is add migration and create the tables.
For that, we will go to tools package manager console.
And here you have to be careful about one thing.
Previously we only had one project, so the default project was bulky web, but now we want to add migrations
and everything on the Razor project.
So you have to select that and you will say add migration, add category to DB.
Perfect.
If you take a look at the migration, it is adding category and it is inserting data.
Looks good.
Let me update the database.
Perfect.
That is done as well.
If we go back to SQL Server, we should have a new database which is bulky razor we should have
the categories table with three categories.
So entity framework code has been set up in our project and you can see how fast it is to get started
with EF core in.
.Net application.