Instructor: Now we want to work on the same
functionalities that we have
in the M V C project with category.
In the web project or the M V C project,
we had controller, but that is not something
that we have when we work with razor pages.
There we have the pages
and in there we have to organize things.
So what we will do is create a new folder for category
and inside there for a list of all the categories,
I will create a new razor page.
We don't have view here, we have razor pages.
When we say a razor page, we have the empty razor page.
We will get started with that.
The index page, we can call that
for categories where we are listing all the categories.
But I have one small suggestion, so let me close this.
And where we have the category,
if you know in model we have the same name.
If you want to use the same name,
you can go ahead and do that, but then you will
have to add the complete using statements many times.
In order to avoid that,
I will rename this to be categories.
That way we do not have to be explicit.
Then in categories, we will add the razor page, MT one.
We want to start fresh
and let me call that Index dot CS HDML.
Now in this page you notice something different
than when we added a view in M V C.
So again, in M V C, I use the term view.
In razor pages, we have the razor page
and the CS file will be page model.
That will be the terminology that I will be using.
So in razor page, we have
at model that is already being defined
and if you examine the path,
that is the exact file that we have in the CS file.
If you think about that in the M V C, we had to define that.
In razor pages, it already creates that CS file and
adds that in the add statement.
And before that we have the ad page that defines
that this will be a razor page.
We do not need this here, we can just have an H one
and we can say category list like that.
With that one line, let me run the razor project.
We will have the startup project as a razor
throughout this section.
So do that and we will run the project.
And perfect.
Now how will we route to the new page that we added?
That is inside categories,
so routing is pretty straightforward.
Whatever is the location inside the pages folder,
that will be the route.
So categories, and then index.
And we have the category list.
Now index is always optional, so if you remove that
it will load the same page.
But with razor pages, we do not have the complex routing
of adding controller action method,
and then the route parameters.
Razor pages has very straightforward routing.
With that configured, let me continue from the next video.