-: Now, we have the Category List here
but we need to load all the categories
from database and display them.
How will we do that when we are working with controller?
Let me move back to the old application here.
We used to get ApplicationDbContext
using dependency injection
and then we were easily able to retrieve all the categories.
It will be same when we are working
with the Razor project as well.
In the Razor project, in the cs file, which is PageModel,
here we will have the constructor.
First, we will have a private readonly ApplicationDbContext.
Let me call that _db
and ctor, tap tap, for the constructor here
and we will get ApplicationDbContext.
Assign that to the local variable.
After that, let me create a property,
which will be List of Category,
and that will hold all the categories.
I will call that CategoryList here
and we need to populate this using Entity Framework Core.
So, CategoryList is equal to _db.Categories.ToList.
That is exactly what we were doing in the controller,
but now, we have to do that in the OnGet handler.
Now, when we have the OnGet and Post handler,
we do not have to write return View.
You can see the return type is void here
because whatever we are setting here in the model,
it is easily accessible
because that is the model that we have.
So, when we return back,
we do not have to write anything else.
It will automatically bind everything.
So, now all we have to do is
on the Index Razor Page here,
directly access that model and display all the categories.
View, we can copy that from Views.
We have the Category Index.
Copy that and make sure to close this file
because the names are the same.
So, you might get confused
and end up working on a different file.
So, if you have to copy,
copy that, minimize it, and close the file.
I will paste all the code that we copied right here
and we do not need the model anymore.
Let's remove that.
Then, we have to worry about the tag helpers.
Previously, we had the tag helpers for controller and action
but with Razor Pages we have asp-page.
Using asp-page,
we can define the route where we have to go
when we create a category
that will be inside Categories/.
We will create Razor Page with the name of Create.
We do not have action there.
We have to give the complete route like this.
Now, if you are not case sensitive, that's okay here.
So, let me add that.
We scroll down, we have the table here,
but where we have the Model,
we do not have the category list.
We have that inside Model that will be a property
with the name of CategoryList.
So, if I go back, rather than Model directly in there,
we will have CategoryList
because model is the complete IndexModel.
Inside there, we have CategoryList
and that can be easily accessed like here.
We need to change the route here.
This will be asp-page
and it will be Category/edit.
Remove the action and where we have to pass the id,
asp-route is still valid
if you are working with Razor Pages.
So, when we add it, if we have to pass the id,
we can pass asp-route-id and that will work.
So, copy this asp-page and paste that for delete.
This will be delete.
We will still pass the id.
That needs to be edited and deleted.
Everything else stays the same.
With that configured,
let me run the project and see if that works.
We forgot one thing here.
Let me go back while it is running.
Inside the _Layout, we have to add categories.
So, copy this li here.
You can see we have the asp-page here.
That will go to categories/index
and we'll display Category here.
Let me see how that looks here.
We have Category.
Click that.
And perfect.
Right now, we are not using any Bootswatch theme.
So, these are the default classes
but you can see everything is working with Razor Pages
and we have our Index Page that is functional.
If you want to add the Bootstrap Icons here,
you can do that.
But, I think this looks good
for the category list right now.
Before I end the video,
if I go back and,
in the cshtml rather than OnGet here,
if this was only Get,
you will notice things will not work
because that On is required.
If I click on Category, you can see things are not working.
So, when we have a Get action method inside Razor Pages,
it must match the exact name, OnGet,
or else it will not work.