Narrator: Now in our project, let me add authorization
in all the correct places, like in the admin controller.
I will bring back the authorized keyword there
in category.
We have company.
Order is authorized
and role admin for the product controller.
On top of that, if you remember in the underscored layout
of master page, we had the role of admin.
So only if a user is admin,
then they will be able to perform current operation
on the content management right here.
So we will bring that back as well.
With that, if I run the application,
when the application starts
they will not see anything with content management.
So for fact, they see manage order, they have home,
and they can see the shopping cart.
If a admin user logs in here,
then they will be able to see content management
and that works as expected.
So that looks good for authorization in our website.
Let me continue from the next video.