Instructor: Now, in the application
where we have the shopping cart,
if a user adds item to the shopping cart,
we want to display count
of the items inside the shopping cart.
Now typically when we were working
with traditional .NET application,
we had something called a session.
We have sessions in .NET Core as well,
but in the default project, it is not added by default.
We have to configure our application to add session,
and whenever we have to do some configuration,
we do that in the program.cs file.
So right there where we have the builder.services,
we will have to add two things here.
First we have to add something
called as distributed memory cache,
and then we have to add session.
When we add session, we can configure multiple properties.
I am adding three options right here.
So that is adding session to the services,
but we also have to add session in our request pipeline.
So after authorization, we will say app.useSession,
and with that our application is configured now
to use session.
But then the main question is how do we add session
in the project?
Well,
to do that, first I do not like using magic string,
so let me add a constant for session.
I will call that public constant sessionCart,
and I will give it a value of session shopping cart.
When we work with session, it is basically a key value,
so we are just giving a unique key name,
that way we can access that
or set our session in the project.
Next question that you have to ask
is where will we set the session?
First when we are adding any item
to the cart that is inside home controller,
we have the details.
Right here we are adding new items to the cart.
Whenever we are adding new item to the shopping cart,
we will be adding that value to session.
So in order to set that it is pretty simple.
We have http context, on there we will say session.setInt32.
And when we are setting that, we need a key and a value.
Now rather than using magic strings,
we have added a constant for the key name,
which is inside static detail, dot sessionCart,
and what will be the value.
Now for the value, we have to go to the database
and get all of the shopping cart for that user ID.
Right here we are getting that
for user ID as well as product ID,
but we basically have to get that for user ID.
So I can copy and paste it here.
And let me add the closing bracket there.
On there we will call the count,
and that will basically be the count
of distinct items that the logged in user has.
So that way we are setting our session
of integer right here.
When you work with .NET Core,
you have setInt and setString.
Those are available by default.
But if you want a custom implementation
like setting a custom object,
you can also do that, but that requires some configuration.
But for our case, the setInt is working as expected.
Now on the layout page where we have the shopping cart,
we want to display this count that is there in our session.
So we want to access session in underscore layout.
If you try to access HTTP context in underscore layout,
it will not work.
When you are in the view, if you want something,
you have to explicitly inject that.
And to inject the iHTTP context accessor,
we first have to add a using statement,
Microsoft.ASPNetCore.HTTP.
Once you do that, then we can inject iHTTP context accessor,
and I will call it the same HTTP context accessor.
Using that context accessor,
we can access the shopping cart session,
we can access the shopping cart session.
Let me scroll down, we have that right here.
And right here, let me add an if condition,
we will say if HTTP context accessor.HTTP context.session.
And there before we were using the setInt32.
But now we want to retrieve. So we will use getInt32.
And the key name is inside SD.sessionCart.
If that is not null, in that case,
we want to display zero.
If that is not null,
then we want to retrieve the value and display that.
So right here with nbsp, we can retrieve that value
and display that in a round bracket.
So HTTP context accessor. HTTP context.session.getInt32.
And we will say SD.sessionCart.
Now in the else part here,
I can basically copy and paste this again.
And we will display zero.
With that configured,
let me run the application and see if that works.
We have zero right now. Let me log in to test admin.
And let me try to add an item to the shopping cart.
We have an exception here. Let me see what that is.
Object reference not set to instance of an object.
Well, let me examine what is going on there.
And I believe this is an issue
because we are doing that before the unitOfWork.save.
So let me cut that and save it first.
That way the record is inside there.
And I will also have to add save inside update.
So do not forget that. And let me run that once again.
I believe there were no items there.
Because of that it was throwing the exception.
Let me try to add the item once again.
Count of two, add to cart.
And perfect.
As soon as we select add to cart,
you can see two items are being displayed.
But that is not exactly right.
Because if you go back here to the home,
and if you try to add the same item again,
the count remains too.
We want the count here to be distinct items
and not anything else.
The reason it is displaying two here is we have some bug.
And let me show that
where we have that it is somewhere right here.
Try to find out what is that bug.
Because of that, rather than displaying one here,
it is displaying two records.
To give you one more example here,
if I add more items to the cart here, let me do that.
You can see now it is updated to five.
Something fishy is going on.
And try to find out what is going on here.
Okay, I hope you were able to figure that out.
The reason when we are saying count here,
it is actually getting the value of count.
If I go to shopping cart, you can see the count is five.
And that is why it is displaying five right there.
What we need to do here is first bug is rather than get,
we want to get all and on there if we take count,
then it will get count of IEnumerable.
I will have to add a function there. And that looks good.
Previously, we were only getting one shopping cart,
but we needed to get all the shopping cart,
and then the count right there.
So with that configured, let me restart the application.
Now the initial session here is not getting set,
we will handle that in the upcoming video.
But if I add a new item here,
you will see the correct count and that is three.
If we navigate there, we have three distinct items.
So that looks good for our shopping cart.
Let me continue from the next video.