Instructor: Next thing that I want to handle is
when a customer lands on the homepage,
if they are already logged in,
then we want to retrieve their session rather
than displaying them zero.
And also when we log out,
we have to clear that session.
First, let me handle the other scenario
on the home controller index page.
We can get the user ID of the logged in user.
So right here we can get the user ID
but value could be null here.
So let me get claim here
and we will check if claim.Value is null.
Well, in this case I believe claim will be null.
So if that is not null, that means a user is logged in.
So in that case, we can get the session and set it,
copy that, paste it right here.
User ID will be inside claim.Value.
Let me add a debugging point here and see if that works.
We log in here and claim is null, so we continue.
That is good.
Next, let me log in here.
Test admin.
And now we have the claim populated.
It retrieves that and perfect.
It adds that to our session.
Great.
So with that, when a user now logs in,
they will be able to see their shopping cart count
inside the navigation.
But now when a user logs out, we need to clear the session.
And also if someone removes the item here,
we need to decrement.
Let me navigate to the cart first.
We will go back to the application
and where we have the cart controller,
let me close all the tabs here.
Inside the cart controller, we have action method.
Let me scroll down, plus, minus and perfect.
We need these too.
After we hit the save here,
we can set httpContext.Session.SetInt32.
The constant name is SD.SessionCart.
And value.
We will have to get that
from unitOfWork.ShoppingCart.GetAll.
And u goes to u.Application.
User ID is equal, equal to.
We have the cartFromDB
but that is actually removed right here.
So we will have to do something fancy.
Let me get that from cart.db.ApplicationUserId
and we will get the count on there.
But at this point, that cart will be removed.
Now right here, right here,
when we try to access cartFromDB,
we have already removed that.
So I can cut this and paste it before the unitOfWork.Save.
And there, where we have the count,
let me reduce that by one
because in the next line, we will be removing that record.
Let me copy this and I will paste that
for the remove right here as well.
And perfect, cartFromDB.
Let me see if that is what I'm using here.
Yes, that looks good.
Break this out in different line here.
And let me add this before the remove statement.
Perfect, that looks good.
Let me rebuild here and try to remove an item.
We need to first log in here.
Let me do that.
We have three items here
and right now when you try to delete,
you will see something odd.
Let me try to delete any one record here.
And you see we have an exception.
The exception is not that clear
but it does give some idea on what is going on.
Now this is a little bit tricky
but to give you one hint here, the issue is
because in repository we have something we are tracking
and as no tracking.
So try to find out and figure out what exactly is wrong
and why you are seeing this error message.
Main reason why I let you figure out what the issue is is
because that is how your real world projects will work.
When you are working, you will run into exception
and you will have to figure out on what is going on.
So try to Google and see if you can come up with a solution.
If not, let me continue from the next video.