Instructor: I hope you are able to figure out
what exactly is going on here,
but by the error message here, you can see
that there is something with the tracking that is going on
and we know when we are getting things,
by default we are not tracking them.
So, what happens in the cart controller in remove
when we are getting the card from DB in get
we are not tracking that entity.
When we use the remove,
that entity is no longer tracked by EF core
and because of that you are seeing that error message.
In order to solve that, all you have to do here
is you have to set the track property to be true.
With that, it'll be able to remove that successfully.
Now we are removing that inside here as well.
So let me see where we have the remove.
I will have to add the track entity to be true,
and let me see if that works.
We will have to log in here as the test admin.
Let me do that.
And we have three items.
Now if I try to remove, you can see it is working
as expected and the cart is also being updated.
If I click minus here, we only have count of one
so it should reduce that to one and perfect.
That worked.
These are the small things that you will get familiar
as you build more and more applications
and as you gain more exposure in M V C.
But one last thing that we have to do is
when we log out here,
we have to clear our session.
So let me do that in the project where we have the files.
Let me search for lock out here
and we have the code behind right there.
When we are signing out
we will set http context
dot session dot set in 32
or rather we can just clear the session.
That will also work if a user is logged out.
Let me restart the application and see if that works.
We have zero, let me log in here.
We have two.
If I log out.
Perfect.
Back to zero.
So with that, our session is looking good.
Let me continue from the next video.