Instructor: Right now,
one thing that we have to do in a hacky way
is whenever a user logs in and we land on the HOME page,
we are getting the session here and we are setting that.
But what if we do not want that hacky way?
What if we want the page model in _layout
where it is getting the shopping cart,
it should automatically check all of that,
and if it does not have a value,
it should go to the database
and find out the count on its own?
So here, we are talking about having a page model
or rather a backend file for _layout.
Now, that is not technically possible with _layout,
but we have something special
which can accomplish the same functionality,
and that is view component.
Now, typically, I explain what something is
before we program,
but view component is one of those things
where we have some configuration that we have to do,
but after that is done, everything will come together.
It is one of the advanced concepts in MVC,
so make sure to follow along
because there is some syntax that you have to follow.
Now, view component is exactly similar to a partial view.
But the difference here is your model or partial view
will have a page model or a code behind file
where you can do some programmings for your UI.
But if you are working with partial view,
you do not have a page model.
In order to get started,
where we have our main web project here,
inside there, I will create a new folder,
and I will have to stop the application, of course,
and we will rename that to be ViewComponents.
Inside that folder, we will be adding our view components
which will basically be a Class file.
Now, we can call this anything we want
like in our case it is a shopping cart count,
so we can call it ShoppingCart.
But after that file,
we have to append a special word which is ViewComponent,
and then we will add .cs.
That is a keyword that is needed for view component.
So let me add that.
Along with that, other thing that we have to do
is this particular view component
must inherit from ViewComponent.
And, again, this is ViewComponent, not ViewComponents.
We have to add that using statement.
Now, this will be the backend file for our view component,
so we need to think about what we want to do here.
We basically have to go to the shopping cart database
and get the shopping cart for a logged-in user.
So we need to inject unitOfWork,
and we can do that using dependency injection.
Then inside here, we will create a method that will handle
the backend functionality for our ShoppingCartViewComponent.
It will return async Task, I can call it IActionResult,
but we know it will be a view component,
so we can directly say IViewComponentResult.
That will be the return type.
Now, the name of the function will be InvokeAsync,
and that is what will be used
when we invoke the view component
which we will see in the upcoming videos.
So name of the method here is InvokeAsync,
and there, we need to retrieve the userId
of the logged-in user.
Let me go and open the Areas, Controller.
We have Customer, HomeController.
Let me copy this code right here. Cut that from the index.
Paste it right here.
Now, right here, if the claim is not null,
we are getting the session and setting that.
Else, if the claim is null,
we can directly clear the session right here,
so HttpContext.Session.Clear.
And that way, we do not have to do that in the Logout,
so I can remove that as well.
Inside the Logout where we added the functionality,
we no longer require that.
Perfect. That looks good.
Now, what we want to return here
is the actual count to our view.
So here, we will say return back to the View,
and we need the count
that is inside HttpContext.Session.GetInt32
SD.SessionCart.
When we clear everything, it will be zero,
so we can return back that integer value.
So now you can think
about we are returning something to the View,
and the model is an integer.
That looks good.
But where will we create the view of this ViewComponent?
Before we add that file,
I can make this code a little more elegant.
Right here, I can check if HttpContext.Session.GetInt32
SD.SessionCart,
if that is not null,
then basically we have a session that is loaded.
We do not have to go to database, so we can return that.
So return View, and we can return back that entity.
But if that is null,
only then we have to retrieve that item.
So rather than that, let me make it if it is null,
then we will set the session here.
Else, we do not want to set our session.
We will directly return whatever is set in our session.
So, basically, the code behind for ViewComponent looks good.
Let me add the frontend view in the next video.