Instructor: We have created the ViewComponent,
but we have to create view for our ViewComponent.
Now that view you cannot create anywhere you like.
There is a certain format that you must follow,
and that will be inside the Shared folder.
So in Shared folder, we will have to create a new folder
with the name of Components.
And in that folder, we will have to create another folder
with the name of our ViewComponent, which is ShoppingCart.
The name must exactly match.
Inside that ShoppingCart folder,
we will be creating a new view.
It will be an empty view with the name of Default.cshtml.
This will basically be the view for our ViewComponent.
Now you can see when we are returning back,
it is an integer.
So here the model will be an integer.
And then what do we want to display here?
Well, if we go to _Layout where we have the ShoppingCart,
we want that icon there,
and I want to display the count right here.
So that will be the model.
That looks good for the view of ViewComponent.
Now this ShoppingCart ViewComponent,
we want to add that in _Layout right here.
To keep things simple,
we do not need the if, else condition anymore.
And inside the anchor tag right here, we will say await.
And we want to inject the component.
So we have Component.InvokeAsync.
And there we have to write the component name,
which is ShoppingCart.
And with that, the ViewComponent
will automatically be injected.
Let me run the application and see if everything works.
If you remember now, on the homepage,
we no longer have the count to retrieve our session.
We have an error here, and let me see,
it is unable to find the view.
It should be in Components.
Whoops, we have a spelling mistake, and that will not work.
It must exactly match that.
So this will be Components.
With that, let me restart here.
And perfect, that works.
I have an extra semicolon, that is not needed here,
let me remove that one.
I have an extra semicolon here,
that is not needed, and perfect.
If you still see the error message
that you were seeing before,
make sure to clean the solution and build it once again.
But now we have 0 here.
If I log in as admin, we have 2,
and if I log out, it will be set to 0, perfect.
So you can see everything is working
as expected with our ViewComponent.
Let me log in as a company and add few items to the cart
and make sure that everything is working.
Perfect, that looks good.
With that in place, let me continue from the next video.