Instructor: Now we need to add
more properties to external login.
So let me do that.
That is inside account.
If I go back to the code here,
let me close all the tabs here,
stop the application and whoops, let me align that again.
We will search for external.
We have the external login.
We do not want to go inside manage.
We want the one inside account, which is external login,
and we have the page model.
So then let me also open the register that we have
where we have already configured more properties.
I will open both of them and perfect.
In the page model where we have the input model
we added all of these properties.
Let me copy that, go to the external login
and I will add them right there.
In order to keep things simple,
if someone is using external login
their role will be defaulted to customer
and they will not be able to get company, employee or admin.
We will keep things super simple with that requirement.
Then if we scroll down here
where we have the on post confirmation async,
it is creating that user.
But before that, let me scroll up
and here we have the on get callback async.
There, if you notice, it is populating input model
and it is getting email from info.principle,
which will be from Facebook.
Similar to that, Facebook will also have name of the user,
so we can copy and get the claim types of name
and we will populate name of the user
when we were on the registration page.
After that we have the on post confirmation async.
Right there we are setting the input.email.
On top of that, we will also set the other properties,
but if you try that, they do not exist on identity user,
so create user press F12.
We will modify that to be application user
and that will solve our problem.
So let me add that here and perfect, all the errors go away.
Now we are creating an application user.
Final thing, when the result is successful,
we want to await _user manager.add to roll async.
We want to add user.role of SD.customer.
With that, configured page model is looking great.
Let me work on external.cshtml.
There we have email.
Copy that and paste it six more times here
and then let me modify name.
We have that.
After name, let me add a phone number.
I will modify the placeholder as well.
Perfect.
Then we have the street address, copy and paste that.
We have city, state and postal code.
Perfect.
That looks good.
Let me modify this thing here.
We will have state and I believe that looks good.
Let me start the application
and try to register using Facebook.
Last time when we tried that,
we did not hit the register button.
Because of that we will be able to continue and perfect.
You can see it retrieves name as well as email
and that is looking great.
Now, if you enter everything else here
and submit the register pattern,
it will log you in automatically.
Perfect.
You can see that's working.
If you click on the hello here, the password does not exist
because we are using external login,
but if we want along with external login
we can add a password as well.
In the external logins here
you can see Facebook is already registered
and that looks good.
Now with that configured, next time when I have to log in,
if I go on the login page, I have Facebook here.
If I select that, it'll automatically sign me in.
So perfect.
You can see how easy and convenient it was.
One thing that I will change is on the register.
Let me bring this to the center.
So let me open the register.cshtml,
scroll down here where we have the div here.
Let me add padding three and text center.
I will also remove this use another service.
Let me go back.
This got misaligned here.
And I want to open login as well.
We have login.
Scroll down.
We do not need this.
Adding three, text center.
Save that and let me go back here.
Perfect, that looks much better.
Log in.
Perfect.
So with that,
external logins have been configured in our application.