-: Now, let's say our application is done
and we are publishing it online.
There, on the signup or the register page,
we do not want them to select a role
because admin, employee cannot be created
by anyone that browses the website.
Also, based on the requirement,
a company account can only be created or registered
by an admin or an employee account.
So what we want to do is the same register page,
we want to add that in the content management
when an admin logs in.
So let me switch back here,
and let me go to register.
Well first, let me close everything,
and let me open underscore layout.
Inside there, in content management, right here,
I will add one more link.
Copy and paste that.
The area will be identity area,
but that is not a controller,
it is a Razor page,
so we have to use ESP page tag helper,
and we want to navigate to register,
which is inside account, and there we have register.
I will call that create user.
So based on that, if we go back,
we have the basic register page here.
One condition that I will add is the dropdown
will only be visible if the role is admin.
So let me go to register here,
and where we have that dropdown?
Right here.
We will add if the role is admin,
only then we will display both company,
as well as the role dropdown.
If I save this here and go back. Perfect.
Now on the register page,
user can no longer select a role.
That is the ideal situation in a production application.
But now, let me log in as an admin here,
and if I go to content management,
there is a tab to create a user.
Perfect.
This time we have the role that is working
because it knows that the logged in user
is an admin user.
To be explicit, rather than register here,
let me display register an admin portal.
If the role is admin, so let me copy this.
We can add an if condition.
If user dot is in role SD dot admin,
then we want to display an h2
where we will display register admin portal.
In the else part,
we will keep things as it is.
Perfect. If I go back, great.
We have admin portal.
When admin is creating an account for someone else,
we do not want this Facebook, so I will hide that as well.
Where is that?
Right here, I believe.
Yep. This is the div.
So if user dot is enrolled SD dot admin,
basically we want if the user is not an admin,
then we want to display this.
So if I save that, perfect, that also goes away.
Now the final changes, if we register for a user,
it typically signs me in with the new user.
Let me show that.
If I am registering an employee,
let me change that to be employee one, register.
You will notice it signs out the admin
and signs in the employee.
We do not want that when an admin is registering
for an account.
We have to modify that in the register page model.
Let me go to the post-action, right here.
If I scroll down, we have the if else condition,
and then let me see where it is signing in.
It signs in right here.
So, in there, we can add an if condition
that if a user is already in role of admin,
that means that user is signed in
and admin is creating that account.
If that is the case, then we do not want to sign in.
Else we want to sign in the user.
So cut and paste it right here
and in the if condition, we can add a temp data,
new user created successfully.
So, perfect. That looks good.
Let me go back, and try that one more time.
We will have to log out and log in as admin again.
Let me do that
and let me try to create a user.
We have dummy information.
Let me hit register, and perfect.
It did not sign in the user
and we get the toaster notification.
So perfect.
That looks good for creating a new user from the admin side.