Instructor: Now let me show you one small bug.
If we log in as a customer here
and we have two items in the cart,
let me place order.
When we hit the pay button
you will notice the order is placed
but the cart here is not getting cleared.
Well, the cart is actually clear
but we are not clearing the session.
So let me do that real quick.
That is inside the CartController.
We have OrderConfirmation.
Let me look that up right here.
Once everything is done here
we can set HttpContext.Session.Clear.
Now, I know that I only have one session in the application.
That is why I am clearing that.
But typically you will empty the session
based on the key name.
But this will work for our situation.
And with that, if you try it once again, it should work.
And I believe with that, everything looks good.