Instructor: Now we have a repository
and we have an interface I repository.
We need our category to implement that repository.
So how do we do that?
In the I repository,
first, I will create a new interface
that will be
I
category
repository.
We will make this a public interface,
and that interface
will implement the I repository interface.
And this time when it implements the I repository,
we know what is the clause
on which we want the implementation for this repository.
That will be the category model where we want to
implement the interface.
That way, we are actually defining now
that when we need the implementation
for I category repository,
I want you to get the base functionality from repository.
What that will do is that we'll make sure we have all
of these base methods where entity will be category.
On top of that, if you remember,
we needed two more functionality
and those who are update and save methods.
So here we will have void update.
There, we will get the category and let me call that O B J
and we will also have a method to save the changes.
So this is the final category repository
interface that will implement the base functionality
that we have for all the repository.
Plus, we will have an update
and save for the category repository.
Now this is the interface we need to have its implementation
in the category repository.
Let me do that in the next video.