Instructor: We created the interface for
category repository.
Let me add the implementation for that in repository
create a class, which will be category repository.
It'll be a public class
and that will implement the I category repository.
If we press control dot here, it'll implement the interface.
But when you see it implements, it is actually
implementing the add get, get all, remove, remove range.
Those implementation we already have
in our generic repository.
So we do not want to add that again.
We want to use the base functionality.
Because of that, along with the I category repository,
we also want to implement the repository
with the class of category
and that will come before the interface like this.
With that, you can see it does not give the error message
or the I category repository or other methods.
But now we have one error here which says there
is no argument that corresponds
to the required parameter DB of a repository category.
Well, if we go to the repository implementation here,
we are saying that application DB context will be provided
to you when the object will be created.
Typically, when we use dependency injection,
they are automatically injected,
but in this case, we are creating on line 12.
So what we can say is, Hey, our category repository
we want to get that application DB context
using dependency injection
and then we can add a constructor, get that here.
And when we get this implementation,
we want to pass this implementation to all the base class.
So here we can say base db.
That way, whatever DB context we get here,
we will pass to the repository and the error goes away.
The two methods that we have here are pretty simple.
When we have to save, we save that on underscore db
dot save changes.
And when we have to update the category,
we will say underscore db dot categories start update
and we pass the object.
Perfect.
So now we have a category repository
that has been implemented.
How can we replace the application TP context
that we are using here with our actual repository?
Let me show you that in the next video.