-: The next item that I want to show you guys
you do not have to do that
but I want to show you how that could be done.
And what I am talking
about is sometimes you might face a situation
where you have to rename your project.
Like let's say where we have bulky
in the project names here
we want to modify all of them to be bulky book.
So how do we do that?
Well, it is pretty simple
but there are some things that we will have to modify first.
Wherever we have bulky here
we will change the project name to be bulky book here
and when I do that, we will see an error message.
Now typically you will not see this error message
but the reason I am seeing that is previously
I tried to rename that and because
of that a dot user already exists
at this location so far that what we will do is right click
and let me open that folder.
Inside there we have the bulky book web user.
We will delete that and then
if I try to rename here, it will work.
Now again, we don't want the bulky user
we want a bulky book web, and perfect.
So again, point number one
you will not see that error message
but I wanted to explicitly show that
because of that I introduced that user.
Then we have to rename all the project here.
Let me do that bulky book dot utility,
bulky book dot models
and we have bulky book dot data access.
Right now we have renamed only the project
but all the files like the controller here
you can see namespace is using bulky web.
In order to change all of that
we will do Ctrl-shift-F, find and replace.
Wherever we see bulky, we want to replace that
with bulky book and let me replace all.
Perfect, that works.
But now if you notice the controller
the namespace is modified here
but the repository and everything you can see it
is not detecting those project.
While sometimes it might happen
that it detects that project
it all depends on the dependencies here.
I am not able to open the dependencies
so let me restart visual studio.
Once I do that, it will reload everything and perfect.
Now in dependencies, when you examine project
it has bulky book dot data access
and it is working as expected
but you can see the models here is not
working, so if we examine the dependencies
in the data project
you can see the name here is messed up
because we renamed a few things.
Changing that is super simple, edit project file.
We will remove both the dependencies here
and we will add the project reference once again
to models and utility.
Perfect. With that, everything should be fixed here.
Let me build the solution and great, that worked.
Finally, let me run the application
and show you something odd, and great.
Right now you can see everything is working as expected
but for some of you the footer here
will not be properly designed.
And let me show you how it will look like.
If we go to views, shared underscored layout.
Let me break the CSS and perfect.
So this is exactly how it will look like.
You might be wondering that, hey,
what exactly is the CSS, and why is it present?
Well, what happens is that is automatically localization
and bundling that is being done with the CSS.
This has been introduced with .NET 6.
If you examine the underscored layout dot CS HTML
there is a .CSS file
and it is automatically scoped to underscored layout.
In order for this to be automatically added to CSS.
inside the link here
we need the HREF with the project name dot style dot CSS.
That is the CSS isolation that has been introduced
and I wanted to show that as well.
So once that matches, it automatically binds
that and you can see the footer is functional as expected,
but if you go to category here, things again will not work.
You can see the exception here
and that is because knowingly or unknowingly
we have also updated the database name to be bulky book.
This has to be bulky.
We did not intend to update the database name
with the Ctrl-shift-F when we updated.
It updated the database name as well.
Because of that, the connection was broken.
And when we modified back,
everything is working as expected.
So even though we have spent about 10 minutes on this video
we have learned some things important.
First, we saw the CSS isolation that comes
with the styling here.
And next we saw how can we modify the project name
and if we modify, some dependencies
gets broken, how can we fix that and make sure
our project is working as expected.
Now traditionally in a programming course,
you will not see this common issues
but when you are working with a real world project
I myself have encountered these issues
and that is why I wanted to spend some time
to give you exposure to these issues
and how to resolve them.
I hope this video was helpful
and let me continue with the course from the next video.