Instructor: Now we have to replace
the CategoryRepository with unitOfWork
in the web project.
First we will go to Program.cs
and we will have to register that to dependency injection.
We no longer require the CategoryRepository.
We need unitOfWork this time.
So perfect, we have unitOfWork
and then unitOfWork internally creates an object
or implementation of categoryRepository.
So here we will have unitOfWork
and let me call that _unitOfWork.
We will get that using dependency injection
and we will call that unitOfWork.
And right here, _unitOfWork is equal to unitOfWork.
Now, in unitOfWork we have Category
and there we have GetAll.
So previously when we were using the CategoryRepository
we did not have to access that.
But now in unitOfWork
we have to write which object we are working on
or which repository we are working on.
And then we can do everything like before.
I will copy this, paste it in all the places here.
And when we have the Save,
we do not have that in repository.
That is directly inside unitOfWork.
So we do not need the repository name.
Then in the edit here we will paste unitOfWork.Category.
Same goes for Update or Save.
We only have unitOfWork.
Perfect.
Let me modify in all the places.
And great, that looks good.
With that, let me run the project again
and see if everything works as expected.
Perfect. We are able to get all the category here.
Let me try to create one.
That works.
And DELETE is also functional.
So everything is working as expected,
but now we are using the unitOfWork
rather than directly the repository.
This gives us one advantage.
In unitOfWork we will have access
to all the repositories that we want,
but with that we have a disadvantage as well.
Like in the CategoryController
we only want CategoryRepository,
but in unitOfWork it will create implementation
of all the repositories that are registered,
like if we have product, if we have order, or shopping cart.
So there are pros and cons in both of them,
but personally speaking, I like the unitOfWork
implementation because it is much cleaner.
So with that configured,
let me continue from the next video.