Instructor: Now I hope you are comfortable
with controllers, actions.
And we are going to add one more hierarchy on top of that.
And the only reason I am showing that
is it is actually a great feature
if you have to divide few things in your project.
And that is called as area.
Typically when we work with routing, we have controller
and then action method.
But .NET team has also provided something special
to divide few things in different areas.
Like if you have a customer facing website and admin panel,
you can divide your project in those two areas.
Now how do you add that in a project?
We will right click on BulkyBookWeb here, add,
and we will click new scaffolded item.
Inside there you can see we have an MVC area.
Let's add that.
And we need to give area a name.
Let's say we have two section in our website.
One is for the admin section,
so let me add an area for admin.
It'll add the NuGet package and scaffold that area.
Another area that we will add will be the customer area
that will have the code related to customer
like homepage, details and much more.
Perfect.
Right here when we scaffold that,
you can see it adds a folder with the name of areas.
Then it has admin, which is the area that we added.
And inside there we have controllers, models and view.
So basically all the code that was previously
just in one location, we can now break that down
in different areas.
But when we add area, you can see the routing here
also changes.
In the scaffold.txt, it displays that, hey,
now you have to add areas in the routing as well.
So let me do that.
Let me copy this.
And we will go to our program.cs.
We have the controller route here.
Let me paste that here and we will add a forward slash.
So now we need to say what area should be invoked
by default, I will call that as customer.
We do not have that, so let me add that area as well.
And we will call that customer area, and let me add that.
Perfect, that looks good.
Now with that, we will have to move our controllers
inside the area folders.
Now in the area you can see we have folder
for data and models,
but we have moved that to the individual project
so we do not need these two here.
Let me delete that from both the areas.
We will only have controllers
and views inside the area Folder.
Category controller belongs to the admin functionality
so I will move that to the admin controller.
Home controller is a customer facing, so I will change that
and move that inside the customer area.
With that, our default route now is customer area,
home controller, and index action.
Now when I moved this, the namespace were also updated,
but if in your case you selected no
and you did not update the namespace,
make sure to update that namespace.
On top of that, how do you tell a controller
that this controller belongs to a specific area?
For that we have the area attribute here.
And we need to give the name
that category controller is inside the admin area
and home controller is inside customer area.
With that configured, let me run the project.
And things are not working.
The constraint customer inside the route option.
Let me see what the route option is.
And of course this will be equal to and not a colon.
Now we have a more user friendly exception,
which says the view was not found.
And that is indeed correct,
because we have moved the controller
but we did not move the corresponding views.
So let me go to the views here,
category, we will move that inside the admin here,
and home, move that to the customer views right here.
Once you move that and if you run the project,
things will still not work.
Where is the namespace, let me see.
It is inside the category views.
And yep, we have the model of category.
But how will we know where exactly is this category?
If you examined, we had that previously in the view imports.
We had dot models.
So along with that we also have to move the view start
and view import.
Both the files, we will paste it inside the view folder
in both the areas.
Perfect.
With that, let me run the project once again.
And perfect, the website comes up and everything looks good.
But when you click on home and privacy, that is working
because both of them are inside the customer area
but category is inside admin area.
When you click there, it tries to look
for category controller in customer, which does not exist.
So we have to modify that.
So what will happen is where we have the asp-controller
now we will also have to define asp-area.
So category is inside admin
and home controller is inside customer.
If you do not write the area, it'll look for that controller
in the existing area where the page is already residing.
That looks good.
Let me run the project and see if that works.
Perfect.
Admin, category, that works.
If you click create new category, it will work
because even if you have not defined the area
we are looking inside the same admin area that we are in.
So you can see create, back to list, edit,
everything is working
because we are working in the same area.
Now typically moving forward,
I will explicitly write all the areas, but for category
I think we are good to skip that
because we will always perform CRUD operations
from the category index page.
But perfect.
With that you can see how areas will add one more layer
in navigation.
And now when we are working with routing
we will define area first, then controller,
and then the action name.