Instructor: Now we have our category,
but we will be adding product
in the upcoming video
where we will be performing CRUD operations.
Now before I add that,
let me add a dropdown in the navigation.
So I will go to get Bootstrap.com.
And let me go to the documentation.
Search for nav bar.
We have a dropdown here.
That looks good.
Let me copy the li here for dropdown.
Copy that.
Go back to our code.
We have under code layout open here,
if not, you can open that.
And after the li elements,
let me paste that right here.
We go back to the ui,
we have hard reload and that kicks in,
but I see a blue color,
and I think that is because of the CSS.
Yep.
I do not need that.
I can comment that out.
Save that and Perfect.
Looks good.
The first one here, I want that to be category.
Cut the li and paste it right here.
We will have to rebuild.
Let me wait for that.
And perfect.
We have category,
but I did not see the color here.
We will have to make that text dark.
Save that here.
And perfect.
We have that, but rather than that,
I can just give it a class of dropdown item,
and let's see if that works.
Perfect.
Much better.
After that,
I will leave the divider here and let's see.
That looks good.
Rather than drop down here,
let me make it content management.
And Perfect.
That looks good.