Instructor: Now our application is complete,
and we want to deploy our application to Azure.
But before we do that, we need to think
about how the very first admin user will be created
in the production database.
On top of that, how will roles of the website be created.
What we did previously is we have a manual hack
inside the Register.
If I go Register.cs, right here we were checking
if the role did not exist, then we were creating it.
But when we deploy the application,
we do not want a hacky way, we want the correct way.
To do things in a correct way,
we have to create something called a DbInitializer.
And with migration, we want to create an admin account,
as well as roles in our website.
Now the question is, where do we add that DbInitializer?
We will do that in the DataAccess folder.
I will create a new folder.
Let me stop the application first.
And that will be DbInitializer.
Inside there, I will create a class file
with the name of DbInitializer,
and I will create an interface,
Show All Templates here,
and that will be IDbInitializer.
That will be a public interface,
and inside there I will add one method,
which is void Initialize.
That method will be responsible
for creating admin user and roles of our website.
So let me implement that right here,
IDbInitializer, implement interface,
and make that public.
Now let me implement this in the next video.