Instructor: Now we want
to implement the initialized method and the DB Initializer.
And there, I want to do three things.
First, I want to push migrations if they are not applied.
Next, create roles if they are not created.
Third, if the roles are not created,
then we will create admin user as well.
So basically, we will create roles and admin user,
along with pushing all the pending migration.
Now, when we are working with creating user
or assigning roles, we have always used user manager,
role manager and application DB context.
So, let me inject all three of them,
using dependency injection.
But once we do that,
then first we want to apply any pending migration.
That we can do inside a try-catch block here
and exception E, perfect.
Here, we will have an F condition
and on underscore DB, we have database,
where we have a helper function,
which is get pending migrations
and we will check if the count of pending migration
is greater than zero.
If that is, then we will apply the migration
by using _DB.database.migrate.
Next, we need to create roles.
If they are not created, we have that inside register.
We can cut that and paste it right here.
That looks good.
And after that, we have to create an application user,
so user manager dot create async.
We will create a new application user
and populate some of the details.
With a comma here, we have to add the password,
so that is what we will add right here.
You can see, we need identity user comma the password.
Because it is an async here,
we will have to call the GetAwaiter.GetResult.
Once the user is created, we will retrieve that user object
from database, using _db.ApplicationUser.
And after that is done,
we will call userManager.AddToRoleAsync,
where we'll pass the user and the role is SD.Role_Admin.
We will call the GetAwaiter.GetResult.
Now, this user that we want to create
will only happen the first time if the role does not exist,
so we can add that inside the same if condition.
And after everything, we will directly return back
to the application and that looks good.
So, perfect, you can see how we are seeding our data
with the initialized method.
But now the question is,
how will this initialized method
or where will we invoke this initialized method?
We have to get creative to invoke that inside Program.CS.
Let me open that and we will add that to our pipeline.
Right after app.run, let me create a method here
with the name of C database and they're using app.service.
We will have to create a scope.
So, I will add a using statement here.
I will say variable scope
is equal to app.Services.CreateScope.
On this scope object, we can get the service provider.
So, on scope, we have the service provider.
There, we have a method, get required service.
And the type of service implementation that we want
is IDB Initializer.
We will store that inside a variable DB Initializer here.
And then, on DB initializer,
we can invoke that initialized method.
Now the seed database, let me invoke that in our pipeline.
So, right here, we can invoke that.
So, that will be invoked every time the application
is restarted, but if we examine the code here,
we are checking the role, if that already exists,
it'll not execute any of the statement.
It'll only execute the statements first time
when it is creating role and that is exactly what we want.
But anytime, if there are pending migrations,
they will be applied automatically.
But one thing is remaining in Program.CS.
We are telling the service provider to get an implementation
of IDB initializer.
But have we registered that in builder services?
We have not.
So, let me add that
by builder.services.AddScoped IDB Initializer
and the implementation is inside DB Initializer.
Now with all of that configured,
let me show you how to test this in the next video.