Instructor: Now, how can we test
if everything is actually working?
Well, doing that is super simple.
Let me close all the tabs here and open appsettings.json.
We have been using bulky database
but now let me change the database name to Bulky one.
Typically when we do that, we have to add migration
but now we are doing that in seed database
so we do not have to do anything here directly
run the application.
It'll automatically create that database
apply all the migration seed admin user
and assign the role of admin.
Perfect, you can see here all the products are created.
Now we do not have any image
because that is the edit that user will have to do.
Let me go to DB Initializer
that was admin@dotnetmastery.com,
and if I try admin123, it should be able to sign me in
and perfect, everything is working as expected.
So that means if we go back here, we should have bulky one
and it should have all the tables, everything is created.
So you can see
with DB initializer how easy deployment will be.
Now, before we do anything else here, let me revert
back the old database name because that has orders
and everything and that is what we will use
if we want to build on to our application.
I can also go back
and delete this bulky one, that was only for testing.
Perfect, let me continue from the next video.