-: In the upcoming videos, we will see
how to send email using SendGrid.
And these two videos are optional videos
and the reason I am saying that is because
when you want to use SendGrid to send out emails,
you need a domain email.
When you are working professionally
you will always have a domain email from your workplace.
But if you are learning something,
it might be possible that you do not have a domain email.
If you do not have a domain email,
SendGrid email will not work.
And that is actually true for other email providers as well.
They prefer you have a domain email.
So if you do not have a domain email,
you can just watch the video
and see how easy it is to implement the email functionality.
That being said, we will be using
SendGrid to send emails in our project.
First, let me sign in here,
because I already have an account.
If you do not have an account,
you can always sign up for a free account.
Once you log in there, on the profile,
we have something called Account Settings.
Inside there, before we do anything else,
there is something called a Sender Authentication.
There you have to basically verify your domain name.
I have already verified, hello at dot net mastery dot com.
Because of that, I am able to use SendGrid.
Now if you are creating your account,
you will have to verify a single sender identity.
You will enter the details here,
and it will guide you on how to verify that identity.
If that identity is not verified using a domain email,
then SendGrid will not work.
So again, if you do not have a domain email,
and you only have Gmail or Yahoo,
do not try SendGrid, it will not work.
But you can watch the video and see how easy it is
to implement email in dot net core.
Now, similar to Stripe, with SendGrid as well,
we need an API Key.
So let me create a new API key here, with full access.
Key name, let me call that as bulky.
Create and view, and perfect.
Let me copy that.
We will paste our keys in the same location,
which is appsettings.jason here.
And right here, we'll add a section of SendGrid,
and in there we will use a key name of secret key
and let me paste the secret right here.
Now if you remember, previously we saw some issue
with sending emails because of that in the utility project.
We implemented the email sender,
which basically implements the build in Iemail sender.
We will enhance this email sender
and accent grid support right here.
So first thing, inside the utility project,
manage NuGet Packages, and there we will browse
for the SendGrid package.
Perfect, we have the package here. Let me install that.
And then we are ready to use SendGrid
inside the email sender.
Now using SendGrid here is super simple.
First we need to access our key here,
so let me create a property to store that key.
And in the constructor here, previously we saw
that with Stripe we created a class
that resembles the property.
And we used to populate that in Program dot CS.
Another way of accessing them,
is we can access the Iconfiguration directly here.
Call that and let's go config.
Then to populate the SendGrid secret here
we will access and that's called config.
There we have a method GetValue,
where we have to define the type.
And here we need to write the key name.
Now in app settings, we have section of SendGrid,
copy and paste that.
We have a key with the name of secret key.
So we will separate that by colon and paste that secret key.
That will reveal the secret value
and assign that to SendGrid secret.
Finally, right here, we have to add
the logic to send an email.
When we are working with SendGrid,
we first have to create a client,
which is inside SendGrid client.
And inside the parameter here,
we have to press the SendGrid secret key.
And that way it will create a client.
Then we need to add the from email address.
So we will say variable from is equal to a new email address
and that email address you can see it is inside
SendGrid dot helpers dot mail.
And there we will write the email,
which I have used to verify the single sender identity.
Which is hello at dot net mastery dot com.
Next, we can give a title here like Bulky Book
and that looks good for the email.
Then what email do we want to send email to?
So to will be new email address
and that we'll receive in the parameter of the
method right here.
Finally, we have the message itself,
message is equal to mail helper dot
there is a method, create single email.
Now previously in older version of SendGrid it was different
but they have simplified it with create single email.
If you have a template,
you can use create single template email.
We have a single email, we can add that,
and we have simple parameter from email
we have that in from, to email is inside to,
subject will receive that in the parameter,
and then we can give plain text content or string HTML.
Plain text content, let me keep that empty.
But finally we have some HTML content
that we will receive in the parameter which is HTML message.
So with that, we have drafted
the message that we need to send.
Finally, on client we will call the send email async
and we'll pass our message
and that will finally send the email.
So you can see how easy it was
to implement the Iemail sender.
It was adding about five lines of code and that's about it.
That is how easy SendGrid implementation is,
when it goes to dot net core.
Let me test that in the next video.