Instructor: How we'll be able
to test this email functionality?
Let me first go to Program.cs
and make sure that I have injected EmailSender correctly.
That looks good.
And because of that,
if I examine the register here,
let me open the page model.
And if you examine,
we have the IEmailSender independency injection.
Also, when the registration is successful here,
it is automatically sending an email to confirm the account.
So that logic is already there.
Let me run the application
and register to see if that is working.
Previously the logic was there,
but the email sender was empty
because of which no email was being sent.
But now that we have added the logic
it should send out an email.
Let me register.
The email address is valid here
so let me hit the register button.
Perfect. That is done.
Let me open Gmail here.
And then of course we will have to look
into the Spam folder
and we have this email from Bulky Book.
It should be Bulky.
I believe I have a spelling mistake in EmailSender.
There we go.
So whatever name we have here,
it is using that right here
and it is displaying,
"Please confirm your account by clicking here".
Now, surprisingly when we will click there,
it takes us to the confirmation page and it displays,
"Thank you for confirming your email".
Now all of this logic is already built in
with the .NET Identity,
because of which you can see in the database
when we examine the ASP.Net users table.
Let me open that.
You will see EmailConfirmed will be true for this account.
Where is that? Right here.
you can see EmailConfirmed is true.
So that implementation is also working as expected.
On top of that,
if you want to send an email once the order is placed,
we can do that as well.
It is straightforward.
We have that in the CartController.
Let me open that.
And there we will have to inject the IEmailSender
using dependency injection.
Let me do that here.
And perfect.
Then the action method will be OrderConfirmation.
And right here we can use _emailSender.
There we have the method SendEmailAsync.
We need to provide email subject and HTML Message.
Email is inside OrderHeader.ApplicationUser.Email.
Next we need a subject,
so we can say "New Order - Bulky Book".
And finally we need some text here.
So this will be HTML.
So we can add a paragraph tag
with the closing tag
and we can say "New Order Created".
And with that we will append the orderID.
That is inside orderHeader.Id.
Perfect, that looks good.
With that configured,
let me restart the application and try to place an order.
We are already logged in.
Let me add item to the cart.
Go to Cart here.
Summary, place order.
Perfect. Let me hit the pay button here.
And that works.
Order number is 1010.
And then if you open Gmail,
you will notice the email "New Order - Bulky Book"
and "New Order" along with the orderID.
Now, you can be fancy with the HTML templates here,
but I am keeping things super simple.
So perfect.
With that, email functionality is looking good
in our project.