Instructor: Now email functionality
and everything is looking good in our project,
it's time to finally deploy the application to Azure.
One thing that I can change here is the logo.
So let me switch back to the project here.
And if you examine,
I think we already copied the image here.
In images, we have book.png.
Let me add that in _Layout, in views, shared, _Layout.
If we scroll down where we have the BulkyBookWeb right here,
let me replace that with the image tag.
And I will say img src, images, book.png.
And let me see the UI.
That looks much better for my project.
Now with that change, I want to deploy this to Azure.
Now when we have to deploy things to Azure,
make sure that you have an active Azure subscription.
You can sign up for a free account and get about $200
in free credit.
I already have an account so I will directly use that.
I will open a new browser and I will write portal.azure.com.
There I will navigate to my Azure account.
And I have an active subscription along with other services.
First we need to create a SQL database.
And for SQL database we will have to create a SQL server.
But let me create a SQL database.
If you do not have that, you can always search here for SQL
and you will see SQL database.
Once you go in there, you will hit the create button.
You will have to select your subscription there,
scroll down, and a resource group.
I will create a new resource group here
which will be DotNetMasteryLiveProject.
After that, we need to give our database a meaningful name.
We can call that bulky.
And we have to create a server.
We need to create a new server.
So let me give that a unique name of bulky,
so bulky.database.windows.net.
Inside there we will be using SQL authentication.
So the user ID will be sqladmin
and password, I will use admin123* for now.
Now obviously in the future I will change things
around here, but this is for testing, so that looks good.
Perfect.
So we are creating a server, a database here.
And we do not want to use elastic pool.
The workload environment, we will keep that as development
because production can be quite expensive.
And right now we are learning things.
We'll configure the database here, and the service tier,
I am going to use the cheapest one, which is basic,
which is about $5 per month.
That is sufficient for my testing.
And that looks good.
With that we have the total monthly cost here.
We will hit review plus create, and looks good.
Let me create the SQL database and the SQL server.
The deployment will take a while
so let me wait for that.
And perfect, the deployment is complete here.
If I go to resource, well, we have the SQL database.
Let me go to the overview tab.
And first thing, we have to add the server firewall.
If you do not add that, you will not be able to
access the SQL server from your IP address.
So make sure to add your firewall here.
We will say selected network
and we will add your client IPv4 address.
And before you hit the save button,
make sure and make sure once again
to allow Azure services and resources to access the server.
Because what will happen is when we deploy web application,
that web application has to access the server.
If you do not allow that,
then it will not be able to access your database.
So with both of them, hit the save button.
We get an error here, so we will have to retry that.
Let me go back to bulky here.
Set server firewall and we will save this.
Perfect, that worked.
Now let me add the IP address.
Perfect, individually, both of them works.
Now right here,
if we examine the connection string inside SQL database,
we have the connection string to connect to our SQL server.
So we need to use this connection string
when we are deploying.
How will we deploy our code to Azure?
We will stop the service here.
And what we have to do is let me collapse everything here,
right click on the solution.
Let me close all the tabs here.
And let me deploy the web project in the next video.