Instructor: Now we need to deploy
the web application to Azure.
Right now .NET 8 is in preview,
so rather than facing some issues with the preview version
we can convert or downgrade our application
to .NET 7 only to learn how the hosting works
and see that in action.
So we will edit the project file here.
Let me open that and it will be .NET 7.
The version I know is 7.0.3,
so I will replace that in all of them right here.
And perfect.
I believe that looks good for the web project.
Save that.
Let me update the utility this time.
.NET 7 and 7.0.3.
Check the other one.
.NET 7.
7.0.3.
Edit project file.
Now, the only packages that we will update
where you see preview
and not any other package like Stripe or SendGrid.
We only want to touch the Microsoft packages
and perfect, that looks good.
With that, let me run the application
and everything should work as it is.
Let me see which one is the issue.
I believe I forgot something
in the web project, edit project file.
Whoops.
7.0.3 and that looks good.
Let me run this.
We are facing one issue here,
because date only has been introduced with .NET 8
and it is not available with .NET 7.
So that will be a little bit of an issue for our deployment.
To modify that, we will have to change quite a few things.
First, in the data here,
well, we have to go to models where we have order header,
change it from date only to date time
and now if I build the application
it looks like it is working here.
Let me run this.
We were converting that and that should not work right here.
It'll be DateTime.Now.Add 30 days.
And with that change
let me run the application and see if that works.
Let me try to place an order as a company user.
We have few things in the card.
That should be okay.
Let me add one more here.
Navigate to the cart and place order.
Perfect.
Order number is 2010.
Let me log out and log in as an admin.
Let me manage that order, which is 2010 here.
Start processing, add the carrier
and tracking and ship order.
Perfect.
We have the payment due date
and that is working as expected.
So with that, everything is looking good on local host
and the project is downgraded to .NET 7.
Let me close all the tabs here.
I will commit that with .NET 7 downgrade
and perfect, that worked.
So our code is all checked in and in the next video
let's work on deploying that to an app service.