Instructor: Now we have created the SQL database
and SQL Server in the Azure portal.
We need to deploy the app service
and that could be done directly from Visual Studio.
If we right click here, we have the publish icon.
But if you want to deploy that
from the Azure portal,
that is also possible
and let me show you that route.
In the App Service here,
we will hit the create
and there we have to select subscription.
Research group,
we will select the same .Net mastery live project.
And the name here, bulkmvc-dotnetmastery.
The name that we are using here will be the web name.
So let me copy that.
It will be .azurewebsites.net.
It will be a code-based application
so we will select that.
And what is the runtime stack?
That is .Net seven.
We need to select the region here.
Operating system, Windows looks good.
And for the plan here,
we want a free plan
so let me select that.
With that, let me hit the next button for deployment.
And if you want, we can enable the CI/CD pipeline.
So if you enable that,
it will automatically deploy changes to the website
as soon as you make a change.
Right here, my GitHub account is already connected here.
I will select organization
and repository is bulky_mvc.
That is the repository name that I have.
So perfect, looks good.
Networking tab.
We will enable the public access
and you can always enable application insights
for logging if you want,
but right now,
everything looks good here.
Let me hit the create button.
Perfect, the deployment is complete here.
Let me go to the resource.
Now if we click on the domain here,
it will not work and let me show that.
So basically our web app is running,
but the code is not deployed.
And if you go back here,
you will notice in the deployment center,
it is in process.
So let me refresh
and wait for this to be complete.
And perfect.
You can see the deployment is successful here.
If I go to App Service and run,
it will not work.
And the reason behind that is inside app settings.
We are looking for a local database,
but we do not have the connection string
to point to the new database that we added.
Perfect.
You can see the generic error,
ASP.Net Core app failed to start.
So how do we fix that?
Well, we first have to provide connection string here.
And ideal way of doing that is, let me go
to database, bulky
and where we have connection string.
Let me copy this.
Go back to our project here
and where we have the app settings,
we have the development.json.
So typically for production,
we will be adding a new file
in the web project
and we will search for app settings.
Name that we will give here is appsettings.production.json.
Add that file.
You can see it automatically maps right here.
There, let me copy whatever we have
inside appsettings.json
and we will paste it
in the production file right here.
Now what we want is we want a different connection
for our production.
So we can copy this.
I will paste it right here
and where we have the password,
I will type in my password admin123*.
Perfect.
So with that, it will be able
to connect to production
and all we have to do here is push the change.
I will have the lecture name, Azure Production Deployment,
commit that and push the change.
Now because CI/CD is enabled here,
let me do pull and push here
and perfect.
Now because CI/CD is enabled here,
if we go to our App Service
which is bulkmvc here,
you will notice a new deployment
will be triggered automatically.
Let me go there and perfect.
You can see because of CI/CD,
it automatically starts the deployment process
because it triggers that, hey,
there was something new
that was pushed to the Git repo.
So let me wait for this deployment as well.
Now while this is being deployed,
one thing that you must, must remember,
in the app server,
if you go to networking tab I believe,
there is a field, allow Azure services
and resources to access this server.
Make sure and again, make sure that this is checked.
If this is not saved,
then you will still see the error message
that we saw right here.
So that is connected here.
Let me go to App Service
and wait for the deployment.
Perfect.
Let me refresh here and perfect.
You can see the deployment is successful.
Now if we go back and refresh,
I believe everything should work now.
It might take some time
to load it for the first time.
So let me wait for that and perfect.
You can see our website is up and running
and that is the power of appsettings.json file.
Because of production,
it is able to detect that,
but on top of that,
what we can do is when we go to configuration,
right now we did not have any ASP Net core environment,
but we can explicitly set the environment
and that variable name is ASPNetCore_Environment
and that will be production.
You save that
and make sure to save it here.
That way, it will restart the app
and it will use that connection.
But if you notice here,
our web application is already running
because it will look for non dev here
and we have production.
It will get the connection string from there,
but we have to make couple of more fixes.
Let me do that in the next video.