Instructor: Now on the production website,
we can log in using the user
that we seeded in DB initializer.
So let me hit the login button
and I will log in as admin at dotnetmastery.com.
Once we do that, then we can modify the product
if we want and we can add image there.
So cotton candy, let me upload image, update.
Let me do that for all of them.
Perfect.
Now if I go to the homepage, great,
all the images arming up here
and let me try to place an order.
As an admin user, some things will not work
and let me show that.
When we go to summary, place order,
it'll redirect me to Stripe.
That is okay.
But if I click the back button here, it will not work.
Because we have the URL that was hardcoded
to local host and that should not be the case.
So we basically have to get this URL more dynamically.
Let me switch back to the code here
and let me do control shift F and search for local host.
I have that in two places.
Let me open both of them.
So first we need to get this https
and that we can get from request.scheme.
That will provide us whether it's http, https.
After that we will have to add this colon
and two forward slash and the later part here,
we can get that using request.host.value.
Finally, we will have to add the forward slash at the end.
So this will get the domain dynamically.
If it's local host, it'll get that.
If it is a website, it will get that.
In the controller here, let me add that as well.
And with that change we will have to commit and deploy.
So here I will name the kit commit as post-deployment,
URL settings, and let me push that.
Perfect, that looks good.
Now when it'll be pushed,
that will trigger one more deployment.
I already saw that on the homepage.
Perfect. We will have to wait again
to see all the changes in action.
Perfect. The deployment complete.
Now if we open the domain again
this time we should be able to place order
and Stripe should be able to redirect us
based on the dynamic URL.
We are logged in.
Let me go to cart here.
Place order.
We navigate to the shopping cart.
If we select back here,
it takes us to the correct shopping cart.
So that is working
and let me try to place an order with the dummy credit card.
Perfect. That work.
If we go to order management, great.
We have three orders in the all.
But you can see some of them are pending,
because we went to the checkout page and then we came back.
So what you can do is on validations
you can add a custom status that hey,
it went to cart, but the order did not go through
and maybe have a cleanup job to remove those orders.
So that is something that you can work with
and modify based on your requirements.
But we have a successful order here
and payment status is approved,
the order status is also approved.
We can start processing, ship the order,
and perfect, all the validations are working as expected.