Instructors: Final change that I want to show is
if we log out here and if we try to register
using Facebook login
it will not work because the redirect URL is not valid.
So we have to go
to developers.facebook.com and let me copy the domain here.
Go to my apps.
We have Bulky here.
Let me go in there.
In settings basic, we need the redirect URI
I believe it was in Facebook settings and right here
along with the local host, we will also add the new URL
with sign in Facebook, save the changes.
Perfect, with that configured, let me go back here
and let me drive Facebook again and great
that is functional.
I can register here
and it will automatically sign me in using Facebook.
So great.
With that, our application is deployed
to Azure and everything is working as expected.