But we have the connection string and appsettings.json file.
What we want to do next is basically create database in SQL Server.
But the database that we want to create, we want to create using code that we have in the application
using entity framework.
Core entity framework core is the framework that will let us do all the things related to database directly
from the code right here.
Now back in the old days of .net to point to entity framework core was already included in the main package
of.
.Net application.
But as the .net framework has enhanced, the basic application comes with the packages that are needed
and everything else have to be added manually to the project in order to add a new get package to our
project.
We will go to bulky web here, right click and we will select Manage NuGet packages.
The first package that we need is Microsoft.Entity Framework Core.
It is already supported based on IntelliSense, but if not, you can search that as well.
Now the version that you see here is 7.0.3, but we are using the .net eight in preview.
So we have to enable this checkbox include pre-release.
If .Net eight was released, then if you do not have this checkbox on, you will see the latest version.
We want the preview version.
So select that and we will select Microsoft.Entity Framework Core NuGet Package.
Let me install that package here.
Accept the license and.
Perfect.
That looks good.
We will be using entity framework core, but for the database we will be using SQL Server.
So that is also displayed right here.
We need the package Microsoft.Entity FrameworkCore.SQL Server.
We have the version here.
Let me install that.
One thing that I will always remind you is if you install one preview version or even with any .net version,
make sure all the Microsoft packages are of the same version.
Like if you install entity framework core with .net eight and then if you install other package with
seven, things will not work.
So make sure that every package that you install is of the same release.
Let's say in middle of the course, if preview two or preview nine of .net eight is released when
you are installing here, you can always install the version that you want and you do not always have
to install the latest one.
So make sure to remember that.
But after the two packages that we installed, we also have to install Microsoft.Entity Framework
core.tools.
This package will enable the commands that we will use for migration.
Now, what is migration?
Do not panic when the time is right.
I will explain everything to you.
But right now make sure to install Microsoft.Entity Framework core.tools to the project.
And perfect.
Now we have installed three packages.
If you go to the installed tab here, you can see all of the packages.
Again, if let's say new version is released, you can go to update here and update all of the packages
rather than updating a single package.
But right now, everything looks good.
Now because we add these packages inside the Manage NuGet package, they are also added in the project
file.
So if I click edit here, you can see in the package reference it has added all three packages right
here.
This is the actual location that is very important.
Anytime you add a NuGet package, an entry will be added inside the project file of that project.
And that way project knows which are all the packages that are being used and it will load all of them.
With that, we have added the NuGet packages.
Let me continue from the next video.