On the category list page.
We want to display all the categories, but if you go to database, we do not have any categories right
now.
Now, if you want, you can do edit top 200 and basically add some categories right here.
But rather than that, entity, framework core provides you with some helper functionality on if you
have to seed some entities in your database.
For that we will have to go to application DB Context.
Let me open that inside the application.
DB context.
After we have the DB set, we will override the default function which is on model creating and that
expects a model builder.
Now this is a default function that is already there in DB context and we want to override the default
behavior.
So we have to use the override keyword for that.
It expects a model builder.
And if you examine any of the migration, we were using something called as migration builder there
and here we are getting a parameter of type model builder Using this model builder, we can see data.
Now again, do not think about why exactly we have model builder or why on model creating.
It is the default thing that entity framework has implemented and we are just using that to seed data.
And in order to see data we will be using model builder.
There we have entity and what entity we want to create or work on.
That is the category right here.
So we will say category and then what we want to do, we want to add some data.
So on that, we have a method which has data and inside that you can see in the params here it expects
a category array.
And if you examine the comments here, it says adds see data to this entity type.
We want to create a new object here so in has data.
We will say new category.
And there we will have to populate ID.
We will give that 1, name.
Let me call that action.
And display order is 1.
Using that it will create this particular entity.
But if you want to create more categories, you can add a comma and paste it multiple times here.
Let's say you want action.
Then you have scifi.
And you have history.
We will change the display order as well, and we will keep them the same as ID.
Perfect.
Now we are telling entity framework core that hey, on category, we want to create these three records.
And again, to do that we will have to add migration.
Whenever anything has to be updated with database, we have to add a migration.
Always, always, always remember that.
So we will say add migration and I will call this seed category table.
Perfect.
That works.
If you examine the migration, it is calling something called as insert data and it is inserting three
records.
All of them looks perfect.
So what do we do to apply this changes?
We run the command update database and that will seed our data.
Perfect with that.
If I go back here and refresh.
Great.
We have three records in our category table.
In the next video, let me show you how we can easily retrieve the three records that we have in our
categories table.