Now in our category page, we are displaying all the categories.
But what if a user wants to create a category?
For that, we need a button here that will take us to a new page which will be dedicated to creating
a category.
So let me add that button and add some styling.
Rather than playing simple H1.
Here, let me remove that.
I will add a div, give it a class of container and we will close that div at the very end.
Right there.
Then we will add a div, give it a class of row and padding top of four.
These are just bootstrap classes that we are using.
We are defining a container.
And inside there we have a row in bootstrap.
Row is divided into 12 columns in a page.
So one row will basically have 12 columns.
What we want to do is inside that div class of row, we will be using six columns.
That means we are left with other six column.
We will add those other six column right here.
So the six columns on the left side, which is the left hand side of the page, we want to display the
heading.
We will use H2 here and we will give it a bootstrap classes of text primary, which is black color.
There we will display category list.
Let me save that.
And.
Perfect.
Looks good.
On the right side here, we want to add the button to add a new category, and that button will be on
the right side.
So with column six, we will add something like text and that will make sure it floats to the right
side.
Inside there.
We want an anchor tag and that will take us to some controller.
And inside there it will invoke some action.
What it is, we have not defined that, but we will do that in the upcoming videos.
We will give it the bootstrap classes of BTN BTN primary and let me say create new category.
Along with that, let me add a bootstrap icon as well.
So I will search for a plus icon.
And we have the plus circle.
Let me use that.
Paste it right here and let's go back.
Perfect.
We have create new category.
Along with padding top for let me do padding bottom and I think three will be good.
Perfect.
That looks much better for our category list page.
Now, what should happen when we click the button of create new category?
Let me do that in the next video.