Now we have the form to create a category, but with .net core, we have tag helpers that we can use
to make this input fields more dynamic because basically we have to bind somewhere that this input field
is for category name.
And the next one here is for display order.
In older versions of .net, we used to bind them with name property.
When we post the form we used to retrieve and assign them.
But .net core has made everything super simple.
We have the model that we have defined here, so with input we have tag helpers which is ASP hyphen
for.
Inside there.
We have to define what this input field will be responsible for and that is for name.
Now, if you think how name is working here, that is because we have category model and that has a
property with the value of name.
If you write name one here, it will not work.
You can see category does not contain a definition for name, so it will only have those properties
which are defined in your model.
And the best part is if you have ASP four, then you do not have to define type as well.
It will automatically find out the type based on the property name.
So the next one here, we will say ASP for that will be for display order.
We type that and IntelliSense already displays that.
Same thing we have for the label name as well.
So if we use ASP for we do not have to define display order here, it will automatically add that and
let me show that.
We will remove the category name here.
Save them and let's go back.
Great.
You can see name and display order.
But then we have another issue.
The property names that we have does not have a space.
What if we want to add a space in display order?
For that.
We have data annotations that we have to add on our model.
Where is that?
We have the category model.
Let me stop the application here.
We have seen the data annotations that were required for entity framework core, but we can also add
data annotations that are useful for client side UI or client side validation.
We have something called as display name.
And there we have to write the name that we want.
So when it is being displayed, we want display order with a space.
And where we have the name, let's say we want to display name.
Of category name.
With that configured, let me run the application again.
So let me go to category again and create new category.
Perfect.
Now we have the category name and display order.
The textbox here looks off.
Let me go back here.
Whoops.
Sometimes you will have to stop and restart for the UI changes as well, but that should be okay.
Let's go back here and perfect now.
Best thing when we are using ASP four and the property name are the same for label and input.
If you click on the label, it will automatically highlight the input field.
So that is also done with the help of Tag Helper.
You can see display order.
It automatically knows it's an integer value and it defines that right here.
So that is the beauty of working with tag helpers.
With that configured, let me continue from the next video.