Now, the validations that we have right now are server side.
And what I mean by that is you will notice when we hit the create button, it hits our debugging point
in the controller and then it returns back the error message.
You will notice the page also reloads.
There we go.
You can see the spinner at the top.
That means it is going to the server.
But what if we want to implement client side validation using JavaScript?
We can easily do validations in the browser itself to make sure this field is populated or not.
Dot net core has already provided some of those things built in.
If we take a look at validation scripts partial, it has the validation jQuery.
Using that we can do client side validation.
And for that we do not have to write much code inside the create view where we have the validation for
we have to include reference to this partial view.
So basically we have to add this partial view, which is a shared view inside the main create view.
And that way whatever code is inside the shared will also be added to the create view that we have.
Now how can we add or consume a partial view?
That is pretty simple.
Since this partial view is only having the scripts, we will have to add that in a new section here
for scripts.
And I have some space.
Let me remove that.
Inside there we will have the razor syntax.
And when we have to consume any partial view, we can do that with the partial tag.
And there we have to provide name.
Make sure to copy the name.
It must exactly match the name that we have in validation scripts.
Partial.
It should be the exact file name.
If that is not same, it will not work.
And with that it has added that partial view in the script section for the View page.
Now, because this partial view was script related, we added that in the script.
But if this was not a script related, you can directly add that right here.
When we have to consume some partial view in a master page.
But that is not the case for now.
So we will add that inside the script section that we have.
But here you have noticed how we can consume a partial view with the partial tag helper that we have
in the.
.Net framework.
And where we have the name here, by default, it will go and look into the shared folder because that
is the default location for any partial view.
Because of that, it will automatically find that and it will add the JavaScript that are needed for
client side validation.
Simple as that.
With that, let me restart the application.
And now the validation will be first done on client side and for custom validation it will go to the
server side.
So in order to test that, actually let me go back and uncomment these lines here because they are custom
validation and let me run the project.
So if we go to category here, and if we create a new category this time when we hit create.
Let me also add a debugging point.
You will notice it will not go to the server.
There will not be any spinner.
We see the error message and you can see it is not hitting our breakpoint as well.
If I enter the category name test here create, we have the other validation.
Once we fulfill that, if it is more than 100, you can see when I am typing it automatically displays
the validation.
But the custom validation that we have is category name and display order cannot be same is on server
side and client side validation is not aware of that.
So when we hit create button this time it will hit our breakpoint and it goes to the server and displays
the server side validation.
With that, we have seen how easy it is to add client side validation in our views in the .net project.
We just have to add the scripts that are provided by default on the page where we want client side validation.