We have the delete cat and delete post action method.
Let me remove the comments here.
And now we want to work on adding the view.
So right click on delete, add view empty view.
Make sure to change the name to be delete dot cshtml and perfect.
Now the view will look exactly same as we have for edit here, so let me copy that and paste it for
our delete.
Few things we have to update is when we delete, we will not have any validation.
So let me remove them and the fields here will be disabled.
User cannot edit anything here and this will be delete category.
Also the button color will be danger and it will be delete record.
That looks good.
Inside the index.
When we are calling delete here, we will have to pass the route ID.
That way we will know which category user wants to delete.
We will call that ID because in the controller that is what we have right here.
Now when we post, we already saw we do not need the ID in the hidden property.
But I always like to add that that way there is nothing magic going on.
We know that we have ID in the hidden property and when we submit that will be populated.
We can also do the same thing in edit even though for ID it is not required, but for other properties
it will be so it does not harm to add this particular line in edit and in delete.
With that I believe everything here looks good.
Let me run the application and see if that works.
We go to category here we have action, which is seven display order.
Let me try to delete test here.
Perfect.
Everything is disabled.
Hit the delete button and great.
That has been deleted.
If I switch back to SQL Server and examine the categories table, we do not have that test anymore.
So great.
All the CRUD operations are working for our category.
Let me continue from the next video.