Now when the update, create or delete is successful, rather than displaying this plain H2 tag, here
it is best if we use something fancy.
And for that we will be using toaster.
If you search for that, we have the first link here and let me go to the demo page.
We will click Show Toaster and perfect.
These notifications are much better than what we have.
We have success, we have Warning Toaster and we have added toaster as well.
So let's see how we can add them in our project.
It is a JavaScript library here and we have the CDNs.
Let me copy the CDN for CSS here.
And where will we add our styling?
We always do all the global stylings in underscored layout.
So let me add that here.
Link rel is equal to stylesheet and ref.
Let me paste the CDN here.
Perfect.
Next, we need the JSS as well.
Now for JavaScript we will have to add that inside the individual notification here.
So when we are displaying that, we have to add that notification.
So here I can add the script tag here and src is equal to paste that.
And let me see.
We need the closing tag as well.
Perfect.
The error should go away.
That looks good.
When we are using toaster here.
We also need jQuery.
We already have that inside the lib here.
So lib, jQuery dist and we have the minified version.
We can use that.
And let me add the closing tag as well.
Perfect.
That looks good.
We will copy this, paste it for the error as well.
And rather than using the .js here, let me use the minified version.
That way when we move to production we do not have to update anything and we are using the minified
once.
We will do the same for CSS as well.
And perfect.
Now, finally, inside the underscore notification, we do not want a boring H2.
Rather we have to see how to use that.
If we scroll down, we have three easy steps.
We added the CSS and JS and then we have toaster.info and the text right here.
Pretty simple.
Let me copy this.
Go back to our code and where we have the temp data.
Before that we will add toaster.success.
And we need the success message right there.
We will add a semicolon here and we need to enclose this in a double quotes.
Also, the toast here will be inside script.
Type is equal to text.
Forward slash Java script.
And perfect.
That looks good.
Let me copy this and paste it right here.
This time it will be error here.
Save that and run the application.
We go to category here, try to edit the display order to 88 or rather 99 and perfect.
We have the fancy notification.
Now, while we are here, I want to make one change.
Right now, the partial view is inside Index.cshtml.
But let's say this is a functionality that will be there across hundreds of pages.
So rather than adding on all of them, we can also add that in underscored layout.
So cut it from here.
And where we have underscored layout before the render body here, I can add the partial view that way.
On all of the pages, this functionality will be available.
We will have to rebuild and apply the changes here and everything will still work the same.
But now wherever we need toast or notification, it will be available and we will not have to add the
partial view for notification.
Let's try delete here and perfect.
Everything is working as expected.
With that, we have incorporated toaster notification in our project.
Now, think about this.
If you did not have partial view on all the pages where you needed to watch the notification, you would
have to add this particular code on top of all the pages.
And if in future, when you wanted to change from toaster to something else, you will have to update
that on all the pages where this code was present, which is not a good idea.
And that is why you should be using partial views.
So with that in place, let me continue from the next video.