Narrator: Now, we want to work on the details page.
For that, what we will do is we will display
all the product details on that page,
and then for those product details, we will ask the user
how many products you want to add to the shopping cart.
So let's go back to our controller.
Inside the HomeController, let me stop this.
We will copy the index action method,
and we will create a details action method.
Inside detail, we do not want a list,
we just want a single product.
So we will retrieve that and I can call this as product.
Rather than GetAll, we will have the GetFirstOrDefault.
In the action method here, we will receive an id
for which we want to view the details.
So inside the GetFirstOrDefault,
we will have our link expression,
u equals to u dot id is equal equal to the id.
(keyboard typing)
We will return back our product model.
Now, inside the details page,
we will also need the number of count
that user wants for that product in their shopping cart.
So we will need to create a view model
since product will not be sufficient.
And once the user adds that,
we will be adding that to the shopping cart,
so it makes sense to create a view model.
(mouse clicking)
I will call that as shopping cart.
We will make that a public class.
We'll do prop here.
We will have a product and we will call it the same.
Next, what we want is count for that product.
So we will do prop integer.
We will have count here and we will add the range validation
that it must be between one and thousand.
That looks good for now, but we will come back
and modify our shopping cart in the future videos.
Right now, if we go to our home controller,
here, we can create a ShoppingCart object.
Let me press control dot.
This will be cartObj is equal to new.
And within the parameters here,
we will assign this to product.
So product is equal to the product here
and I want count to be defaulted to one.
So right here we can set count is equal to one.
That's perfect.
We will return the cartObj to the view and let's save this.
In the next video, let's create the details view
and display all the details.