Instructor: I hope you were able
to complete the assignment
but if you face any issue
let me do that together in this video.
First thing, we have to create
our products table in the database.
So we have the package manager here.
Let me open that,
and we'll add migration.
Now, when you add migration,
if you face error here,
like if I just add the migration,
add products to db,
this will not work.
Because the default project here
is the bulky book web project,
it should display an error message.
Right now we see a different error message
and that is because where we have the hasData,
this should be product.
I hope you corrected that when you tried the assignment,
but with that, let me try adding migration.
Of course, we get error message
because the default project is web project.
When we add a migration
that has to be updated to data access.
With that,
let me add the migration,
and perfect, that looks good.
Let me update the database,
and great,
it completed successfully.
If we scroll down here, in the migration,
it is also seeding the data.
So, that looks good.
Let me switch back to the SQL server here
and examine bulky, tables, products table.
It should have six record,
and great, that looks good.
If we go back to the assignment,
our first step is complete here.
Next we need the product repository.
For that we will go,
and basically we can copy and paste
the category repository,
rename that to be product repository.
We will have to do the same with the interface here.
So this will be IProductRepository,
copy that name,
and we will make sure to rename our interface.
That will be on the product,
and in the update we will get a product object.
Looks good.
Let me go to the product repository here,
and we will modify that IProductRepository.
Class name will be ProductRepository,
and this will be product.
Constructor name will be ProductRepository,
and in the update we will get the product
underscore db.products.update.
Perfect.
Our repository also looks good.
Final step, we have to add that to our unit of work.
Let me open the interface
as well as the implementation.
This one will be IProductRepository.
We will call that as product.
Close the interface here.
In the implementation
we will have to add the IProductRepository,
name that as product,
and we will say product is equal to new ProductRepository.
Pass the application db context.
With that, I believe our unit of work
as well as a repository for product is complete.