Instructor: We have unit of work in place
for our product repository.
It is time for the second assignment
where you have to create product controller
and action methods for the CRUD functionality.
After you create the controller and action methods,
then you will have to create view
for all the crowd operations
and add client side and server side validation.
All of the steps here, we have already done that
for category controller, so you have to replicate them.
And the only reason I am making you
replicate them once again
is that you will gain some experience
on how to work with all the create functionalities
with models, views, and controller.
The only difference this time is
that you have more properties
and product than category model.
So make sure to practice all the CRUD operations
and I will show you how to do that in the next video.