Instructor: Now before we work
on anything else where we have the image U R L
we want this to be a file upload.
Let me switch back here.
Let me close the get comment here and I will go to create.
Right now we are only working on create and not edit
and I have a very good reason for that
which I will cover in the upcoming video.
But right now, let me scroll down
where we have the image here
we do not want the A S P four.
We will say input type is equal to
file and form control.
Looks good.
We do not want validation.
Let me remove that.
And let me go back and see how that looks.
Perfect. Looks good here.
Then where we have the form right here,
we will have to add one thing.
We have to add the E N C type
which will be multi-part form data.
If you do not add that, then file upload will not work
so make sure that
in your form you have multi-part form data.
With that, we basically have an input element
or rather an input file, upload in the product, create.