-: We have added the code to update the product
and remove old image if that exists.
Let me see that in action here.
We have an old image.
Let me pin this so we can see the old image being deleted.
And let me upload a new image.
We will hit update here.
And you notice here the new image was added
but the old one was not deleted.
Let's debug and see what happened.
We will add a break point here.
Let's go back and try to update a new image here.
Update and let's see.
It did not go into the F condition here
and for some reason the image URL is null.
The reason behind that is if I go back to the absurd view
we have the image URL
but it is not there in any input field.
Because of that, when the form is posted
it does not stay there.
We will have to add the image URL
in a hidden field as well
and that should resolve our issue.
With that configured, let me run the application once again.
Let me go to product and one with the image here.
Let me delete the other image here
because I know that is fake one
and I just have the last image that is there.
Let me try to update this one, update,
and it should go inside the if condition.
Perfect, that works.
If I continue here, you can see the old image was deleted
and we have the new guid.
If we click edit here, we have the new image.
Perfect, update image is working as expected,
but one issue is
let's say we are only updating the title here.
If I save that, image stay as is.
But if I go to edit here, image is still there.
One thing that I will show here is EF Core is smart.
If I update this to be the title here
and let me add a debugging point once again,
we are not modifying the image here.
If I press update
you will notice it goes to the update here
and it has the new product that has everything right here
and the product here title is updated.
EF Core will basically update all the properties right here
along with title.
So if in case somehow the image URL was empty here
then that image would be removed from the table entry.
So what we can do is in this case
even though the update is working, when we are updating
we can be explicit about what needs to be updated.
So right now everything is working
but if you want, you can be explicit.
If we go to repository, product repository,
we have the update method right here.
Rather than directly updating the object here
we can retrieve the product object from database,
based on the OBJ ID that we receive right here.
And once we have that product from the database
we can manually update that.
So we can say if OBJ from Db is not now
then we want to update which properties.
We will have to do a manual mapping
for all of those properties.
And after that we can be explicit
that if OBJ dot image URL is not null,
only then you update the image URL.
If you have any other custom logic
you can add that here as well.
But this is how you can do a manual mapping if you want.
And that is one
of the reason I have update inside the individual repository
and not in the generic repository.
With that configured, if you run the application
everything will still work the same.
Let me see that in action.
And let me also examine the product image here.
So have that side by side.
I will update the title here and maybe the description.
We update that, hit the debugging point.
Let me remove that and perfect, both of them are updated.
Final thing, we have the category ID that is being
displayed here, but we need to display that
inside the product index.
Let me do that in the next video.
But before that, let me add image to all
of the other books that I have.
So Fortune of Time, I will select that, update.
Dark Skies, I have an image for that.
Next, Vanish in the Sunset,
we have cotton candy,
and Rock in the Ocean,
Leaves and Wonders.
Perfect. We will not delete these two right now.
We will handle that in the upcoming videos,
but if we add it, perfect.
The images are now coming up for all the books.
Perfect. Let me continue from the next video.