Instructor: We have to create JavaScript
to post an Ajax request
and load data.
So that will be a little bit tricky,
so let me walk you through all of that here.
In the wwroot folder,
we have css, js.
Right there, let me add a new file.
I will stop the application.
New item,
and I will call that product.js.
Let's add that.
Now if we go back, let me copy what we have for DataTable,
paste it right here.
We are loading the DataTable here,
but we need to do that on document.ready.
Because of jQuery, we can use $ document.ready
and we will call a method loadDataTable.
Let me create that function here.
And inside there, I will basically cut and paste this code
in a variable dataTable is equal to.
And let me paste that.
You can see it is looking for something
called as myTable, and that we will add later on.
Do not worry.
Rather than myTable, let me call that tblData.
First thing, we need the API URL that is inside admin.
We have product and getall,
that should retrieve all the records.
Now once we retrieve those records, we have to format that.
If I go back to the documentation
and go to the Data tab here
and scroll down,
you can see we can render columns and that can have data.
The first property here is data.
But because we are using Ajax here,
that will automatically be loaded.
So we can copy the columns here,
go back to the code,
and I can paste it after the curly bracket, add a comma,
and we will add columns.
The columns here will be inside the colon here.
And the Ajax as well, we will add that in double quotes.
I will add that in curly bracket for the values,
add a comma,
and let me format that a little bit
so that everything makes sense.
We need the closing curly bracket here.
Let me add that.
And perfect.
Things are looking good,
but in the Ajax here, we can directly use that,
or we can define the URL.
Because when we have Ajax call,
it is possible you want more options or more properties
that is why it is an object.
Next we have the columns.
Now we have the data here and we have field names.
And along with that, we can also give some option
like what will be width of all the columns.
Before we work on adding the column names here,
let me actually go back to our index here.
And where we are displaying the foreach loop,
that is no longer needed
because we will be using DataTable for that.
In here, all we have to do
is we need to add the ID of tblData.
So where we have the table, we will give that ID.
We do not need the tbody.
We can remove that.
DataTable will take care of configuring all of that.
Only thing that we have to do is add the JavaScript code.
So we will add a section for scripts.
And inside there, we will add the reference
to src js product.js.
We have already added DataTable in the underscored layout.
So with that configured, let me run this
and I want to show you an error message
which is very common when you are working with DataTables.
We go to product here and we have a warning.
It says requested unknown parameter name
for row zero column zero.
You can see we are asking for name here
and it does not find that.
The reason is the JSON object that controller returns
it does not have anything with name.
But if I change that to be title and if I refresh here,
this time you can see the error is position not found.
That is because the column names are not valid,
but title gets populated if you click Okay.
So you can see the issue right here.
We need to have the exact column names.
So if we go to index here, copy all of them,
like ISBN,
Price,
and we have the Author,
let me save that.
Go back here and refresh.
You can see it is still not working.
Why is that the case?
Well, it has to match what the API is return
and it is case sensitive.
So we need to know what the API is returning.
We can copy and paste this.
Let me call the api product/getall.
We can copy this API,
go to JSON formatter,
open that in a new tab,
and let me paste our API code.
Let me go back and copy that once again
and paste it here.
And perfect.
You can see it is title, isbn, author,
listPrice has a capital P.
So if you want to display that, it must exactly match.
So let's do that.
We will keep this open here.
And where is that?
Right here, we have isbn, all lowercase.
Copy, paste that.
listPrice, copy and paste that.
Author, all lowercase.
And finally, we want the category name.
Category name, if we go here, it is inside category
and then we have name.
So you have to write category.
and then the property inside there is name,
that is exactly what you have to use.
And once you do that, the error goes away.
So if you notice that error message,
that means in your DataTable,
your property names are not valid.
Now if I go to index here,
let me add a width of 100% for the table.
And that looks much better.
With that we have Title, ISBN, Price, Author, and Category.
We can modify some of the width in the product.js,
like title can take 25%.
ISBN, that's okay.
This can take 10%.
Author can take up 20.
And category name, that looks good.
If I sum them up, it is total of 85, I believe.
So we have 15 more.
In that 15 more, I want to display two buttons.
So how can we add custom buttons where we have the columns?
Let me show that in the next video.