Instructor: In data table, we want buttons to edit
or delete any of the product.
If I go back to the code here,
we have basic columns,
but with that basic column,
we can make things super fancy.
Let me show you how to do that.
We will copy that, paste it one more time.
The next column,
whenever we are editing or deleting
any of the product, we need the product id.
So for data, we basically need the id here.
If I save this and go back,
it will display the id.
I do not want that to display the id.
Rather than that,
I want to display some buttons right here.
So for that what I can do
is there is something called as render.
And there we can define a custom render function
that we want.
So here, we will say function,
and the parameter we will take data,
which is basically the id.
Now here, inside the string,
we will have to write the HDML that we want to render.
Like if I add a div here with a closing div,
and if I said, "Hello,"
if I save that and go back,
you can see it displays "Hello" right there.
But rather than that,
in the div let me add a bootstrap class
of btn group,
give that a role of group.
Now, right now I have to write everything in single line,
but if we want multi-line,
we can use the symbol
which is on top of the ash track
where we can write multi-line HDML.
So you can see we can break it out
in different line,
and it still treats that as a string.
First, I will add an anchor tag here
with href that is empty right now.
We will add some bootstrap classes,
and I'm adding a pencil bootstrap icon.
If I save that here, go back,
perfect, We have the added button.
Similar, to add it here,
let me make some space
and add a delete button
with an icon for trash fill.
And great, that looks much better.
I can reduce the width here to make sure
that we have enough space.
So let me do that.
We will make this 10%, author can be 15,
and we can change this to be 25%.
Perfect. Looks good.
Now when a user clicks edit,
we need to write the href here.
So we have to redirect to admin area,
product controller, upsert action,
and there we have to pass the id.
So id, we have that in the data here,
so we can use the dollar sign
and use data because we are saying
data is basically the id.
With that, if I go back,
you can see edit it is functional
and that link is working as expected.
In the next video,
let me add an a EPA endpoint for delete
and then invoke that.