Instructor: When we are deleting our product,
I want an alert,
And for that I will be using SweetAlert2.
If we see notification here,
you can see it is a fancy notification.
Let me go to the installation tab here and we have the CDN.
Let me copy that, and I will add that in our project.
I have _layout here.
Let me add that.
Now how to actually invoke that.
Now let me go to the examples here
and if we scroll down
we should have an example with confirm button.
This is exactly what we want.
We want a confirmation box and if they select
Yes, delete it, then we want to delete the product.
So I can copy the Swal.fire.
Go back to our project here
and we will add that in product.js file.
Let me create a function here, Delete,
where we will get the URL that needs to be invoked.
I will paste the Swal.fire.
Now in here when user selects okay, let's delete that.
We want to make an Ajax request to our controller
to delete this particular product.
And I will make this HttpDelete.
That is what it should have.
I will do continue editing here and let's go back.
So if it is confirmed, I will set $.ajax
and we will have the Ajax request.
We will first have the url that we will receive
in the parameter of the method right here.
Next, we need the type and that is HttpDelete.
So we will write DELETE here.
And what should happen if it is successful?
Well on success, let me have a function
where we will get the data back.
If it is successful, what are we returning back here?
We are returning a success and a message.
So that will be available in data right here.
What I can do is I can just call our toastr
notification .success and pass that data.message.
With that configured, we have to pass this URL
and we will have to replace this href with an onClick.
So we have the URL that looks good.
What I can do is I can replace href with an onClick.
Call the delete function here.
And I will pass that right here.
That looks good.
With that configured, let me rebuild and see if that works.
We go to product here.
Let me try delete, perfect.
If I hit cancel, nothing happens.
But when I select, Yes, Delete it, it hits the endpoint.
And if I continue, you can see on the UI
that product is still visible.
But that is not the case.
If I load the product page again, that is gone.
So what is happening is even though
that product is getting deleted,
the data table is not getting refreshed.
Refreshing that is super simple as well.
If I go back to product.js here.
When we have the results success here.
We can say dataTable.ajax.reload.
This data table we have that right here.
But in order to access that
we need to create a variable with the name of data table.
With that, it'll be available right here
and it'll be able to reload that.
So perfect.
With that configured,
let me restart and test everything once again.
We will have to create a new product.
I do not want to delete the existing products.
Perfect, we have that here.
We hit delete.
Yes, delete it, delete successful,
and the data table also reloaded.
With that we have all the correct functionalities
for product working as expected.