When you will be working with the course, you will require some project resources.
I have added all of the project resources in one place, which is .net mastery.com.
So there if you navigate to courses, go to the course detail.
Here we have a few things right here.
First, I have a live preview of the final project that you will be building if you want to navigate.
Next, I have GitHub code.
Well, let me go back and open that in a new tab here and there.
If you notice, I have all of the commit based on the lecture name.
So we have section and then the lecture name.
If you go there, you can exactly see in that lecture what was modified.
So if something does not work for you, you can go here and look at that exact commit to make sure that
you do not have anything else.
That is a great resource.
Then we have course content.
Make sure to download that and let me open that file.
Once you open that, you will see two folders inside there.
If you are taking the old course in .net six, there are all the resources based on the old course.
But if you are taking the .net eight course, there are all the project resources where we have all
the image that are being used.
We have code snippets for lecture and I have the final PowerPoint which you can use in your project.
So make sure to download all the project resource before you move forward in the next video.