Instructor: In this course, we will be using .NET 8.
Right now, .NET 8 is in preview.
So if you download .NET 8,
currently preview.2 has been released.
First, you have to download the version
based on your system.
I have downloaded Windows x64.
And once you download .NET 8,
then you have to download Visual Studio 2022 Preview.
You need the Preview version if you want to work with .NET 8
because it has not been released yet.
Preview version can be downloaded for free.
Just go to visualstudio.microsoft.com/vs/preview.
Make sure to install .NET 8 and Visual Studio Preview
before you proceed with the course.
Now, if you want to follow along with .NET 7,
you can obviously do that and everything will work
other than one change that has been introduced in .NET 8,
where they have new type, for date only and time only.
But other than that, everything will work perfectly fine
with .NET 7 as well.