Let me give you a brief overview of what we will cover in this course.
Now, as we know, we are building a real world application, so our final project will have an entire
architecture.
When we work with entity framework for database, we will be using repository pattern and unit of work.
Then we will see temp data view back view data in .net core.
What are the differences between them and ideally when you should use each one of them?
We will also see API controllers along with razor pages.
Then we will integrate many advanced features like sweet alerts, rich text editor, data tables with
.net core.
So basically many JavaScript packages.
After that, we will integrate security in our application.
For that, we will use the .net identity and we will implement roles and authorization in our application.
In order to capture payments, we will be using Stripe payment and we will also see how to process refund
using Stripe.
Then we will see sessions in .net core and how to send emails using SendGrid.
We will also build a user management in our website where basically we will manage all the users.
We can toggle their roles dynamically.
On top of that, we will implement social login using Facebook.
That way they do not have to enter all the details when the sign up.
We will also look at some advanced concepts like view components in .net core and how to see database
using DB initializer.
Once the application is complete, we will deploy the complete application to Azure and that way you
will gain experience on how to deploy your application.
Now what I have covered right now is at 10,000 ft overview.
So let me continue with our journey from the next video.