What we have to do is create a project using Visual Studio 2022.
I have opened Visual Studio 2022 here and I will select create a new project on the left hand side here.
I will have recent project templates, but what we want to do here is search for MVC.
And with that we should get ASP.NET Core Web app.
Now the project we want to work on is MVC application.
So make sure to select the one with Model View and Controller.
There is also a web app without MVC that uses razor pages.
We do not want that.
We will give our project a name of bulky web, location wherever you want to save it.
And then we need a solution.
Name. now solution name,
I will keep that as bulky because in there we will have multiple project.
With that configured, let me hit the next button.
The framework that we want to use is .net eight.
We will select that, authentication type.
We will be adding authentication later on.
But right now we want to keep things super simple and then we will add on to our project.
So right now we will keep that as none configure for HTTPS.
That looks good and we will not check that.
Do not use top level statements.
It is just adding the using statements at the top and it is not that important.
That is why we can just ignore that and hit the create button.
With the click of that button, the magic happens and your project is created.
I will explore all the files and folders that are being created by default.
But before that, let me add this to source control.
I have already signed in to my git repo.
So that is coming along.
Repository name.
Let me call that bulky underscore MVC.
I will make that a private repository for now, but once the course is launched, I will convert that
to be a public repository.
With that configured, let me hit, create and push button.
And perfect.
We have two outgoing changes.
Let me push them.
Perfect.
So we have created our project and we have committed our code to the git repo.