Next folder that we have is www.
Root folder.
And this is an important folder in the application.
This folder will basically host all of the static content of your .net core or your project.
Now what is static content?
Static content basically means any CSS, any JavaScript, any NuGet packages or third party libraries,
or if you have any images, files, PDFs, PowerPoint and so on.
Anything that is static, which does not have an HTML code goes into the W.w.w root folder.
So you can see right here we have a global site dot CSS, which is already being used in the application.
So if you want to add some styling here, you can always add that.
Next we have the JS file, which is site.JS, but that is empty.
We just have a basic template there.
Inside the lib folder we can see bootstrap, jQuery, jQuery validations.
All of them are included by default when you create an MVC application.
In future when we have to add images or anything else which is static, we will always add them in one
place, which is www.
Root folder.
Always remember that.
After that, we have controllers, models and views that I will cover in the upcoming videos.
But after that we have something called as Appsettings.json.
And then if you expand that, you can see we have app settings, .development .JSON.
App settings will be the place where you will host all of your connection string.
Now when I mean connection string, it is not just connection string, but basically any secret key
that you have for your application.
An example of that will be for your email.
You might be using SendGrid or you might have a secret key for email.
You will add that in app settings.
When you have database connection, you will add those secret keys there.
If you are using Azure Blob Storage or Azure Storage account, you will be storing all of those connection
in one place.
That way, when you have to change a connection, you always know that you have to go to Appsettings.json
and not go through all the code trying to find out where is that connection.
All of your connection or secret keys should always go inside.
Appsettings.json.
Now here you see there is appsettings.json and app settings, dot development dot JSON.
If you remember inside launch settings dot JSON, we have the ASP.NET Core environment.
Now, based on this environment, it will be configuring to use a different connection string.
Like let's say in production, you will have an environment variable with the name of production.
Then inside Appsettings.json.
Well, in the project here, let me add and show you that new file.
We will be adding a new item.
And we will search for JSON file.
We have the app settings file.
I will call that app settings .production .JSON.
We save that here.
And what will happen with .net core is it will dynamically use that connection.
Whoops, I have a spelling mistake there.
Fix that.
So perfect.
Now in production, if your ASP.NET Core environment name this is production, then it will be using
the connection string and all the settings from this app settings .production  .JSON.
So it is pretty smart on what connection it will use, but we will uncover that in the upcoming videos.
Right now we do not want to go into that complexity.
Only thing you should remember is all of your secrets or connection string will go in app settings dot
json file.
Let me remove the production file that I added.
Right now we are not going to use that, but in the final section where we will be deploying the code,
I will modify that and show you how things work.
So perfect.
With that, in the next video, let's examine Program.cs, which is a critical file.