Now I want to cover a main file, which is Program.cs.
In the older versions of .net Core, we used to have two files.
We had Program.cs and we had Startup.cs.
But with the newer version, the .net team has combined both of those files in one file, which is
the Program.cs file.
Now, here, let me zoom out.
And when we have to configure a net application, there are two things that you should remember.
First, we have to add some services to our container, and next we have to configure the request pipeline.
In the program.cs.
Those are the two things that are being handled.
First.
You can see there is builder dot web application that creates a builder.
On that builder, we are adding some services.
Right now we are using MVC for our architecture and that is why on builder.services it has added something
called as ADD controllers with views.
That way it knows that, okay, our application will be using controllers and those are already defined
in the .net project, so I know how to handle that service.
In future we will be adding many more services inside Program.cs file.
Like if we have to inject something using dependency injection, which is a very critical aspect in
.net core.
We will inject all of them inside the services right here.
And the next thing that we have is we have to configure the request pipeline.
Pipeline basically means that when a request comes to an application, how do you want to process that?
Now, one thing that you see on line nine here is we have app.environment.is development.
This is the same environment variable that we saw in launch settings.
Dot JSON is development is a built in helper and you can see we also have is production staging.
But if you have some custom environment name you can use is environment and pass it there as well.
That's too technical for now, but I just wanted to give you some overview on how the environment variables
are being used.
Here we are saying that if the environment is not development, then we want to use an exception handler
and we want to redirect to home error page.
But if it is development, then we want to see that exception.
That is why we have this if condition.
After that, in our pipeline we have added https, redirect and app.use use static files.
When we add the use static files, it will configure the www route path and all the static files in
there will be accessible in our application.
After that, we are adding routing to the request pipeline and we have authorization.
Now, ignore this authorization right now.
We will cover that when we have authentication and authorization in our project.
But by default in the request pipeline, just have that authorization is added.
If you even forget that, That's okay.
Next, we have something that is important.
Now, when we have an application, we are telling it how the routing should work.
And for that we have app dot map controller route.
It basically has a default pattern that if nothing is defined in the route, you should go to something
called as a home controller.
Inside there you should go to index action and ID here can be defined or not.
A question mark in .net basically means that ID can be defined or it can be null.
So we are defining the default route that it should follow.
And finally we have app .run that will basically run the project.
Now, it might be confusing on what is going on here.
Why do I need Program.cs file?
What is all this?
Middleware pipeline?
Very strange words.
Do not worry, when we progress with the course, everything will start making much sense.
The reason I spent five minutes on this file right now is you have a rough idea that there is one file
where if I have to add a service to the container or I have to configure the middleware, I have to
go to program.cs file.
That is all that I want you to digest from this five minutes and have a rough idea of what I talked
about.
If nothing here makes sense, that's okay.
You should only remember that when you have to configure something in the pipeline.
Program.cs is the place you have to go with that understanding.
Let me continue from the next video.