Instructor: We are able to place order with
both the accounts of company as well as a customer user.
With that in place now we want to work on order management.
Like how will we update the order status to processing,
shipped and how can a company user make a payment later on?
First we need to add an order controller
where we will be having different action to display
all of the orders.
So first thing first, let me switch back to the code
and we will stop the application here.
Whoops, I restarted, let me stop that.
And inside admin we will have order management.
So in admin orders, let me create a new controller
with the name of order controller.
We will go with the empty controller.
That looks good.
Now for displaying all the orders,
we will be using data table.
So we can go to product controller,
and where we have the A P I, let me copy this,
and I will paste it right here.
Perfect. The A P I call looks good.
We do not want the delete, let me remove that.
And we need to add unit of work.
So right here we will have private,
read only I unit of work
underscore unit of work.
In the constructor, we will get the I unit of work
and underscore unit of work is equal to unit of work.
In the get all here, we will be getting a list
or I innumerable of order header.
So OBJ,
I will call that order headers is equal to
unit of work dot order header dot get all
and we want to include application user.
That looks good and we will return
back the OBJ order headers.
Great. So our order controller looks good
with the get all A P I endpoint.
But before I end the video,
typically when we retrieve anything related to order
we have to retrieve order header as well as order detail.
So for that it makes sense to create a new model
and let me do that.
It'll be a view model.
I will call that order VM for order view model
and it will be a public class.
Now that will have order header,
and it will have a collection of order detail.
So prop,
that will be I innumerable of order detail
and let me call that order detail.
Perfect. So we have a order review model that has
order header and all the order detail related to that model.
With that in place, let me continue from the next video.