Narrator: Now we need to display
all the orders in the index page.
So right click on index, add view,
it will be empty, looks good.
Let me add that,
the code we can copy that from product index,
copy everything, paste it here.
And we need to create a new js which will be order js.
When we are working with order here,
I want to display id, name, phone number,
email the order status and order total.
So we will update all of those properties in
the detach right here.
We do not want a link here to create a new product.
Let me remove that and I will remove this div altogether.
This will be order list,
and the model here will be order view model.
Well, when we are working here,
we do not want a model because
we are getting that from data table.
So let me remove that and I believe that looks good.
Next I want to work on the JavaScript.
So copy and paste the product JavaScript,
rename that to be order.js.
Perfect, we are on the order.js,
and there we have to retrieve all the columns.
The first one here is the id, followed by name,
and then we have phone number.
After that if I go back to index,
email status and total.
So email is inside application user.email.
Next we have order status,
and let me copy and paste this.
Once again, we have order total.
The render button here we will leave that as it is
right now and we do not want anything to delete,
so I will remove that as well
as the delete link right here.
Perfect, let me save that and we will work on
underscored layout where it is right here.
Where we have the privacy.
Let me change that to be admin,
controller will be order controller,
index action, and I will call that manage order.
Save that and let me run the project.
We will navigate to manage order,
and it does not find that admin order.
What is incorrect?
Whoops, we forgot the area here.
Area is admin.
With that, let me restart here and make sure that works.
Now when we go on the page, we will see a common error
with the data table and that looks good.
The reason behind that is when I was adding this
I did not care about the casing that we have here.
I have told you many times that you must always
remember what is the jason that is returned
and based on that you have to make it the exact case.
So now let me correct that.
That way you always remember to make sure
that this is case sensitive.
With that, if I go back and we still see the error here,
And of course we are not going to order.
That is the reason.
Save that and perfect.
Now we have all the details in our data table.
With here, let me change that
and phone number, make it a little bigger.
Perfect, that looks much better for our order data table.
With that in place, before I end the video.
In admin, we have the order controller
and there I will create an action
for details where we will pass the order id.
Let me call that order id and pass the data.
That looks good and we do not want added here.
Perfect, this looks much better.
Now before we work on the details, let me continue
and modify a few things here in the next video.