Instructor: Now on the Order List page,
I want to add a filtering here on the order status.
You can of course search for that.
But what I want to do is add a tab here
and display multiple status so user can click there
and toggle the order list right here.
For that, let me switch back, and we are on the index.
Inside the card-body, let me a div,
give it some Bootstrap classes of d-flex,
and justify-content-between, give it padding bottom of 5
and padding top of 2.
Within there I will add an empty span,
and then I will add a ul element
where we will display all the status in an li element.
For the ul, I will add some Bootstrap classes of list-group
and list-group-horizontal-small.
In there, I will be adding the multiple li elements.
Now li elements, I will be adding them inside anchor tag.
So the first anchor tag,
let me give it a style of text-decoration as none.
And what will be the route?
So asp-controller name, it will be the Order controller,
and the action name will be the same, Index action.
So it will basically bring them back to the same page,
but on top of that we will be adding an asp-route,
so asp-route-, we want to give some status.
So status is equal to, let me call the first one, inprocess.
Then right here, let me add an li, give it a class
of list-group-item, and I display In Process.
So that is the first li element.
Copy that and paste it four more times.
Let's say we want to display all the orders
where payment is pending.
After that, we want to display all the completed ones,
all the approved ones,
and we will have All to display all the status.
Now for each one of them,
we will have to give them a unique status.
So for all, let me give it all.
Next, we need approved, then we have completed,
and payment pending, we can call that just pending.
Perfect. With that, if I save and go back, great.
We have that here, and when we click, you can see the URL.
It is appending the status as expected.
Next task that I want to do
is based on what is selected here.
We want to give that particular box some styling.
That way we can tell which one of the status is selected.
Let me do that in the next video.