Instructor: Now based on the status here,
we want to toggle which one of the status is active.
Doing that is super simple.
Let's say if in process was selected,
we basically have to add a class of active
and with that, you can see it displays
that in process is selected.
But we have to do that dynamically.
Based on the status here, we have to add that variable
to each one of these ally element.
So what we can do is right here, let me add some razor code.
First thing, we have to retrieve the status
based on the query string that we have in the URL,
so we will say variable status.
We want to retrieve that from context dot request dot query
and the name is status.
After that, let me create five more variables here
for all the status that we have right here.
And it must match with the exact names that you see
inside the ASP route status.
We are giving them a default class of text primary.
Then we want to switch case here where,
based on the status, we will toggle the bootstrap classes.
So first case will be pending
and we'll copy paste that here.
If the case is pending, the pending variable
we will change the bootstrap classes to be active.
Text white, and we can give it BG primary.
We will break the case there
and that looks good for the pending class.
Let me copy this and paste it about four more times.
I will copy that for in process,
I have completed, I have approved.
And then for the default, we will say all is equal
to active text white and BG primary.
So based on whatever is selected here,
we are toggling the bootstrap classes
and we forgot one thing.
We need to change the variable names as well.
Perfect, that looks good.
Now these variable names, we can dynamically assign them
to the ally element like in process.
Next we have the pending one here.
Then we have completed,
scroll down, we have approved, and we have all.
With that, if you save and go back,
you can see when pending is selected,
we have a class there. When we change to completed,
the links are working as expected,
so the UI part is looking good,
but we need to toggle the functionality.
That way the order list is also updated
based on the status that is selected.
Let me do that in the next video.