Instructor: Right now in the order list
we are retrieving all the orders,
but we want to add a filter based on the status.
So let me do that.
We will switch back here
in the order controller
where we have the get all.
We will also receive one parameter,
which is status.
And then when we retrieve all the orders here
we can add a switch condition based on the status.
And what I will do, whoops,
this will be switch.
Let me go to the index here
and copy this case as it is,
paste it here.
If it is pending
we will filter the OBJ order headers
is equal to OBJ order headers dot where
and we will say U goes to U dot payment status
is equal to SD dot payment status delayed.
Pending will have all the orders
where the payment is pending
for the delayed payment.
In order for this to work,
we will have to convert this to be an I enumerable
and there we go.
Next we have the in process,
let me paste it here.
And we have the status in process
and that will not be payment status
that will be order status.
Then we have completed
that will be status shipped
and approved.
We have status approved.
Finally, for all we do not want to do anything
we can't return back.
So that looks good
for adding filtering
in the order controller.
Now from the order dot JS
when we are passing the order get all
we need to pass the status right here.
What we can do here is
in document dot ready we can get the complete URL
by using window dot location dot search.
Then we will be adding a nested looking
if else condition URL dot includes.
If that includes in process,
I do not want any spelling mistake
so let me go to index, copy the status exactly.
If that is in process
then when we are loading the data table
we will pass in process.
So basically in the load data table
we will get a status here this time.
Let me cut this,
then we will have an else block
and we will have nested if else.
Let me copy and paste this two times.
Next status.
Let me go to be completed here.
Let me go back.
We have pending
and I will have to paste it once again.
That will be for approved.
Perfect.
In the else here, we will load all record.
So perfect.
We are sending the status here.
When we are calling the get all here
let me up end the status.
So status is equal to,
and we will add that.
With that, I believe everything should be good now
and let me refresh here.
Whoops, it doesn't work.
Let me restart to make sure everything is functional
and let me see that.
Let me go to order management.
Perfect. All is selected.
Displays all the order.
If I go unapproved, it displays the two.
We don't have any completed
and one we have payment pending
that is being displayed.
So perfect.
With that our filters are working as expected.
One change I will do is the edit here.
Let me reduce the width there
so that, so the last one here
we will make that 10%
and name, I will increase that to be 20.
Phone number, 20 looks good.
This I will make it 20 as well.
And let me see how that looks.
Perfect, much better.
With that, let me continue from the next video.