Bhrugen: Now we can see all the orders here,
but how about OrderDetails?
We need to create that action method
and retrieve all the OrderDetails in Index here,
if we scroll down.
Well not here, in the order.js.
We are passing that as orderId.
So let me create that action method in the OrderController.
Let me do that.
Areas.
Perfect.
Right here, I can copy the Index, paste it here,
call that as Details and integer will be orderId.
Based on that orderId,
we have an Order ViewModel, which we can populate.
In there, we need to retrieve the OrderHeader
that we will do from unitOfWork.OrderHeader.Get.
We will get that using u=>u.Id==orderId,
and we can include the "ApplicationUser".
That looks good.
We can also retrieve the OrderDetail
from unitOfWork.OrderDetail.GetAll
because there will be more than one OrderDetail.
We will get that based on the orderId is equal equal
to the orderId.
And this one will not be orderId.
It is OrderHeaderId.
Let me correct that.
When we retrieve the OrderDetails,
let me include properties to get all the product details.
That looks good for the Order ViewModel.
Let me call that OrderVM.
And when we return to the view,
we will pass the Order ViewModel.
Let me add a debugging point here
and see if the Order ViewModel is getting populated.
We will go to Manage Order here.
Click Edit.
It should hit our break point here,
and perfect.
We have the OrderDetail there.
The OrderHeader is also looking good.
So perfect.
It is populating everything here
but we need to add that view.
So let me create the 'Details' view in the next video.