Instructor: Now we need to work on the view
for order details.
So let me switch back and stop the application.
On the details here, we will add view, empty view.
Make sure to name it exactly the same, details.csHTML.
Now for designing, we should not waste our time.
So let me switch back to our snippets.
Section 12.
We have the order details, UI.
Copy that and paste all the HTML and CSS.
And with that configured,
let me run the application to first get a feel
of what we want to build.
We go to Order Management, Edit, and perfect.
We have quite a few things right here.
On the left side here, we have all the order details
and we also have a button to update the order details.
Now the order details can only be updated
by admin or an employee.
So if a user is logging in and they are looking
at their order summary,
they will not be able to update their order details.
Before we work on all the items and the buttons here,
let me first work on order header here,
and modify this to display all the details,
and only admin will be able to update them.
So let me switch back and work on them.
First thing we have a back to orders here,
and in that case we will redirect them back
to the index action.
After that we want to check a role of the user.
Based on that, they will be able to update any details.
So as an example, the name here
and we will say if User.IsInRole,
that way we can check a role of a logged-in user.
We want to access our static detail.
And there we have a role of admin
or if user is in role, and we will say SD.RoleEmployee.
So if a logged-in user belongs to one of these role,
then they will be able to edit the names of input.
We will use asp for.
That is order header.
We forgot to add the model here.
We are passing the order view model.
So that will be model.
Once we add that, the asp for will be for OrderHeader.Name,
type will be text here, and class will be form control.
Perfect, that looks good.
All the squiggly lines went away.
Along with that, let me also add validation.
If we are allowing them to update that in the else part,
I can copy this, paste it here.
But we will make this a read only.
So if the role is not admin or employee
then it will be a read-only field,
else they will be able to update.
Let me save and run the application and see if that works.
Right now we are not logged in.
If we go there, you can see the name is read only.
I am not able to edit, but let me log in here as an admin.
Whoops.
The email was test admin.
Let me fix that.
And perfect, that works here.
Now if we go to Manage Order and if I try, that works.
So our roles is being implemented based on the user type.
They will be able to update the property.
We have to add this logic to everything else right here.
So we have phone number.
Let me modify that.
And let me paste it for all the properties,
and then I will start modifying them.
We have quite a few properties, so be patient.
The last one here is payment status.
We are on that one and let me start adding all of them.
Wherever I have the input field,
I will replace that with what we copied.
And perfect.
Let me try to modify them.
So we have address here.
Next we have the city.
Whoops, it was street address.
My bad.
We have city.
We have the state.
Next we have the postal code.
Copy that.
Then we scroll down.
Email will always be a read only,
so they will not be able to update that.
Let me fix that one.
And that is inside ApplicationUser.Email.
The next field that we want here is order date.
Order date also it should not be editable at all,
and we will display its value
from OrderHeader.OrderDate.ToShortDateString.
Next we have the carrier and tracking.
With carrier and tracking let me add both of them
and let me remove the validation
because if a user wants to keep them empty
or something like that,
we will handle those validation
using some JavaScript.
Right now let me keep things simple here.
Perfect.
We have carrier and tracking.
Scroll down.
We have the shipping date.
For shipping date also it will be a read-only field.
So rather than validations and everything,
and asp for, we will be adding value
which will be OrderHeader.ShippingDate
and ToShortDateString.
Then after that we have the Session ID
and Payment Intent ID.
These fields we do not want to display
if the user is not admin or employee.
So let me copy this if condition,
add it at the top here,
and I will close it after both the divs right here.
And if that is admin or employee,
then we will display and both of them will be read only.
So right here we have the SessionID
and we have the PaymentIntentID.
Then we scroll down.
We have the Payment Due Date and the Payment Date.
Now at a time only one of them will be visible.
Basically if SessionID is null,
that means that we have a payment due date
and payment has not been made.
So right here we can check
if and Model.OrderHeader.SessionID is null.
That means that Payment Due Date should be visible.
So let me cut this,
paste it here,
and it will be read only.
We do not want the asp for.
We will add a value there and that will be inside
Model.OrderHeader.PaymentDueDate.ToShortDateString.
Let me copy this whole div actually,
and I will paste it right here.
This one will be PaymentDate.
And let me go back here.
Else, we will display the Payment Date.
Perfect, looks good.
After that we have the Payment Status,
and that can be a read-only field.
So let me display Payment Status read only.
With that, let me save it here and let's go back.
Great.
All the details here are being populated.
We do not have a shipping date or payment due date.
Because of that, you see the dummy dates right here.
If I go back here, let me pick an approved order.
That looks good.
And the other one, we have the Session ID
and Payment Intent ID.
Now if I log out here, and if I go to Manage Order,
and right here we do not see the Session ID,
and that looks good.
So with that we have modified
the order header details right here.
Let me continue from the next video.