Instructor: Right now we will not worry
about the update or the details button
but basically this button will only be visible
if user is admin or employee.
So we can add that same logic.
Let me switch back here,
and I will copy the
if condition where I have the button here.
I will paste that,
so if it is admin or employee
only then we will display that button.
Perfect.
Now next thing we need to display the order summary.
Let me do that.
In order summary,
we have to display the current order status
so that is insight model dot order header
dot we have the order status.
Then if we go back,
we need to display each product here
based on what we have in order detail.
So right here in the ul,
I will add a for each loop
variable detail
in model dot order detail
and I will close that right here.
For each one of them, we need to display the title
so that is insight detail dot product dot title
and we need to display the individual price
which is insight detail dot price.
We will convert that to currency format here.
Perfect. That looks good.
Let me copy that.
Next we have the quantity that is inside detail
dot count.
Then we want to display the multiplication
of count and price here.
We will use the add sign.
We want to go to detail dot count
multiply that by detail dot price
and we will convert that to the currency format.
Then we need the grand total here.
That is inside model dot order header
dot order total
and convert that to currency.
Save that, and let me see.
Perfect. That looks much better.
Finally, we have all
of these fancy buttons to update the order status.
Now before we work on updating the order status,
let me first work
on updating the order details in the next video.