-: In this video we want to work on updating
the order details when we hit
the update order details button
and that button will only be visible
if the user is admin or employee.
If I scroll down and take a look at that button here
the type is submit here.
So it'll basically go to the same form that we have here.
So in order controller we have to create
a details post action method.
Now we can create the details post action method
but if you examine in the details
we have way more buttons at the end here as well.
So how can we have different button
post to different action method.
That is simple, where we have the update order detail
we can add ASP action and whatever action we add here
it will post to that action method.
So this one, let me call that update order detail
and we will make it update order detail.
Now this action method must be authorized
and the authorization is not one role.
We want the role of SD dot admin
or we want the role of employee.
So we can have a comma separated list here
and we can say role of employee.
So both of this role will be able to post here
let me add HTTP post here and that is perfect.
Now when they post here
we want to retrieve the order header ID.
So what we can do is if we go to the top
we do not have a view model, this order view model
let me create a property here
which will be order view, model,
and let me bind this property.
Now that we have, we do not want to create a new one here.
Let me use that one for fact.
And in the update order detail
we will already get that populated but we need
the order header ID in a hidden input field.
So let me add that right here.
That way we will be able to get the ID.
Now right here let me create a variable order
header from Db and we will retrieve the complete
order header from database.
So order headers, we have the get there U goes to
U at ID is equal equal to order view model
dot order header dot ID.
That is what we have in the hidden property.
So it will retrieve that and we will retrieve
the order header from database.
Now we have to manually map what are all the
fields that we want to update here.
Like first, we will update name, phone number,
street address, city, state, and postal code,
and we will map them like that.
Next, we also have carrier and tracking, but those
two we only want to update if they are not null or empty.
So we will say if string dot is not null or empty
then we want to update the carrier,
paste that one more time for tracking number.
I believe that looks good for all the properties
that I want to update.
So then we can call unit of work dot order header
dot update, and we will pass the order header from Db.
Once we do that, we have to call the save there
and that will save everything in database.
Finally, what we can do is we have a temp data
and we can display a notification order details
updated successfully and then where will we redirect back?
We want to redirect back to the same order details page.
So we will say redirect to action.
We want to redirect to name of, we have the details action
comma, and there in the details we need the order ID.
So we need a new object here.
We have to populate order ID from order header dot ID.
I believe that looks good.
Let me save and run the application.
We will have to log in as an admin user or an employee
and go to manage order.
Let me try to update few things here, and perfect.
That looks good.
Let me click update order details, and if I refresh here,
let me go back and for some reason you can see
it was not updated.
Let me try to add a debugging point
and see what is going on.
I will add debugging point in both the action method.
When we hit update order detail,
whoops, for some reason it is calling the get
and not this update order detail.
Let me see in the detail.
We have the button. Well, we have the input.
Let me change that to be button and it detects
the tag helper.
Let me cut this and I will add that between the tags here.
Perfect, looks good.
Let me continue.
We have to restart here.
Let me do that,
and let me log in again as admin.
And we go to manage order.
We hit the correct break point here.
Let me continue, try to update, and perfect, that works.
Hit continue again, and perfect.
Let me try to update everything here just to make sure
that all the fields are updated correctly
and let me go back to manage order and perfect.
So with that, our update functionality is looking great.