Instructor: Now, before I work on anything else here,
I want to add some validation here that if an admin logs in,
they'll be able to see orders from everyone,
and the same holds true for an employee.
But if any other role logs in, like customer, or a company,
they should only be able to see their orders.
So let me add that in the validation.
I will go back here in the OrderController,
where we have the GetAll,
we need to check the role of the logged in user.
So if User.IsInRole and if that is SD.Role_Admin
or User.IsInRole SD.Role_Employee.
If it is one of them,
then we will retrieve all the OrderHeaders.
Let me cut that, and we will say objOrderHeaders
is equal to paste what we copied.
Whoops. We have two equal to, let me remove one.
In the else part, the objOrderHeaders,
we will have to filter that based on the user ID.
So first, let me get the user ID using claimsIdentity.
That should sound familiar.
And let me call that userId.
We will load our obj here, unitOfWork.OrderHeader.GetAll
where we will say u goes to u.ApplicationUserId
is equal to the userId.
And we will include the properties.
So, includeProperties: ApplicationUser
without any spelling mistake.
That looks good.
Perfect.
So, with that, let me restart the application
and see that in action.
We are logged in as an admin, let me log out here,
and let me log in as a company user.
If we go to MANAGE ORDER now,
we should not be able to see all the order.
And that looks good.
If I log out and if I log in as an admin,
then I should be able to see all the orders.
Perfect. That looks much better.
With that in place, let me continue from the next video.