Instructor: Now if we go to the details here,
we have few buttons.
Let me work on when these buttons should be displayed.
The first button here is pay now.
That button should only be displayed for company user
where the payment status is equal to delayed payment
and the order status is shipped
because a company, we are giving them net 30
and they can make the payment
after the order has been shipped.
So, let me add that if condition first
where we'll go back to the details, scroll down
and here, rather than input, let me change all of them
to be button.
We will also have the closing text there,
so let me make that change.
And we will add the text between them.
So, pay now, start processing.
Next, we have the ship order.
And we have cancel order.
Perfect, let me remove the value.
And that looks good.
Now, the pay now should only be visible
if payment status is equal to delayed payment
and the order status is shipped.
So, that is the first if condition right here.
Let me do control A, control KD to align that.
Next, we have the start processing.
Now, all of these buttons here
to start processing, ship order or cancel order,
we want them to be only accessible by admin or an employee.
So, we will add the if condition.
Uf user is admin or employee,
only then they will be able to access these buttons.
But even then, we do not want to display all the buttons.
Start processing should be displayed
if the status is approved.
So right here, if the status is approved,
then we will display start processing.
Now, if the order is in processing,
only then the ship order should be displayed.
So, if the order status is in process,
then we will display the ship order.
So, the last one that we have here
is if model.OrderHeader.OrderStatus.
If that is not equal to SD.StatusRefunded
and we will be adding more condition.
Let me copy this one.
So, if it is not refunded
and it should not be status canceled
and it should not be shipped as well.
So, if all of these three conditions are true,
only then we will allow them to cancel the order.
And again, to cancel order, they will have to contact
and only admin or employee can cancel a order.
So, this condition looks good.
Let me go back and perfect.
Now, we only see start processing and cancel order
because the payment status and order status are approved.
So, the logic that we added here is looking good.
Let me continue from the next video.