Lecturer: Now let me work on the first button
Start processing.
When an admin hits the button start processing
we basically have to update the order status here
to be in process.
That is straightforward.
So right here in the button
let me add ASP action and that will be start processing.
Then let me create this action method.
Where?
Let me do that right here.
That will be HTTP post action method
and we need the same authorized keywords that we have here.
Copy that, paste it here.
Public I action result.
Let me copy the action name,
stop processing to avoid any spelling mistake.
Inside there we have to call unit of work
dot order header dot update status.
We need to pass the id that is inside order VM
dot order header dot ID and what will be the next status.
That is SD dot status in process,
we do not want to update any payment status.
That will stay as it is.
Then underscore unit of work dot save and we can
display the temp data, copy that
and redirect back
the order ID is inside order view model,
dot order header dot id.
Let me run the application and see if that works.
Let me go to manage order here
and whoops we get an exception here.
That is because user is not logged in,
well the complete order controller
we can add authorized keyword.
Let me run it again and that should work now.
If I click manage order, it redirects me to log in
and perfect it is approved for delayed payment.
If I do start processing, perfect we see the toaster
and current status is processing.
Next status that we see is ship order.
When a user clicks ship order
we will change the status but we want to make
sure that carrier and tracking are populated.
If they are empty, then ship order cannot be processed.
We have already added suite alert in the project
so let me use that to add those validation.
Let me go back and do that in the details here
where I have ship order.
I will add an on click event here
and we will return validate input.
I will create that
in the section here scripts and let me align that.
Control A, control KD insight there we have validations
on this page for ASP span, where is that?
We have the validation
so we should include the validation scripts partial.
Let me add that here
and then I will add a custom Java script.
We'll create the function.
Let me copy the name to avoid any spelling mistake there
and inside there we will have the IF condition.
We will say document dot get element by id.
Let me add an ID of tracking number.
I have not added that but I will do that after
I add the condition dot value if that is empty.
In that case I want a suite alert.
We will say SWAL dot fire,
we want error, title will be oops, text will be,
please enter tracking number and we will return false.
Let me copy this if condition paste it one more time here.
Next id, let me call that as carrier
and we'll display, please enter carrier return false,
else we'll return true.
We need to add both of these id.
So let me search for carrier.
We will be adding the ID here of carrier
and let me go down for the tracking number,
copy that exactly and I will search for tracking.
I will add the ID here of tracking number.
Perfect, and let me restart the application.
Let me log in again as admin here, manage order.
And if I click ship order
well you can see something is happening here
and carrier is not being set.
If I refresh here, that comes back.
So basically validate input is not being fired.
Did I add that in the correct one?
Yes I did.
Let me press F12 here
and let me log in again as dashed admin.
Let me go to manage order here and let me press F12.
Let me go to source here
and refresh the page inside the js.
Well inside the details here, if I scroll down
I have the JavaScript right here.
Let me add some debugging point
and hit the ship order.
The document dot get element by id.
So it is saying the value is null
it is basically returning true here.
And why is that?
Well, we have an issue here.
We have a single equal to that should not work.
This will be equal,
equal to and it is a silly mistake there.
Let me restart the application.
It is a common mistake with JavaScript
but now let me try that and perfect.
It says please enter tracking number.
If I enter that, then it works.
So our JavaScript validation are working.
Let me add the update status.
We will go to order controller.
Let me copy the start processing,
paste that one more time
and I will call that ship order.
Let me copy that
and we have to give that action name right here.
ASP Action ship order.
Perfect, now in this case we want to update the status
to be shipped
but on top of that we also have to update the tracking
and carrier information.
So what we can do is we will first retrieve the order header
from database.
We will retrieve that first and then we want to
update tracking carrier order status and the shipping date.
So let me update all four of those properties.
And finally we also want to update the payment due date.
If the payment status is delayed payment
then we have to update the payment due date as well.
So if order header dot payment status is equal
equal to SD dot payment delayed
then we want to update order header,
dot payment due date is equal to date time,
dot now, dot add days, we want to add 30 days.
That will give them the net 30 to make the payment.
Now this is date only,
for that we will say date only dot from date time
and there we have to pass the date time.
It'll convert that to date only and we will assign that.
Finally, once all of that is done
we will say unit of work dot order header
dot update and we will pass the order header
and save the changes.
For the toaster here we will say order shipped successfully
and we will redirect back to the order details.
With that configured, let me restart the application.
Let me log in here as an admin
and I have created couple of more orders.
Right here let me go to manage order
and we have one that is processing
and one customer is approved.
Let me go there.
We start processing ship date,
we have to enter a tracking information
and if I hit ship order,
perfect, the order status looks good.
Let me go back to one of the company orders here
and start processing that.
Add some tracking information and ship the order.
Perfect.
Now when a company order is shipped
you can see a pay Now button gets enabled here
and on top of that payment due date is also populated.
So perfect ship order is working as expected.
Let me continue from the next video.