Instructor: Button that I want to work on
is Cancel Order.
So let me go back here actually to the orders.
And if we have something that is approved here.
This is a customer order.
So if we cancel the order, we want to update the status.
But on top of that, I want to show you one more thing.
We actually want to give a refund to this customer,
and we have the Payment Intent ID.
Based on that, we can use Stripe to easily give refund.
Let me show that.
We will go back here in the Details,
where we have the Cancel Order.
Let me add an asp-action of CancelOrder.
Copy that, and we will create an action method.
Let me copy this action method for ShipOrder,
paste it here with the closing bracket,
and I will copy the action name CancelOrder.
Perfect.
When we have to cancel the order,
first we will retrieve that order from database.
And then, inside orderHeader,
we can check the PaymentStatus.
If PaymentStatus==SD.PaymentStatusApproved,
that means payment was already done
and we have to give them a refund.
Now in order to give them a refund,
we will create a variable options
of new RefundCreateOptions.
And you can see that is inside the Stripe class.
That looks good.
Inside there, you can give some Reason,
like RefundReasons.RequestedByCustomer.
And you have to provide the Payment Intent ID
that is inside orderHeader.PaymentIntentId.
Once you have the option,
then again we have to create a service.
But this time, it will be a RefundService,
which is inside Stripe.
And then, we will get a refund object
by calling the service.Create with the options.
Simple as that.
With that, the refund has been processed.
And if you want, you can also log the refund status
or the refund ID in your database by creating a new field.
What I will do is right here,
I will update unitOfWork.OrderHeader.UpdateStatus.
Change that to be orderHeader.Id.
The ID is inside orderHeader.Id.
And the status will be StatusCancelled.
Payment status will be SD.StatusRefunded.
In the else part here,
we are not going to give them any refund,
so we will directly say StatusCancelled.
Finally, we have to save the changes,
so let me copy that from the top here,
paste it here,
and I will say, "Order Cancelled Successfully."
Redirect back.
Perfect. That looks good.
Let me save this and restart the application.
We are logged in as the admin here.
Let me go to Manage Order.
And Customer, let me go there and click Cancel Order.
Perfect. Order canceled.
Then, let me go to Stripe
and see if a refund request actually came through.
We will go to Payments here, and perfect.
You can see refund has been initiated.
And Payment Intent, if you notice, ends in SAD,
and that is what we have right here.
So canceling an order is working as expected,
and we are giving them a refund if the payment was made.