Instructor: The last thing that I can think of right now
is pending, is if a order is shipped by a company,
then they need to make the payment,
which is a delayed payment.
So let me work on that.
So let me go back to the code and where we have that button,
we will handle that directly on the submit of the same form.
So we have button type = "submit."
We can create a post-action method with the name of detail.
Let me do that, right, well, I can add it anywhere.
Let me do that before the API CALLS.
I will create an action method
with the name of details, pay now but the action name,
I have explicitly defined that as details.
So if I save that and if I add a break point,
well, I will have to return back to the view.
Let me copy this and paste it here and let me try that.
If I go to manage order where we have the company,
hit pay now, perfect!
You can see it is hitting the endpoint and that looks good.
Right here what we want to do
is based on the order header id, I want to retrieve
and populate the order header and order details again
because when we are posting, we might lose some information.
So based on the ID, let me retrieve the order header
and order detail once again.
Then we want to work with Stripe.
So let me open the controller where we have Stripe,
inside the cart controller, scroll down
and let me copy everything right here with the Stripe logic.
Copy that and we will paste it right here.
This time when everything is successful,
let me create a new page for payment confirmation
and we will add the orderHeaderId.
So here let me say orderHeaderId is equal
to Order View Model.OrderHeader.Id.
Let me correct the case there and that looks good.
But if they cancel we want to redirect to the same page.
So that will be admin
and this payment confirmation will be in admin and order.
So cancel will be admin/order/details.
We need the order ID, that is again inside.
Whoops, let me add the dollar sign there
and Order View Model.OrderHeader.Id.
So that looks good.
Now for the line items, we need the shopping cart
and that is inside Order View Model.
Now we have the order detail.
Based on that we will get the price
and product title as well as the count.
We will add that. That looks good.
We scroll down, create session, that looks good.
Next, we have to update the ID,
once everything is successful.
So Order View Model.OrderHeader.Id
and we will pass the session ID and payment intent ID.
Perfect, I believe everything else looks good.
We do not need that redirect
and let me rebuild and apply the changes.
Before I test that,
let me create this payment confirmation real quick.
That will be similar to order confirmation.
So I can copy this, go to order controller
and paste it right here.
Rather than ID, I wrote that we will return orderHeaderId.
Let me modify that.
We will retrieve the order header based on that.
Well if you want, you can include the application user.
I do not think we will use that.
Then if the PaymentStatus == DelayedPayment,
we want to make sure that the payment actually went through.
So in this case this is an order by a company.
And then we will get the session, SessionId.
We will check if the payment status is paid.
In that case, we want to update the payment intent ID
and we want to update the status.
So status, we will add the ID there and that looks good.
But one thing that we have to modify is
we do not want to change the order status.
The only status we want to change
is the payment status
because the order might already be shipped.
So we do not want to modify that.
So here we will go to orderHeader.status
and we will use the same one.
I believe that looks good.
We do not worry about the shopping cart this time,
we only return back to the view
and we will return the orderHeaderId.
Let me create this view now.
This will be PaymentConfirmation,
let me copy that to avoid spelling mistake,
right-click, Add View
and we will paste that,
UI will be similar to what we have
for order confirmation.
Let me copy and paste that here
and here we will display Payment Successful.
We will display order number here, that looks good.
And right here we will display,
Payment has been applied successfully!
We will add a link to go back to the order details.
We have the asp route ID
and everything else that is needed for the order details.
Let me run this and see if everything works.
Now what we did so far is similar to what we learned
when we were processing the payment first time.
That is why I went a little bit fast.
Let me edit here and click pay now,
we hit our endpoint here, continue from there,
it should redirect to Stripe.
That works.
Let me make a payment.
We will hit the Pay button here and let's see what happens.
Perfect, payment successful.
And we have the order number eight.
Let me go to database and see if that works.
We need the order header here.
Perfect, payment status is approved
and order status remains as shipped
and we have the payment intent ID, that looks good.
So with that, we are now handling the delayed payment.
If we go back to that particular model,
to that same order, now we do not see the pay now button.
So all the logic and functionality are looking good.