Instructor: We want to implement a repository pattern
for data access inside our project.
Since this is a big project,
it is always good to have a repository pattern
rather than accessing the database directly,
like we are doing inside the controller right here.
So, let me close all the tabs here,
and we will start fresh with our data access project.
We need to create a repository.
So, first thing first, let me create a folder here
with the name of Repository.
And inside there,
we will create a folder for IRepository,
which will hold all the interface,
and the implementation will be inside Repository.
So we can move our IRepository inside the Repository folder,
like that.
So first, let me implement the interface
inside the IRepository,
we will implement interface,
and I will call that IRepository.
Let's add that.
This will be a public interface,
and this interface should be generic.
Right now, we have category,
but as we move forward, we will have cover type,
company, user, order header, order details, and much more.
This repository should be able to handle all of the classes.
We can say here that this will be a generic repository
where T is a class.
It does not matter what class it will be,
we do not have to define that here,
it will just be a class.
Then it can be a category that we have right now,
or maybe order header, order details.
We don't care about that,
inside our repository, this will be a generic repository.
So, hypothetically,
let's assume that this T is a category for now.
In that case,
what will be the common methods that we want to implement?
To check those out,
we can go back to our web project.
In there, we have the Controller folder.
Let me minimize that.
And inside the controller's folder
let's open Controller.
So you can see here,
we have an IEnumerable
where we are getting all the categories.
So we need to implement that here in the generic category.
Return type should be an IEnumerable of T,
T basically can be any class,
it can be category when we are using
inside the category controller.
We do not want any parameters here,
we just want to retrieve all the categories,
that is our first requirement.
Then if we scroll down,
we have a requirement to add a category.
So when we are adding a category,
we are passing the object that needs to be added,
which is an object of the class.
So, let's implement that right here.
The return type will be void,
method name, we can give it Add,
and in the parameter,
we will give the entity that needs to be added.
Let's go back to our controller.
Next requirement that we have is Edit,
and inside Edit, we want to find that based on the id.
Now, if you remember here, you can use directly Find,
that works if what you are finding is a primary key.
But if that is not a primary key,
you can use FirstOrDefault to find that based on the id.
Of course, with FirstOrDefault,
you need the using statement of LINQ.
But with that, this approach will work on any column,
not just the id.
So, let's say if you want to find the category
where Name is equal to some name that you have here,
this will work with FirstOrDefault,
but it'll not work with Find.
So rather than implementing Find in our repository,
it makes sense to implement something like FirstOrDefault.
So we can go back to the IRepository,
and let's implement the FirstOrDefault
at the very beginning.
What will be the return type of FirstOrDefault?
It'll return an object of the class that we want.
So this will be the generic class, T,
that will be the return type.
We can call this method as GetFirstOrDefault.
And what will be the parameter here?
The parameter that we want here is this expression,
or something similar.
We can have this exact expression inside the parameter.
Because this is an expression inside there,
we have a function that is handling some scenarios
and filtering data.
To implement this exact function,
if we go to our IRepository,
we will say we want an expression here.
We'll press Control + . for LINQ.Expression,
because that is a LINQ expression.
Inside that expression,
we have a function where the first parameter
is the generic class, and the output will be boolean.
We will call that as filter.
This will be a required property
when we are calling the GetFirstOrDefault,
because if we are recruiting only one record,
we will always need a filter condition.
So with that,
we have handled this GetFirstOrDefault scenario perfectly.
We can use this if you want,
or you can un-comment the code that we had before,
it will still work the same.
Next, let's scroll down.
We have the edit post, where we are updating some record.
Now, update is something
that will not be common for all the repository.
Because let's say when you're updating category,
you have a different logic,
when you're updating a product,
you have a different logic because you have images
that needs to be updated.
So update is not something that will be consistent
across all the models that we have.
Because of that, it makes sense not to include that
inside the generic repository.
So we will come back to update in the later videos.
After that, we have Delete, in which we have Find,
we have implemented the GetFirstOrDefault,
and we have the POST action method
where we are removing something.
Inside Remove here, we just want to remove an entity,
so we have to pass that, and the return type will be void.
So we can copy the Add here,
paste it again for Remove.
Lastly, it is possible you want to remove
more than one entity,
so for that, we have something called as RemoveRange.
When we want to RemoveRange,
we will receive more than one entity here,
so rather than T here,
we will receive an IEnumerable of T,
which is a collection of entities.
So with that, our generic repository looks good.
As we proceed with the course,
we will face some complex scenarios,
and we will come back here to modify our repository.
So with that, let's continue from the next video.